{"id": 538, "text": "[Captain's\nmess] \n(The food is making Tucker's eyes water.)TUCKER: I thought Cajun food was\nhot. (Archer takes a bite and nearly loses his voice.) \nARCHER: D'Marr, what do you\ncall that spice? (A white-skinned alien, reptilian with frills around the jaw and\nlarge scale plates on the head.)\nD'MARR:  Hajjlaran. The warlords on Preenos use\nit to test their courage. (to T'Pol) You sure you won't have some? \nT'POL: My courage doesn't need testing. \nD'MARR: I have other items to trade. I can get you some Triaxian silk\nfor, say, another protein resequencer? \nTUCKER: I bet you'd look good in Triaxian silk. \nARCHER: What we really need are engineering supplies. \nTUCKER: Raw duratanium, dilithium ore. \nD'MARR: I'm sorry, I prefer to deal in more exotic goods. But, about\ntwo days from here there's a small system. You might find what you're\nlooking for there. \nT'POL: We haven't detected any inhabited planets on long range scans. \nD'MARR: It's not inhabited. Not exactly. \nARCHER: What do you mean? (D'Marr takes a drink.) \nD'MARR: Mmm! This is excellent. What is it again? \nARCHER: Coffee. I can have my Chef wrap up a few kilograms for you if\nyou wouldn't mind telling us where we can find those supplies. \nD'MARR: Captain, please. This isn't a matter of negotiation. I'm\nthinking of your safety. \nARCHER: Ten kilos? \nD'MARR: It's pure luck that I even found it. \nTUCKER: Found what? \nD'MARR: A ship, crashed on one of the inner planets. There were no\nlifesigns aboard, so I landed to claim my rights of salvage. \nTUCKER: What'd you find? \nD'MARR: A transport vessel, largely intact. I could have stripped it\nbare and made a fortune. \nT'POL: Why didn't you? \nD'MARR: The, er, crew objected. \nARCHER: You said there weren't any lifesigns aboard. \nD'MARR: There weren't. There wasn't anything alive. \nTUCKER: What are you saying, the ship was haunted? \n [Bridge] \n (Enterprise is in orbit of a planet.) \nT'POL: The atmosphere is thin, but breathable. \nARCHER: Any biosigns?", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 15, "LOC"], [38, 46, "PER"], [156, 162, "PER"], [327, 334, "LOC"], [504, 512, "LOC"], [591, 599, "LOC"], [1218, 1225, "PER"], [1856, 1862, "LOC"], [1867, 1877, "SHIP"]]}
{"id": 539, "text": "[Hoshi's quarters]\n\n (Hoshi\nis in her bathroom when she hears a soft voice.) \nTARQUIN [OC]: Hoshi. (She goes into her living quarters.) \nHOSHI: Hello? \nTARQUIN [OC]: Do you understand me? I think you do. Can you see me? \n(There's a shadowy figure in the corner.) \nHOSHI: Ensign Sato to Security. \nREED [OC]: Go ahead. (the figure is gone) Hoshi? Is everything all\nright? Hoshi? \n [Command\nCentre] \n ARCHER:\nI thought I was the only one who lived here during my off hours. \nT'POL: I'd like you to see this. These are the locations where we've\nencountered spatial anomalies. I analysed the sensor logs from the\nXindi database. These are the co-ordinates where that vessel was\naffected. \nARCHER: Seems pretty random. \nT'POL: That's what I thought, until I ran a vector analysis of the\ngravimetric waves coming from the sphere we discovered. The\ninterference patterns implied another wave source. \nARCHER: A second sphere. \nT'POL: It appears so. The simulation suggests that the anomalies occur\nwhere the waves intersect. \nARCHER: If you're right, then we should be able to start predicting\nwhere we're going to run into trouble. \nT'POL: If we're going to create an accurate map, we'll need precise\nmeasurements of the sphere's gravimetric fields. \nARCHER: Assuming there is a second sphere, how far away is it? \nT'POL: Less than four light years. \nARCHER: Set a course. \n [Bridge]\n\n HOSHI:\nNothing? \nREED: I ran every scan in the book. There's no sign of any intruder\nanywhere on the ship. \nHOSHI: Maybe our sensors missed something. \nREED: I went through all the logs for the last twenty four hours. To\nsay they were uneventful would be an understatement. This is good news.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[22, 27, "PER"], [92, 97, "PER"], [271, 282, "PER"], [286, 294, "ORG"], [381, 395, "LOC"], [609, 614, "GPE"], [1, 8, "PER"], [339, 344, "PER"], [371, 376, "PER"]]}
{"id": 540, "text": "T'POL\n[OC]: Previously on Enterprise \n\n DEGRA [Command\nCentre]: (referring to a sphere) How to you plan to get\ninside? \nARCHER: We're pretty sure we've found a way in. I'm sending a crew in a\nshuttlepod. \nT'POL: The Spheres are controlled by a network of artificial\nintelligence. This section houses the redundant memory core. It should\ncontain a significant amount of information. \nARCHER: We're hoping that'll include data on the Sphere Builders. \n([Inside the Sphere, MACO\nHawkins is grabbed and killed by the Sphere defence mechanism.) \nREED: Hawkins! \nDEGRA [Ready room]: I'll\nbe at your side no matter what happens. \nDOLIM [Xindi Council Chamber: We've\ntaken control of the weapon. We're going to launch it. \nDEGRA [Council Chamber, earlier]: Wait! \n(He tries to stop Dolim and he and Archer get hit) \nDOLIM [Degra's quarters]: We\nhave an image of your ship firing. \nDEGRA: They left me no choice. \nDOLIM: You've left me no choice. (stabs him in the chest) The crew of\nthat ship are the last Xindi you'll ever betray. \nHUMANOID [Xindi Council Chamber]: The\nweapon cannot be launched without three of the codes. \nDOLIM: Do you really believe we haven't considered that? \nARCHER [Bridge]:\nHoshi! \n(She's beamed away.) \n [Reptilian Interrogation room]\n\n HOSHI: Why am I here? What do you want? \nDOLIM: We were impressed with your linguistic abilities. Aquatic is\ndifficult to master. I've heard it spoken my entire life but still, it\ndoesn't come easily to me. \nHOSHI: Maybe you should have applied yourself more. \nDOLIM: We have some encoded data we need translated. \nHOSHI: I'm not a cryptologist. \nDOLIM: I have confidence in your abilities.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[47, 61, "LOC"], [432, 447, "SPEC"], [630, 651, "LOC"], [722, 737, "LOC"], [774, 779, "PER"], [791, 797, "PER"], [815, 822, "PER"], [998, 1003, "SPEC"], [1035, 1056, "LOC"], [1193, 1198, "PER"], [1355, 1362, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 541, "text": "T'POL\n[OC]: Previously on Enterprise \n\n DANIELS [Enterprise\nJ]: We're four hundred years in the future. \nARCHER: You know about the alien we found, the test subject? \nDANIELS: He belongs to the same race that built the Spheres. They're\naltering this space to make it habitable for their species. You have to\nmake the Xindi understand that humanity isn't the enemy. \nDEGRA [Degra's ship]: The\nweapon won't be launched for several days. Show us your proof.\nDEGRA [Sickbay]: You're\nsaying the Expanse will no longer be compatible for us. \nPHLOX: For any of us. \nARCHER [Ready room]: We're\ndestined to form an alliance to stop them. \nDEGRA: You need to speak to the Council. With the evidence you've shown\nme they'll have no choice but to take us seriously. \nBUILDER [Xindi Council Chamber]: If it\nweren't for my assistance your species would be facing destruction. \nDEGRA: Is it true your species built the Spheres? \n[Degra's ship]\nDOLIM [on viewscreen]: Where is Degra? \nARCHER [Bridge]: What\nkind of weapons do you have? \nDEGRA: You expect me to attack a Reptilian warship? \n(Degra's ship blows up the attacker.) \n\nT'POL [OC]: The Reptilian vessel's been destroyed. \nDEGRA [on viewscreen]: They would have contacted the Council and\nexposed our alliance. \nHUMANOID [Degra's ship]:\nHe'll be killed the moment he steps into the Council chamber. \nDEGRA: If Archer is telling the truth, then all the Council's efforts\nwill be for nothing. \n [Trans-dimensional space] \n (A milky atmosphered place with no points of\nreference, just the camera swooping from one white bald female figure\nto another.) \nBUILDER: We've been successful. The Xindi weapon is days away from\ncompletion. \nPRESAGE: The timelines don't support that assessment. \nPRIMARY: What have you seen?", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[49, 61, "SHIP"], [317, 322, "SPEC"], [373, 380, "PER"], [490, 497, "LOC"], [662, 669, "ORG"], [764, 785, "LOC"], [915, 922, "PER"], [977, 983, "LOC"], [961, 966, "PER"], [1054, 1063, "SPEC"], [1075, 1082, "PER"], [1130, 1139, "SPEC"], [1219, 1226, "ORG"], [1324, 1339, "LOC"], [1394, 1403, "ORG"], [1628, 1633, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 542, "text": "ARCHER: Previously on Enterprise\n\n\n          REED [Corridor]: We don't have a complete casualty list yet, but so far the news isn't good. Five people are confirmed dead, \n          dozens wounded. \n          ARCHER [Reptilian brig]: If you destroy Earth you won't just be eliminating my species, you'll be eliminating your own. \n          T'POL [Sickbay]: Do you have any idea why they released you? \n          ARCHER: I think I may have gotten through to one of them. Degra. \n          DEGRA [Xindi Council Chamber]: We were told the Reptilians attempted to build a bioweapon. \n          BUILDER: Who told you this? \n          HUMANOID: We've also learned that they were building this bioweapon in the past, on Earth. \n          T'POL [Sickbay]: When I was exposed to trellium, it affected me in a way I wasn't prepared for. I discovered \n          I was able to access certain emotions. I wanted more. I devised a way to inject it into my bloodstream. \n          PHLOX: You must have known it was dangerous. Trellium exposure is deadly to Vulcans. \n          TUCKER: (having his nightmare) Elizabeth, get out of there!\n\n [Cargo bay]\n\n          ARCHER: We're in bad shape, I can't deny that, but we're still in one piece. Enterprise is a tough \n          ship. She took more than anyone could ask her to and then some, and so have all of you. I wanted to say \n          thank you. I only wish I could thank the eighteen crewmen who were lost. Like you, they understood how \n          important our mission is and they accepted the risks. We came into the Expanse not knowing what we'd find, \n          with no one to rely on but ourselves, but we're going to succeed, to accomplish our mission, for everyone \n          on Earth who's relying on us, and for the eighteen.\n          \n [Ready room]\n\n          TUCKER: We managed to get into sections six and seven on C deck. We found Taylor and Kamata. \n          T'POL: That accounts for everyone. \n          ARCHER: What's our status on weapons? \n          T'POL: Mister Reed has both forward phase cannons back online in addition to the aft torpedo launchers. \n          Hull plating is up to eighty percent. \n          ARCHER: That'll have to do. \n          TUCKER: We could wait, hang back until we've had a chance to make more repairs. \n          T'POL: Degra's message was clear. We're to meet him ten hours from now. \n          ARCHER: And I don't intend to be late. \n          TUCKER: Maybe that's what he's counting on. Lure us into an ambush while we're still licking \n          our wounds. \n          ARCHER: I've made my decision. We have a lot of work to do. I suggest we get to it. \n          TUCKER: Aye sir. (T'Pol leaves.) \n          ARCHER: Commander. Crewman Taylor was one of yours, wasn't she? \n          TUCKER: She was an EPS control specialist, a damn good one.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[216, 225, "SPEC"], [248, 253, "LOC"], [346, 353, "LOC"], [469, 474, "PER"], [494, 515, "LOC"], [535, 545, "SPEC"], [712, 717, "LOC"], [737, 744, "PER"], [1041, 1048, "SPEC"], [1092, 1101, "PER"], [1124, 1133, "LOC"], [1223, 1233, "SHIP"], [1556, 1563, "LOC"], [1723, 1728, "LOC"], [1865, 1871, "LOC"], [1882, 1888, "PER"], [1893, 1899, "PER"], [2014, 2025, "PER"], [2308, 2315, "PER"], [2719, 2733, "PER"], [1785, 1795, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 543, "text": "Captain's personal log, February 12, 2152. After a brief detour, we're\nback on course for Risa. Everyone's looking forward to some much needed\nshore leave. \n [Archer's quarters] \n ARCHER: I've got my eye on a place called Suraya\nBay. Villas built right into the cliffs. A perfect spot to enjoy a few\ngood books. Might even do a little diving when I (comm. beep) Computer,\npause. Archer. \nT'POL [OC]: We're picking up a distress call, Captain. It's coming from\na vessel approximately two light years to port. \nARCHER: Any idea who it is? \nT'POL [OC]: No, sir. Should we alter course? \nARCHER: Go ahead. I'll be right there. (to Porthos) Looks like your\nwalk on the beach will have to wait. \n [Corridor] \n(Archer is talking with a tall humanoid in flowing robes, with a\nstrange tattoo on the chin.)  ZOBRAL: Plasma residue? \nARCHER: Your warp injectors were full of it. \nZOBRAL: I must be more diligent about routine maintenance. \nARCHER: Unless you enjoy being adrift in the middle of nowhere. \nZOBRAL: I'm sorry to inconvenience you something this trivial. Be sure\nto thank Mister Tucker for his time. \nARCHER: He wanted me to thank you. It isn't every day he gets to tinker\nwith alien engines. We also found a microfracture on your starboard\nhull. They're sealing it now. \nZOBRAL: Oh, your crew is very thorough. \nARCHER: We were glad to help. \nZOBRAL: Do you answer every distress call you pick up? \nARCHER: If we can. \nZOBRAL: The galaxy could use more people like you. \n [Shuttlepod bay] \n ZOBRAL: Tomorrow you'll join me in my home. Bring\nCommander Tucker. I'll prepare a meal in your honour. It's the least I\ncan do to show my gratitude. \nARCHER: That's very generous, but I promised my crew a trip to Risa. \nZOBRAL: That can wait one more day, can't it? \nARCHER: If I put them off much longer, I'm going to have a mutiny on my\nhands. \nZOBRAL: There's going to be a Geskana match. I doubt you've ever seen\nanything like it. \nARCHER: Geskana?", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[90, 94, "LOC"], [159, 167, "PER"], [222, 232, "LOC"], [379, 385, "PER"], [434, 441, "PER"], [1074, 1087, "PER"], [1434, 1440, "LOC"], [1476, 1490, "LOC"], [1544, 1560, "PER"], [1708, 1712, "LOC"], [704, 710, "PER"]]}
{"id": 544, "text": "ARCHER\n[OC]: Last time on Enterprise. \n(The explosion in the atmosphere of the Paraagan mining colony.) \nHOSHI: (in Sickbay) There's nothing left. No buildings, no trees, no\npeople. \nARCHER: That's impossible. There were thirty six hundred colonists. \nARCHER: (Ready room) The mission's been cancelled. \nTUCKER: I can't believe you're letting them do this to us. You've\nwaited all your life to command this ship. \nDANIELS: (Archers apartment) History never recorded the disaster.\nSomeone violated the Temporal Accord. Someone who doesn't want your\nmission to succeed. \nARCHER: Are you telling me that Enterprise didn't cause that explosion?\n\nARCHER: (Ready room) He brought me back ten months, but I knew\neverything I know now. How is that possible? \nARCHER [OC]: The Suliban destroyed that colony. (attack on cloaked\ncruiser) We're going back to get proof. \nFUTURE MAN: (Temporal chamber) Have your ships bring me Archer. \nT'POL: (Bridge} Captain Archer is no longer aboard Enterprise. \nSILIK [on viewscreen]: I thought he was smarter than this. He could\nhave saved all your lives. \nREED: It's targeting our warp core. \nDANIELS: (Devastated building) You're in the thirty first century,\nCaptain. \nARCHER: If bringing me here caused this, then send me back. I'll take\nmy chances with Silik. \nDANIELS: You don't understand. The time portals have been destroyed.\nEverything's been destroyed. There's no way to send you back. \nARCHER [OC]: And now, the conclusion. \n [Bridge] \n T'POL: He's not on board. You must have sensors\nthat can confirm that. \nSILIK [on viewscreen]: You've lied to me before. If you don't tell me\nwhere he is I'll have no alternative but to \nT'POL: Come see for yourself, or send your soldiers. You'll realise I'm\ntelling the truth. \nSILIK [on viewscreen]: Drop out of warp and prepare to be boarded.\n(Ends transmission.) \nREED: Security teams to docking ports one, two, and three. \nT'POL: This is Sub-Commander T'Pol. All security teams remain where you\nare. \nTUCKER: Are you crazy? How do we know how many Suliban are coming", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[79, 87, "LOC"], [116, 123, "LOC"], [261, 271, "LOC"], [424, 431, "PER"], [601, 611, "SHIP"], [651, 661, "LOC"], [768, 775, "SPEC"], [872, 888, "LOC"], [915, 921, "PER"], [940, 954, "PER"], [932, 938, "LOC"], [975, 985, "SHIP"], [1188, 1195, "PER"], [1284, 1289, "PER"], [1465, 1471, "LOC"], [1918, 1937, "PER"], [2028, 2035, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 545, "text": "[Sickbay] \n (Phlox\nis going around putting various foodstuffs into various cages and\ncontainers) \nHOSHI: Feeding time? \nPHLOX: When isn't it? (He takes a bundle of fluff out of a box.) \nHOSHI: What is that? \nPHLOX: It won't bite. It's called a tribble. (She takes it.) PHLOX: It was\nextremely difficult to acquire. They're outlawed on most worlds. \nHOSHI: Why? Is it dangerous? \nPHLOX: Oh, far from it. All it's capable of doing, really, is eating\nand breeding. The problem is they breed quite prodigiously. (Phlox takes it\nfrom her and drops it into another cage, where, amid much screeching,\ntrembling of foliage and rattling of the bars, we assume it gets eaten.)\nPHLOX: The only thing that keeps their population in check is the abundance of\nreptiles on their homeworld. Are you feeling all right, Ensign? \nHOSHI: I just came by to give you this transmission. It's from the\nDenobulan Science Academy. Marked urgent. \nPHLOX: Thank you. \n [Situation\nroom] \n TRAVIS:\nThese caverns go on for fifty kilometres. \nPHLOX: They've mapped fifty kilometres. No one knows exactly how far\nthey extend. \nTUCKER: What were these scientists of yours doing down there? \nPHLOX: This cave system is known for its mineral formations. The\nspeleothems are supposed to be particularly unusual. \nARCHER: They've been underground for six months. The Denobulan Science\nAcademy lost contact with them three weeks ago. The planet's called\nXantoras. The government's been politically unstable for several years.\nIn the last few weeks a militant faction has taken control. \nPHLOX: They're demanding that all off-worlders leave. Anyone who fails\nto comply could face imprisonment, or possibly worse. \nREED: Then why don't the Denobulans evacuate their own scientists? \nARCHER: They can't get here in time. Enterprise is less than a day\naway. We've been asked to pick them up. First we have to find them.\nYou've had some caving experience. \nTRAVIS: There are some pretty steep inclines here, but I think I can\nhandle it. \nARCHER: What about you and Malcolm? \nTUCKER: Don't worry, Captain. I'm sure Travis is an excellent teacher. \nARCHER: Get some gear together.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 8, "LOC"], [13, 18, "PER"], [244, 251, "SPEC"], [509, 514, "PER"], [802, 808, "PER"], [878, 903, "ORG"], [942, 956, "LOC"], [1329, 1354, "ORG"], [1415, 1423, "LOC"], [1699, 1709, "SPEC"], [1779, 1789, "SHIP"], [2021, 2028, "PER"], [2052, 2059, "PER"], [2070, 2076, "PER"]]}
{"id": 546, "text": "[Bridge]\n\n(Travis is looking at a series of archive pictures\non his station monitor.) \nTRAVIS: This was their first view of it. \nHOSHI: If you don't look too close, you'd think it was Earth. \nTRAVIS: Breaking ground on the town hall. \nHOSHI: Is that Captain Mitchell? \nTRAVIS: No, I think that's Mitchell. \n(Archer enters.)\nARCHER: Are we there yet? \nTRAVIS: Three hours seventeen minutes to go, sir. \nHOSHI: Travis has been digging through the archives. \nTRAVIS: There's tons of data here. Crew manifests, survey photos,\nweekly status reports. I was hoping to find something, a clue to what\nhappened. \nARCHER: You'd be the first. \nTRAVIS: I've been fascinated by Terra Nova since I was a kid, sir. I\nalways thought lost colonies affected boomers more than anyone else.\nSomething about people who choose to live off-world. \nHOSHI: Captain, do you think anyone's still there? \nARCHER: I'll let you know in about three hours and seventeen minutes. \n [Captain's mess] \n T'POL: Terra Nova? \nARCHER: I'm surprised you've never heard of it. \nT'POL: I'm not familiar with the early years of human space\nexploration. \nTUCKER: Really? Every school kid on Earth had to learn about the famous\nVulcan expeditions. \nT'POL: Name one. \nTUCKER: History was never my best subject. \nARCHER: It was called the Great Experiment. Could humans colonise deep\nspace? They'd already build New Berlin on the Moon, Utopia Planetia on\nMars, even a few asteroid colonies, but all within our solar system.\nWhen they found an Earth-like planet less than twenty light-years away,\nit was hard to resist. \nTUCKER: It took them what, nine years to get there? \nARCHER: Nine years there, nine years back, but they made it. \nTUCKER: My grandfather remembered seeing their first transmissions when\nhe was a kid. \nT'POL: What happened to them? \nARCHER: People have been trying to answer that question for a long", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 7, "LOC"], [11, 17, "PER"], [184, 189, "LOC"], [250, 266, "PER"], [296, 304, "PER"], [308, 314, "PER"], [409, 415, "PER"], [664, 674, "LOC"], [831, 838, "PER"], [949, 963, "LOC"], [974, 984, "LOC"], [1182, 1188, "SPEC"], [1146, 1151, "LOC"], [1364, 1374, "LOC"], [1382, 1386, "LOC"], [1388, 1403, "LOC"], [1407, 1411, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 547, "text": "(A\nrocky, scrubby terrain with a bit of a settlement and some machinery\naround. A young boy runs to bring water to a couple of workers on a\nrig, when they see a small craft flying towards them.) \nMAKLII: (orange headband) Is it them? \nTESSIC: (red haired man) I don't know. No. It's not their ship. It's\nsomeone else. \n(as it comes in to land, we see that it is a shuttlepod. Pod 1 to be\nexact, and once it is down safely, Archer, T'Pol and Tucker climb out,\nwearing desert fatigues, to be met by the two men) \nARCHER: My name is Captain Archer from the starship Enterprise. We\ntried to hail you, but there was no response. \nTESSIC: Our communications are down. \nARCHER: That must make it difficult to do business. A Kreetassan\nmerchant told us this was a deuterium facility. \nTESSIC: He was correct. \nTUCKER: Our ship took some damage a few weeks ago. We lost most of our\nreserves. \nTESSIC: I'm sorry, but we can't help you. Two of our pumps are offline.\nYou'll have to return later in the season. \nARCHER: Our supply will be gone in less than two weeks. \nTESSIC: There's nothing we can do. \nT'POL: Are you certain? You seem to have a large inventory. Our sensors\nshowed over eighty thousand litres. \nTESSIC: You scanned our tanks? \nARCHER: I apologise, but when you didn't respond to our hails. You sure\nyou couldn't spare a few hundred litres? \nTESSIC: We're holding that for someone else. Come back at the end of\nthe season. I'm sure we'll be able to accommodate you. (Tessic starts to walk\naway.) \nMAKLII: Do you have any experience repairing extraction pumps? \nTUCKER: Not specifically, but I could grab some tools and take a look. \nMAKLII: (to Tessic) We get those pumps operating, we can make our\nquota. \nARCHER: It seems that there might be an opportunity for us to help each\nother. \nTESSIC: Follow me. (Archer and T'Pol do. Tucker returns to the pod for\nhis tools.) \n [Shuttlepod] \n (Tucker hears someone making gun noises. It's the boy,\nwho is startled when Trip activates an alarm.) \nTUCKER: What are you doing in my chair? \nQ'ELL: I didn't touch anything. I just like to look inside the ships", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[376, 381, "SHIP"], [423, 429, "PER"], [431, 436, "PER"], [441, 447, "PER"], [530, 544, "PER"], [563, 573, "SHIP"], [717, 727, "SPEC"], [1473, 1479, "PER"], [1651, 1657, "PER"], [1813, 1819, "PER"], [1824, 1829, "PER"], [1834, 1840, "PER"], [1894, 1900, "PER"], [1969, 1973, "PER"]]}
{"id": 548, "text": "[Cell]\n\n (Light streams in through roof windows onto Travis\nand Archer, who are lying on blankets on a hard floor.) \nTRAVIS: Captain? Sir? (No response, so Travis gets to his feet wearily and\nlooks around. The door is unlocked, so he opens it to see a pair of\nSuliban walking by. When the coast is clear, he goes exploring. Later -) \nARCHER: How many? \nTRAVIS: I saw at least thirty. This place is pretty big. There could be\nmore. \nARCHER: Any idea who attacked the shuttle? \nTRAVIS: I didn't exactly have time to get a good look. (Archer finally gets to his feet.) \nARCHER: The energy readings we got from\nthe other side of that moon could have come from a Helix. (Archer gives Travis\na leg up to look through a window.) \nTRAVIS: There's a wall about five metres high. It's looks like it\nsurrounds this entire building. I see something that might be a guard\ntower but I can't be sure. \nARCHER: Any people? \nTRAVIS: No, sir. (He gets down.) \nARCHER: You up for another walk? \n [Compound corridor] \n(Suliban look like they have pale yellow\nporridge for skin.)  WOMAN: You're the new arrivals. \nARCHER: Why are we here? \nWOMAN: Why are any of us here? (A siren goes off, other Suliban come\nout of their rooms and stand still. In the open area, four military\nlooking men walk around the Suliban there, until one drops his cup.\nWhen he bends to pick it up, the leader zaps his hand with his stick\nand moves on.) \nKLEV: (to Archer and Travis) Follow me. \n [Grat's office] \n (These military look almost entirely human except\nfor a small detail between the eyebrows.) \nGRAT: Thank you, Major. Please, sit down. (They remain standing.) GRAT: I can\nunderstand why you're upset. No doubt you've had a difficult afternoon.\n\nARCHER: To say the least. \nGRAT: I meant to speak to you earlier, but I had some urgent business\nto attend to. I apologise. We don't see many starship captains here.\n(reading from a PADD) Jonathan Archer. \nARCHER: That's right. \nGRAT: You must be Travis Mayweather.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[125, 132, "PER"], [53, 59, "PER"], [64, 70, "PER"], [156, 162, "PER"], [260, 267, "SPEC"], [532, 538, "PER"], [679, 685, "PER"], [666, 672, "PER"], [999, 1006, "SPEC"], [1175, 1182, "SPEC"], [1284, 1291, "SPEC"], [1419, 1425, "PER"], [1430, 1436, "PER"], [1452, 1458, "PER"], [1579, 1584, "PER"], [1901, 1916, "PER"], [1960, 1977, "PER"]]}
{"id": 549, "text": "[Armoury] \n (The\nwhole crew is present, with the senior crew together on the upper\nlevel, as Archer gives a speech.)\nARCHER: The most difficult task facing any Captain, any crew, is the\nloss of a shipmate. We've come here to honour one of our own. In the\ntime we knew him, he showed us just how much one life can truly matter.\nWe will never forget what he did for us, and for the ship he loved so\nmuch. We will go forward with renewed determination to complete this\nmission, so that his sacrifice won't just have been for the people on\nthis ship, but for all the citizens of Earth.\n(And the person laid out in the torpedo case is - Charles 'Trip' Tucker!) \n Two\nWeeks Earlier \n [T'Pol's\nquarters] \n (Tucker and T'Pol\nare lying on their sides, massaging each other's heels.) \nTUCKER: We just reroute the system taps, compress the antimatter stream\nbefore it reaches the injectors. \nT'POL: That will stabilise the warp field? \nTUCKER: Every simulation I run comes back with the same result. We'll\nbe able to cruise at warp five point oh with no field fluctuation. I'm\ntalking about a ride so smooth you could build a house of cards on the\nwarp reactor. \nT'POL: If we can maintain high warp for extended periods, we can cover\nthe Expanse more quickly. \nTUCKER: Which boosts our chances of finding the Xindi weapon in time. (T'Pol winces as he presses the wrong bit of her foot.) \nT'POL: To the left. \nTUCKER: Oh, sorry. You get me talking about the engines and I forget\nwhere I am. Don't know what it is about fine-tuning a piece of\nmachinery. \nT'POL: Lie on your back. \n(She kneels by his head.) \nTUCKER: You know, you made this sound a whole lot worse than it is.\nT'POL: Advanced neuro-pressure can place great demands on the body. \nTUCKER: Well, I have to say that so far, it's a piece of cake. \nT'POL: We haven't gotten to the more challenging postures. \n(She leans over him to press his ribcage.) \nTUCKER: Well, I'm always up for a challenge. \nT'POL: Breathe. \n [Engineering]", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 8, "LOC"], [93, 99, "PER"], [160, 167, "PER"], [575, 580, "LOC"], [632, 653, "PER"], [679, 686, "PER"], [700, 706, "PER"], [711, 716, "PER"], [1227, 1234, "LOC"], [1298, 1303, "SPEC"], [1321, 1326, "PER"], [1965, 1976, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 550, "text": "[Ready room]\n\n\n(Porthos is uneasy, and howls.) \nARCHER: Come here. \n(The little dog runs over to him.) \nARCHER: What's the problem? \n(He picks up a book from the floor.) \n [Engineering]\n\n\nCREWMAN: Commander? \nTUCKER: This can't be right. Did you run a diagnostic? \nCREWMAN: Twice. \nTUCKER: Let's check those relays. (In\nSickbay, the animals are restless. In the Mess hall, food is leaping up\nto the ceiling. A corridor floor flexes and knocks two crewmen over.) \n [Ready\nroom] \n\n(Archer's desk ripples, the coffee cup leaps into the air and just\nfloats there.) \nT'POL [OC]: Captain to the Bridge. \n [Bridge]\n\n T'POL:\nWe're getting reports of anomalies from all over the ship. \nTRAVIS: The warp field's fluctuating. \n [Engineering]\n\n (There\nare streams of energy coming from the warp engine) \nARCHER [OC]: Bridge to Engineering. Report. \nTUCKER: I don't get it, Captain. Half the plasma relays have reversed\npolarity. \nARCHER [OC]: Shut down the reactor. \nTUCKER: I'm trying, but it's not cooperating. \n [Bridge]\n\n TRAVIS:\nWe're losing main power. \n [Engineering]", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 11, "LOC"], [197, 206, "PER"], [320, 327, "LOC"], [362, 371, "LOC"], [465, 475, "LOC"], [480, 488, "PER"], [574, 581, "PER"], [589, 595, "LOC"], [600, 606, "LOC"], [718, 729, "LOC"], [805, 811, "ORG"], [815, 826, "ORG"], [861, 868, "PER"], [1004, 1010, "LOC"], [1050, 1061, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 551, "text": "Captain's Starlog, December 27, 2154. We're on course for the\nBerengarius system, a potential site for the first in a series of\nproposed Starbases. \n [Bridge] \nT'POL: A Vulcan science vessel surveyed the seventh\nplanet over fifty years ago. The file states it's an M class world with\na flourishing ecosystem. No intelligent life. \nARCHER: Sounds promising. \nT'POL: They did report one distinctive feature which bears mentioning. \nARCHER: And that is? \nT'POL: A species of flying reptile, some reportedly over two hundred\nmetres long. They're also said to breathe fire. There's been lingering\nquestions over the accuracy of this report. \nARCHER: Can't wait to find out. \nREED: There's a ship. It's on an intercept course. \nT'POL: I don't recognise the configuration. \nARCHER: Let's see it. \n(A rounded, green ship is on the viewscreen.) \nREED: Doesn't look very friendly. \nARCHER: Tactical Alert. Let's see what they want, Hoshi. \nHOSHI: They're responding. \n(The caller is green, wearing leather and with bits of metal on his\nhead.) \nHARRAD [on viewscreen]: Captain Archer. \nARCHER: And you are? \nHARRAD [on viewscreen]: Harrad-Sar. Deactivate your weapon systems\nimmediately, or I'll be forced to open fire. (pause for opening\nsequence) You're still targeting my ship. \nARCHER: And you're targeting mine. It seems we're at an impasse. \nHARRAD [on viewscreen]: Not for long. \nARCHER: Instead of sitting here pointing guns at each other, why don't\nwe deactivate our weapons together? \nHARRAD [on viewscreen]: Very well. (snaps fingers) \nARCHER: Now, what can we do for you? \nHARRAD [on viewscreen]: I have a proposal to make. \nARCHER: I'm listening. \nHARRAD [on viewscreen]: I prefer to discuss business in person. You're\ninvited aboard my ship. \nARCHER: We've dealt with your people before. The experience wasn't one\nI care to repeat. If you can give me some idea what this is about? \nHARRAD [on viewscreen]: What I have to say could smooth relations", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[62, 73, "LOC"], [151, 157, "LOC"], [169, 175, "SPEC"], [922, 927, "PER"], [1058, 1072, "PER"], [1121, 1131, "PER"]]}
{"id": 552, "text": "[Ready\nroom] \n T'POL: This text book is what you wanted me to\nsee? \nARCHER: Not exactly. (He holds the book cover up by the side of his computer\nscreen.) ARCHER: Look familiar? This was my first astronomy book. My father got\nit for me on my eighth birthday. I used to stare at the cover for\nhours. The Arachnid Nebula. Who'd ever have thought I'd get to see it\nin person. It's less than a light year away. We'll be there in a few\nhours. \nT'POL: (reading bookplate) From the library of Admiral Johnny Archer? \nARCHER: I had high hopes when I was a kid. (comm. chirps) Yes? \nREED [OC]: Sir, there's a ship approaching at half impulse. They're\nhailing us. \nARCHER: Do you know who it is? \nREED [OC]: Hoshi says they're using a Vulcan frequency. \n [Bridge] \n (A small ship with curved nacelles is on the\nviewscreen.) \nARCHER: Doesn't look like any Vulcan ship I've ever seen. \nT'POL: This class of vessel hasn't been used for a long time. \nHOSHI: They're hailing us again. \nTAVIN [on viewscreen]: Is this the Earth vessel Enterprise? \nARCHER: It is. I'm Captain Jonathan Archer.\nTAVIN [on viewscreen]: My name is Tavin, Captain of the Vahklas. It's\nvery good to meet you. (He's older, going grey, with a hint of a smile.)\n\nARCHER: I get the feeling you weren't sent out here by the High\nCommand. \nTAVIN [on viewscreen]: Not quite. We're a civilian ship. \nARCHER: What brings you out this far? \nTAVIN [on viewscreen]: I suppose you could say we're on a mission of\nexploration. \nARCHER: From what I'm told, Vulcans aren't that interested in\nexploring. \nTAVIN [on viewscreen]: We're not typical Vulcans. I'd be happy to\nexplain, but first I'd like to ask a favour. \nARCHER: Certainly. \nTAVIN [on viewscreen]: Our propulsion and life-support systems are in\nneed of repair. We'd be grateful for any assistance you could offer. \nARCHER: We'll see what we can do. \n [Captain's mess] \n (The two ships are docked together.)", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 11, "LOC"], [302, 317, "LOC"], [485, 506, "PER"], [724, 730, "SPEC"], [745, 751, "LOC"], [844, 850, "SPEC"], [1005, 1010, "LOC"], [1018, 1028, "SHIP"], [1050, 1073, "PER"], [1109, 1114, "PER"], [1131, 1138, "SHIP"], [1278, 1290, "ORG"], [1501, 1508, "SPEC"], [1588, 1595, "SPEC"], [1856, 1870, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 553, "text": "[Decon chamber, 8:47 pm] \n (Enterprise is orbiting a planet. Hoshi is putting\ngel on T'Pol's back, while T'Pol is smothering Archer's back and he is\ntreating Porthos.) \nARCHER: Starfleet didn't send us out here to humiliate ourselves. How\nlong were we in orbit, grovelling? Six days? \nHOSHI: Five, sir, and it wasn't exactly grovelling. \nARCHER: Apologising, asking forgiveness, just because we ate lunch in\nfront of them on our own ship months ago. I call that grovelling. \nHOSHI: They were offended. \nT'POL: The Kreetassans manufacture plasma injectors. We need one. \nARCHER: So we spend six days grovelling. \nHOSHI: Five days. \nARCHER: And when they finally agree to talk to us, we go down. And what\ndo they do? They keep us waiting for twelve hours and then send us\npacking. No explanation, no plasma injector. Just leave, go back to\nyour ship. \nT'POL: We obviously offended them again. \nARCHER: Maybe my hair's parted on the wrong side. I'm exhausted, and\nI've had it with these people. \nHOSHI: (answering comm.) Go ahead. \nPHLOX [OC]: The three of you are clear to go, but I'm afraid I'll need\nto keep Porthos for a while. \nARCHER: What's the problem? \nPHLOX [OC]: He picked up a pathogen of some kind on the surface.\nNeither decon agent has been effective. \nARCHER: What are you going to do? \nPHLOX [OC]: I'm not sure yet. I'll let you know as soon as I run some\ntests. \nHOSHI: (as she and T'Pol leave) Feel better, Porthos. \nARCHER: Doc'll have you good as new before you know it. I might even\nbreak the no-cheese rule tonight. (Archer goes to leave, and Porthos whimpers.)\nARCHER: Sorry, fella. You got to stay. \n [Engineering - 9:09 pm] \n TUCKER: We're playing with fire, Captain. It's\njust a matter of time before this injector gives up the ghost. \nARCHER: You've got four more. The ship can run on four. \nTUCKER: Yeah, but it can't run on three. You know what happens at warp\nspeed when you've only got three plasma injectors online. \nARCHER: What are the odds of us losing another one before we find a\nreplacement?", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 14, "LOC"], [28, 38, "SHIP"], [61, 66, "PER"], [85, 92, "PER"], [105, 110, "PER"], [125, 133, "PER"], [177, 186, "ORG"], [514, 525, "SPEC"], [1441, 1447, "PER"], [1682, 1689, "PER"]]}
{"id": 554, "text": "[Bridge] \n\n(Enterprise is flying close to a massive star.) \nT'POL: It's losing mass at an extraordinary rate. \nREED: How long before it goes supernova? \nT'POL: A hundred years, maybe two. \nARCHER: Too bad we won't be around. It's going to be one hell of an\nexplosion. \nT'POL: Speak for yourself. I might very well be around. \nTUCKER: Can't forget Vulcan longevity, Captain. A hundred years from\nnow? How old would that make you? \nARCHER: No earth ship has ever been within ten light years of a\nhypergiant. How much farther can we move in? \nT'POL: Our hull temperature is approaching eleven hundred degrees. It\nwould be unsafe to get any closer. \nARCHER: Then we'll have to run our scans from here. Tell Astrometrics\nto get going. I'm sure they're champing at the bit. \nREED: We may not be able to get any closer, but someone else has. \nARCHER: You found a ship? \nREED: Bearing two six one mark four. They must be at least twenty\nthousand kilometres farther in than we are. \nARCHER: Let's see her. (A ship comes up on the viewscreen.) ARCHER: Recognise\nit? \nT'POL: No. \nARCHER: Hail them. \nHOSHI: The interference is pretty heavy, sir. \nARCHER: Then try audio. This is Captain Archer of the starship\nEnterprise. I assume you've detected us. \nDRENNIK [OC]: Captain Drennik. Where have you travelled from? \nARCHER: The Sol system. And you? \nDRENNIK [OC]: We come from a system called Vissia, more than twenty\nfive light years from here. We saw you arrive yesterday. I assume\nyou're here to study the hypergiant. \nARCHER: My species has never seen one up close. \nDRENNIK [OC]: It is quite a sight. Have you measured its rate of\nnucleosynthesis? \nARCHER: I'm afraid we haven't developed the technology to do that. \nDRENNIK [OC]: If you don't mind eliminating the development stage, I'd\nbe more than happy to help you modify your sensors. \nARCHER: Thank you. I'm not sure we have anything to offer you in\nreturn. \nDRENNIK [OC]: You could invite us to visit your ship. Meeting new\nspecies is one of our primary goals.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 7, "LOC"], [12, 22, "SHIP"], [347, 353, "SPEC"], [365, 372, "PER"], [441, 446, "LOC"], [703, 715, "ORG"], [1168, 1182, "PER"], [1199, 1209, "SHIP"], [1263, 1270, "PER"], [1316, 1326, "LOC"], [1381, 1387, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 555, "text": "[Mess\nhall] \n (Enterprise is in orbit of a grey planet, and Reed\nand Travis are playing chess.) \nTRAVIS: You'll win in eight moves. \n(Reed turns the board around so they can set up a fresh game.) \nREED:\nYou're really starting to get a feel for the game. \nTRAVIS: Thirty two pieces, sixty four squares. It's not as if it's\ndifficult. The total number of possible outcomes is limited. \nREED: Ten to the one hundred twenty third power. \nTRAVIS: That's what I mean. Chess is so predictable, I'm surprised\nanyone bothers to play it. \n(The new game starts quickly, with Travis playing white.) \nREED:\nTheir average life span's only about a hundred years. With no time to\nplay all the possible games. \nTRAVIS: What a waste. \nREED: Careful. No emotional involvement. \nTRAVIS: I know the rules. Observation without interference. \n(Another speed-chess game finishes already.) \nTRAVIS: You'll win in five moves. \nREED: I'm the ship's champion. I win all the tournaments. \nTRAVIS: How do you think they'll react to what's on this planet? \nREED: Well, that's what we're here to find out, but in my experience,\nall physical species are alike. I don't expect humans will be any\ndifferent. \nTRAVIS: Do you think our hosts will die tonight? \nREED: It's possible. For some of the species that have come here, I've\nseen the whole crew die. For others, only a few. \nTRAVIS: But somebody always dies. \nREED: Always. \n(A new game is set up.) \nREED: Your move. \n[Shuttlepod]\n\n(An away team is returning from the planet.\nHoshi pulls something from her hair.\nHOSHI: I can't wait to get back. \nTUCKER: Two days ago, you couldn't wait to get off the ship. \nHOSHI: Sifting through a Klingon garbage dump. Not my idea of exploring\nstrange new worlds. \nTUCKER: Getting tired of exploration, Ensign? All the planets starting", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 10, "LOC"], [15, 25, "SHIP"], [60, 64, "PER"], [69, 75, "PER"], [134, 138, "PER"], [564, 570, "PER"], [1496, 1501, "PER"], [1654, 1661, "SPEC"], [1760, 1766, "PER"]]}
{"id": 556, "text": "(As\nEnterprise hangs motionless in space, a small vessel approaches.) \n [Alien ship] \n (Three males with enormous earlobes are seen in\nthe little ship - a fourth enters shot during the dialogue.) \nULIS: Kora noosa. Kora noosa! \nMUK: Irr zoun nagool ahsp. \nULIS: Uch. Cucht eeta ekrajhn-voy? \nGRISH: (piloting) Irr gnales. Nohm setron quethivoo. \nULIS: NanDi. Vanee eday. \n(They come alongside Enterprise and dock.) \n [Corridor] \n (They enter by the starboard airlock wearing\ngasmasks, and we see the crew slumped against the bulkheads,\nunconscious.) \nMUK: Cucht nee va zeh? (Krem sees how small human ears are,)\nKREM: Nass. (Muk tells him to hurry up.)\nMUK: Y-solah-na. Y-solah-na! \n [Mess hall] \n(Krem fingers some food.) MUK: Krem. Tenda sout\nbazul. Ningor. Ningor! \n [Engineering] \n(Awed by the engine.)  KREM: Oh! Gard-day latinum\nsou-tah! \nMUK: Lahje. Sapa-moul! (don't touch) \nKREM: Ehj saf-rey tomen-dee. \nMUK: Konah see-oh-mahj irr zoon. (Krem spots T'Pol lying against the bulkhead.) \nKREM: Ooo. Senpa tah-moy.\nLorala rrela. Latinum soun teyvalah. \nMUK: Ulis tenda vool. \n [Turbolift] \n MUK: Sa mopree. (They remove their gas masks.) \n [Bridge] \n (Everyone looks asleep at their posts) \nMUK: La-voy Daemon. (Krem sets off an alarm on helm.) MUK: Leru deemo mirra.\nMirra. (He gets out his communicator.) MUK: Muk lat Ulis. \n [Alien ship] \n ULIS: Klaxut. \nMUK [OC]: Feesha vou dolay. \nULIS: Rejahvey. \n [Decon chamber] \n (Tucker wakes up. He is wearing blue singlet and shorts.) \nTUCKER: Doc, isn't my time up yet? You", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[4, 14, "SHIP"], [393, 403, "SHIP"], [685, 694, "LOC"], [771, 782, "LOC"], [947, 951, "PER"], [958, 963, "PER"], [1083, 1092, "LOC"], [1146, 1152, "LOC"], [1217, 1221, "PER"], [1495, 1498, "PER"]]}
{"id": 557, "text": "(We see\nthe crew out cold, on the floor or slumped over their duty stations.) \nT'POL [OC]: Science officer's log, August 14, 2152. Enterprise remains\non course for the trinary system. I've transmitted a distress call but\nthe nearest Vulcan ship is more than nine days away. By the time they\narrive, they may only find debris, if that. Even if Enterprise makes it\npast the black hole without being destroyed, it seems likely the crew\nwon't survive. \n [T'Pol's quarters] \n T'POL: I'm continuing my analysis of the condition\nthat's stricken the crew. Without Doctor Phlox's assistance I'm not\nhopeful about reversing its effects. I'm documenting my findings so\nthat Starfleet will at least have a record of what happened. The\nsymptoms began not long after we set a course for the trinary system.\nThat was nearly two days ago. \n [Situation room] \n ARCHER: You're sure it's a black hole? \nT'POL: A class four. \nARCHER: According to the Vulcan star charts, your people have surveyed\nmore than two thousand of these things. \nT'POL: That's correct, but none of them were part of a trinary star\nsystem. \nARCHER: How close can we get? \nT'POL: The gravitational shear between the stars is extreme. We'd have\nto drop to impulse, but we should be able to approach to within five\nmillion kilometres. \nTUCKER: Close enough to get some nice pictures. \nARCHER: How long would it take to reach the system at impulse? \nT'POL: Two days. \nARCHER: Set a course. (T'Pol leaves them.) ARCHER: Trip. If you've got some free\ntime, I'd love it if you take a look at my chair. \nTUCKER: Sir? \nARCHER: The Captain's chair. \nTUCKER: Wh-What about it? \nARCHER:: You may have noticed that I don't sit in it very much. \nTUCKER: Is there a problem? \nARCHER: It's uncomfortable. When I lean back I feel like I'm about to\nslide out of it. I have to sort of perch on the edge. \nTUCKER: I always assumed it was the best seat in the house. \nARCHER: Take a look at it for me? \nTUCKER: I was going to purge the impulse manifolds. \nARCHER: The chair first, if you don't mind.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[131, 141, "SHIP"], [233, 239, "SPEC"], [343, 353, "SHIP"], [451, 458, "PER"], [556, 570, "PER"], [663, 672, "ORG"], [931, 937, "SPEC"], [1469, 1473, "PER"], [1576, 1585, "PER"]]}
{"id": 558, "text": "[Mess\nhall] \n ETHAN: How can you eat that stuff? (She is eating soup and reading about termites.)\nCUTLER:  It's healthier\nthan that. \nETHAN: At least this tastes like something. \nCUTLER: I guess it just takes a more discriminating palate to\nappreciate Vulcan cuisine. Do you know there are over five thousand\nsubspecies of termites on Loracus Prime? \n(A glow comes in through the window, every one gets up and looks at a\nbeautiful blue planet.) \nETHAN: I thought we were headed for a nebula. \nCUTLER: Anybody hear about this? \nCREWMAN: Not a word. \nCUTLER: I wonder if somebody lives there? \nETHAN: There's a lot of plant life. It might be an oxygen atmosphere. \nCUTLER: What do you think, first contact? \nCREWMAN: I don't see any cities or agriculture. \nETHAN: Maybe they live underground or in the water. \nCUTLER: Is that snow on those mountains? \nETHAN: You'd think the Captain would make an announcement or something.\n\nCUTLER: Well, call him. \n [Bridge] \n ARCHER: T'Pol. \nT'POL: Seventeen percent oxygen, eighty one percent nitrogen. \nTUCKER: Sounds like home. \nARCHER: Any people? \nT'POL: The planet supports a diverse ecology, but there are no signs of\nhumanoid life. \nARCHER: Still, someone may have a claim on it. We don't want to go\nwaltzing into their back yard. Scan for marker buoys, beacons, man-made\nsatellites. \nREED: None in range, sir. Looks like no one's planted a flag just yet. \nARCHER: Prep a shuttlepod, Mister Tucker. (Tucker starts to leave) I\nlike the looks of the northern continent. See if you can find a good\nplace to set down. \nTRAVIS: Yes, sir. \nT'POL: Captain. There are a number of protocols you may want to\nconsider. \nARCHER: Protocols. \nT'POL: Vulcan ships would begin by sending automated probes down to", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 10, "LOC"], [252, 258, "SPEC"], [335, 348, "LOC"], [873, 880, "PER"], [950, 956, "LOC"], [968, 973, "PER"], [1426, 1439, "PER"], [1442, 1448, "PER"], [1583, 1590, "PER"], [1678, 1684, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 559, "text": "[Shuttle]\n\n (Degra wakes up on the floor of a small vessel.\nHe's dishevelled, his hair is long, and they are being attacked.) \nDEGRA: who are you? (Archer is at the controls, also dishevelled with long hair.) \nARCHER: They're\ntargeting our engines. \nDEGRA: What do you want with me? \nARCHER: You're the weapons expert. See if you can get those shields\nback online. If we don't raise the shields, the only that's going to be\nleft of this ship is a cloud of vapour. (He pushes Degra aside and does it\nhimself. Degra looks out of the porthole.)\nDEGRA: Insectoids! \nARCHER: These could be shield emitters. They're not going to last for\nlong. \nDEGRA: Open a channel to those ships. \nARCHER: What? \nDEGRA: They're Xindi. I'll order them to hold their fire. \nARCHER: It's been a long time since any Xindi took orders from you.\nWe're carrying five hundred litres of warp plasma in the starboard\ntanks. We'll have to vent it. Turn these down on my mark. They're going\nto destroy us. Now! \nDEGRA: What happened? \nARCHER: The plasma got into their intake manifolds. Their engines are\noverheating. \nDEGRA: I want to know who you are. Why you've abducted me. \nARCHER: You really don't remember. I was afraid this might happen. It's\nme, Archer. \nDEGRA: What species are you? \nARCHER: You've been through a lot in the last two days. Just let me\nfigure out \nDEGRA: What species! \nARCHER: I'm human. (Degra backs away as far as he can.) \nDEGRA: You're from the Earth vessel. \nARCHER: Degra, you have to listen to me. I'm not your enemy anymore.\nYou've spent the last two days in an interrogation chamber. Whatever\nthe insectoids did to you in there must have affected your memory. My\nname is Jonathan Archer. The two of us just escaped from an insectoid\nprison colony. \nDEGRA: Prison? \nARCHER: We've shared a cell for almost three years. \nDEGRA: That's not possible.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[13, 18, "PER"], [148, 154, "PER"], [475, 480, "PER"], [508, 513, "PER"], [708, 713, "SPEC"], [792, 797, "SPEC"], [1376, 1381, "SPEC"], [1384, 1389, "PER"], [1444, 1449, "LOC"], [1467, 1472, "PER"], [1675, 1690, "PER"], [1727, 1736, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 560, "text": "[Bridge]\n\n (On the viewscreen is a battered looking object,\ndrifting in space.) \nARCHER: Biosigns? \nT'POL: None that I can detect, but its hull seems to be scattering our\nsensors. \nARCHER: Any idea what happened? \nREED: I'm not reading any weapons signatures. Possibly some sort of\naccident. \nARCHER: Bring it into Launch bay two. \n [Launch bay two] \n REED: There's no windows. I'm not sure whether\nthis end's the bow or the stern. \nT'POL: Captain. This might be a hatch. \nREED: If it is, it's been fused shut. With your permission, sir? \n(He gets a phase pistol and starts cutting into the thing. When he's\ndone, Archer forced the hatch open and starts coughing. T'Pol checks\nthat the air inside is safe. Archer climbs inside and finds a seat at\nthe far end. He turns it around to discover a desiccated occupant.) \nT'POL: He's human. \n [Sickbay] \n PHLOX: This was a human male. A microcellular scan\nshould tell us his age at the time of death. Apparently, you're not the\nfirst humans out this far. \nARCHER: Whoever this is, he's rewritten our history books. Can you get\na DNA sample? \nPHLOX: The tissue damage is extensive, but I should be able to isolate\na few fragments. \nARCHER: If he's a member of Starfleet, his genetic profile is probably\nin our database. Run a comparison as soon as you can. \nPHLOX: Absolutely. \n(T'Pol enters.) \n\nT'POL: There aren't any ships or inhabited systems for several light\nyears. \nARCHER: I wonder if this could be Zephram Cochrane. They say he was\npiloting a one-man vessel when he disappeared. \nT'POL: How could he have travelled this far? \nARCHER: There were a lot of rumours after he was lost. One of them said\nhe was testing some kind of experimental warp ship. Any markings on the\nhull or control panels? \nT'POL: We haven't found any.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 7, "LOC"], [334, 348, "LOC"], [440, 447, "PER"], [614, 620, "PER"], [664, 669, "PER"], [706, 712, "PER"], [828, 833, "SPEC"], [838, 845, "LOC"], [867, 872, "SPEC"], [1203, 1212, "ORG"], [1322, 1327, "PER"], [1450, 1466, "PER"]]}
{"id": 561, "text": "[Holodeck - Proton's\nship]\n\n(We are back in the land of black and white Saturday afternoon serials at the cinema.)NARRATOR:\nThe Adventures of Captain Proton! Chapter Eighteen: Bride of Chaotica! The\nevil Doctor Chaotica kidnaps Constance Goodheart and plans to sacrifice\nher to Arachnia, Queen of the Spider People. (Constance screams, Chaotica laughs.) Captain Proton travels\nmillions of miles to Planet X where he will invade the Fortress of\nDoom. Chaotica fires his fiendish Death Ray. Certain death for Proton\nas his rocket ship bursts into flames.KIM: We\ndidn't burst into flames in the last chapter. Why are these recaps\nalways so inaccurate? \nPARIS: Well, they brought people back to the theatres. \nKIM: Cliff-hangers. \nPARIS: The lost art of hyperbole. You ready? \nKIM: Aye, Captain. \nPARIS: Let's get this show on the road. Computer, begin Chapter Eighteen. \nKIM: We're receiving a transmission. It's Chaotica. \nPARIS: Imagising. \nCHAOTICA [on imagiser]: Captain Proton. Surrender! \nPARIS: Not a chance. Release Miss Goodheart and we'll be on our way. \nCHAOTICA [on imagiser]: I'm afraid your secretary has already been\npromised to Queen\nArachnia as a Supreme Sacrifice. (Constance screams.) \nKIM: You'll never get away with this. \nCHAOTICA [on imagiser]: Oh, ho ho ho, but I shall. You escaped from my\nDeath Ray once, but you won't survive this! \nKIM: He's charging the weapon. \nPARIS: Brace for impact. \nKIM: Direct hit. We lost both engines. \nPARIS: Steering jets are on the fritz.(The periscope reveals a range of mountains dead ahead.)\nKIM: We're going down! \nPARIS: The landing gear is jammed. Hang on!  (They get shaken about a bit.)\nKIM: Opening hatch. \nPARIS: Welcome to Planet X. \nKIM: What's the plan? \nPARIS: This is the part where we defeat Chaotica's soldiers, steal\ntheir uniforms, and make our way through the underground caverns. \nKIM: Hey, I thought you said there were slave girls in this chapter. \nPARIS: After we infiltrate the Fortress of Doom, we'll free Chaotica's\nharem. Let's go.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[12, 20, "PER"], [1, 9, "LOC"], [142, 156, "PER"], [185, 193, "PER"], [204, 219, "PER"], [228, 247, "PER"], [278, 314, "PER"], [317, 326, "PER"], [336, 344, "PER"], [354, 368, "PER"], [398, 406, "LOC"], [432, 448, "LOC"], [450, 458, "PER"], [507, 513, "PER"], [783, 790, "PER"], [910, 918, "PER"], [964, 978, "PER"], [1021, 1035, "PER"], [1141, 1155, "PER"], [1689, 1697, "LOC"], [1763, 1773, "PER"], [1958, 1974, "LOC"], [1987, 1997, "PER"]]}
{"id": 562, "text": "[Holodeck]\n\n(The Doctor is showing off the photographs he has taken with his holo-imager. His audience is less than enthralled.)EMH:\nAnd, since I was the only crewmember who could survive the corrosive\natmosphere, it was up to me to retrieve the data module and save the\nday. Ah, here I am, mission accomplished. Then of course there was the\nperilous mission to Lav'oti V. You remember that one, don't you Mister\nParis? \nPARIS: How could I forget. \nEMH: Here you are after your unfortunate slip into the fetid mud pits\nof Palomar. (Torres laughs.)\nPARIS: Hey, I was pushed. \nEMH: Of course you were. \nJANEWAY: Thank you, Doctor. We've all enjoyed your holo-images\nenormously. \nEMH: Oh, but I haven't finished yet.\nTORRES: There's more? \nEMH: The best is yet to come, Lieutenant. I've created a fascinating\ntwelve part holographic essay which I call 'Under the Skin'. Humanoid\nanatomy as art. Let's begin with this stunning magnification of the\nVulcan reproductive gland. Note the composition, the subtle variations\nin colour. \n [Bridge]\n\n KIM:\nTwenty one hundred hours, Commander. All systems reporting normal. \nCHAKOTAY: Acknowledged. \nKIM: Like I said, it's twenty one hundred hours. \nCHAKOTAY: I heard you the first time, Harry. \nKIM: They've been in there over an hour. \nCHAKOTAY: I'm aware of that. \nKIM: Didn't the Captain ask you to rescue them after thirty minutes? \nCHAKOTAY: Harry, you and I were lucky enough to enjoy the Doctor's\nscintillating exhibition for two full hours. Would it really be fair of\nus to deny our friends the same unforgettable experience? \nKIM: Of course not, sir. \n [Holodeck]\n\n(Janeway hands off her large coffee mug to the Doctor as she leaves stony-faced.)EMH:\nThank you. thank you for coming. We'll do it again soon. We've still\ngot thousands of light years to while away. This could be a weekly\nevent.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 9, "LOC"], [17, 23, "PER"], [362, 371, "LOC"], [406, 418, "PER"], [522, 529, "LOC"], [532, 538, "PER"], [621, 627, "PER"], [767, 777, "PER"], [867, 875, "SPEC"], [944, 950, "SPEC"], [1029, 1035, "LOC"], [1070, 1079, "PER"], [1225, 1230, "PER"], [1321, 1328, "PER"], [1385, 1390, "PER"], [1433, 1441, "PER"], [1601, 1609, "LOC"], [1613, 1620, "PER"], [1659, 1665, "PER"]]}
{"id": 563, "text": "Captain's log, stardate\n51367.2: We've spent the last three days on the Mari homeworld. It's\nbeen a while since we've had the opportunity to make new friends and\nthe crew seems to be making the most of our stay. \n [Transporter room] \n(Paris gets off the transporter pad carrying a large brown package.)PARIS:\nNeelix. \nNEELIX: Tom. Been doing a little shopping? \nPARIS: It's a present for B'Elanna. \nNEELIX: What is it? \nPARIS: Well, it's sort of personal. \nNEELIX: Of course. Say no more. I'm on my way for a little romantic\nrendezvous myself. (Paris sniffs the air, then Neelix.)\nPARIS: Neelix, are you wearing cologne? \nNEELIX: Talchok musk. Very enticing scent, don't you think? \nPARIS: Well, it certainly is musky. \nNEELIX: I'm going to see Talli again. \nPARIS: Ooo, that was fast work. Where are you taking her? \nNEELIX: Well, actually I haven't gotten that far yet. I'm going to\nvisit her shop under the pretext of buying some produce for the ship,\nand then I thought I'd just sort of segue smoothly into some dinner and\ndancing. \nPARIS: Sounds like a good strategy. \nNEELIX: Do you really think so? I mean, you used to be quite the lady's\nman. \nPARIS: Used to be? \nNEELIX: I mean, of course, you're involved now, so you won't be\navailing yourself of all the beautiful, fascinating and very\nopen-minded Mari women. \nPARIS: Neelix, are you trying to depress me? \nNEELIX: I just, I haven't been with anyone since Kes, and I'm feeling a\nlittle rusty. I could use some advice. \nPARIS: The best advice I can give you is to just be yourself. \nNEELIX: Right. Be myself. \nPARIS: Actually, that's the second best piece of advice. \nNEELIX: What's the first? \nPARIS: Go a little easier on the musk. \n \n[Market place] \n(Janeway is haggling over the price of metal ittems.)JANEWAY: I'm sorry, Mister Guill, but that's my final offer. \nGUILL: Actually, Captain, I sense you'd be willing to raise your price", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[72, 76, "SPEC"], [215, 231, "LOC"], [235, 240, "PER"], [309, 315, "PER"], [326, 329, "PER"], [388, 396, "PER"], [545, 550, "PER"], [572, 578, "PER"], [588, 594, "PER"], [630, 637, "SPEC"], [745, 750, "PER"], [1309, 1313, "SPEC"], [1329, 1335, "PER"], [1417, 1420, "PER"], [1714, 1721, "PER"], [1786, 1798, "PER"], [1845, 1852, "PER"]]}
{"id": 564, "text": "[Planet surface]\n\n(Birds\nfly into the air of a purple-skied planet as a small Borg Sphere\ncrashes into a swampy area. Its four survivors clamber from the wreckage.)\nTWO OF NINE: Input failure. \nFOUR OF NINE: Input failure. \nTHREE OF NINE: Input failure. \nSEVEN OF NINE: Our link to the Collective has been severed. Initiate\nsecondary protocols. The vessel's transwarp chamber is approaching\ncritical pressure. We must evacuate this area. \nALL: Agreed. \nTWO OF NINE: No directional coordinates available. \nSEVEN OF NINE: That way. Bearing three zero one. \nALL: Agreed: \nSEVEN OF NINE: Bring that drone. \nCaptain's\nlog: stardate 53049.2. We've docked at the Markonian outpost and agreed\nto mutual visits, so I'm allowing shore leave to anyone who wants it.\nCommander Tuvok has objected to taking on too many visitors, but\nsecurity issues aside, I'm looking forward to a cultural exchange, and\nmaking some new friends. \n[Ready\nroom]\n\n(Voyager is docked at a space station or\ndrift. Chakotay carries a strange object with four hinged arms through\nthe bridge, trying not to hit anyone with their tennis racket style\nends as they flap around.)CHAKOTAY:\nCaptain? (There is a large plant on her desk, others by the window and many more bits and pieces scattered around the room.) \nJANEWAY: I'll be right with you. The station manager didn't tell me the\nvines were prehensile. I went to put some water in the pot and it\ngrabbed me. \nCHAKOTAY: This is a gift from the Kinbori delegation. I don't know its\nname, only that it's used in one of their sacred games and it's very\nheavy. \nJANEWAY: Put it down anywhere. Thank the Kinbori for me and give them a\ntoken of our esteem. (She hands Chakotay a book.)\nCHAKOTAY: I already gave them a Voyager medallion. They seemed\nappreciative.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[78, 89, "SHIP"], [282, 296, "ORG"], [656, 665, "SPEC"], [755, 770, "PER"], [918, 928, "LOC"], [932, 939, "SHIP"], [979, 987, "PER"], [1043, 1053, "LOC"], [1147, 1154, "PER"], [1458, 1465, "SPEC"], [1613, 1620, "SPEC"], [1676, 1684, "PER"], [1726, 1733, "SHIP"]]}
{"id": 565, "text": "[Mess Hall]\n\n(Neelix\nis pouring an orange drink.) \nNEELIX: Anthraxic citrus peel, orange juice with just a hint of papalla\nseed extract. An experimental blend. \nTUVOK: The success rate of your culinary experiments has not been high.\n\nNEELIX: Ensign Golwat tried some yesterday, and she thought it was\ndelicious. In fact, she had a second glass, and she never has seconds. \nTUVOK: Ensign Golwat is Bolian. Her tongue has a cartilaginous lining.\nIt would protect her against even the most corrosive acid. \nNEELIX: All I ask is that you try it, Mister Vulcan. \n(Tuvok\n\nsniffs and sips.) \nTUVOK: Impressive. \nNEELIX: Ah! I'll start squeezing that second glass. Breakfast is coming\nright up. Porakan eggs. \nTUVOK: Porakan? \nNEELIX: The most flavourful eggs in the sector. Scrambled with a little\ndill weed, a touch of rengazo, a galactic favourite. Now, these eggs\nwere not easy to prepare. After we picked them up on Porakas Four, I\nhad to sterilise them in a cryostatic chamber for three days. Then each\nand every one had to be parboiled \nTUVOK: Mister Neelix, I would prefer not to hear the life history of my\nbreakfast. \nNEELIX: On Talax it's a tradition to share the history of a meal before\nyou begin eating. It's a way of enhancing the culinary experience. My\nmother was brilliant. She could make every course, every garnish come\nalive by making it a character in a story. My favourite was the one\nabout the crustacean who \n(Flames surge up around the egg pan, setting the contents alight.\nNeelix quickly smothers it with a lid.) \nTUVOK: What happened? \nNEELIX: Er, some sort of power overload. I'm afraid it decimated your\nbreakfast. This is what my mother would call a tragic ending. \nTUVOK: Engineering has been making adjustments to the plasma conduits\nto accommodate a new energy source. It may have created a thermal surge\nin the galley systems. \nJANEWAY [OC]: Janeway to Tuvok. Please report to the bridge. Mister", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 10, "LOC"], [14, 20, "PER"], [242, 255, "PER"], [380, 393, "PER"], [397, 403, "SPEC"], [542, 555, "PER"], [559, 564, "PER"], [687, 694, "LOC"], [709, 716, "LOC"], [913, 925, "LOC"], [1043, 1056, "PER"], [1131, 1136, "PER"], [1410, 1420, "SPEC"], [1492, 1498, "PER"], [1696, 1707, "ORG"], [1869, 1876, "PER"], [1880, 1885, "PER"]]}
{"id": 566, "text": "Captain's log, stardate\n48693.2. We've altered course to investigate some unusually intense\nphotonic activity in a nearby protostar. Lieutenant Torres and I are\nbeaming aboard samples for further analysis. \n [Engineering]\n\n TORRES:\nContainment field is active. We're ready for transport.\nJANEWAY: Energise.\n(Glowing orange gas fills a container.) \nTORRES: That's strange. Both containers should have been filled.\nJANEWAY: Here's the problem. A slight breach in the annular confinement\nbeam.\nTORRES: I'm aborting transport. Okay, let's try that again. Energising.\n\n(Both containers fill this time.) \nTORRES: All right. I'll get a complete phase spectrum analysis on this\nas soon as possible.\nJANEWAY: If this photonic matter works as well as I think, it could\nboost the efficiency of our power converters fifteen percent.\nTORRES: I'd say more like twenty.\nJANEWAY: How long will it take to finish the preliminary analysis?\nTORRES: Um, six hours. Maybe more.\nJANEWAY: I'd like to get it sooner than that. I believe Ensign Kim is\noff duty. Could you use his help?\nTORRES: Can you convince him to give up his free time?\nJANEWAY: I think I might be able to. Janeway to Kim. That's odd.\nComputer, locate Ensign Kim.\nCOMPUTER: Unable to comply. Ensign Kim is not aboard the ship. \n \n[Bridge] \n TUVOK:\nSensor logs show no record of any unauthorised transporter activity and\nall shuttlecraft are accounted for. If Ensign Kim left the ship, he did\nnot do so by conventional means.\nCHAKOTAY: His last shift ended four hours ago, and he was scheduled for\ntime on holodeck two when he went off duty. No one has seen him since.\nJANEWAY: Scan the holodeck. What's the matter?\nTUVOK: There is significant interference in the holodeck. I cannot\nobtain a clear scan.\nJANEWAY: Is it a system malfunction?", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[133, 150, "PER"], [209, 220, "LOC"], [1013, 1023, "PER"], [1153, 1160, "PER"], [1164, 1167, "PER"], [1198, 1208, "PER"], [1238, 1248, "PER"], [1277, 1283, "LOC"], [1405, 1415, "PER"], [1632, 1640, "LOC"], [1709, 1717, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 567, "text": "[Shuttlecraft]\n\nPARIS:\nWarp five. Warp six. Warp seven. I've reached critical velocity. \nTORRES [OC]: Okay. Everything looks good on this end. Fire up the new\nengines. \nPARIS: Acknowledged. Engaging transwarp drive in four, three, two.\nTranswarp online. Warp nine point two, nine point three. My vector's\ndrifting. \nKIM [OC]: Try to stabilise your field symmetry. \nPARIS: Got it. Warp nine point six, nine point seven. I'm reading a\nfracture in the port nacelle pylon. \nTORRES [OC]: Full power to structural integrity. \nPARIS: Warp nine point nine, nine point nine five. I'm approaching the\nthreshold, but the nacelle isn't holding! \nKIM [OC]: Tie in auxiliary power! \nPARIS: It's no use. I'm breaking up! I'm breaking \n[Holodeck]\n\n(Paris\nis sitting on the floor.) \nTORRES: You're dead.\n\n[Mess\nhall]\n\nTORRES:\nIt's the pylon again. Every time we get close to crossing the\nthreshold, the subspace torque rips a nacelle off the shuttle. \nKIM: What about a duranium alloy? We could try using it to reinforce \nTORRES: No, I've thought about that already. It's too brittle. \nNEELIX: More coffee? Ah, you look like a happy bunch. \nKIM: We've hit a wall. \nNEELIX: Oh. Well, maybe I can help. \nPARIS: Great. Do you know anything about quantum warp theory or\nmulti-spectral subspace engine design? \nNEELIX: No. But I'm a quick study. What are we working on? \n(Neelix sits and looks at the array of PADDS.) \nTORRES: Do you have anything to eat? \nNEELIX: Sure. There's some Kalavian biscuits, somewhere in the kitchen.\n\nTORRES: I guess I'll go find them myself. Fill him in. \nKIM: Neelix, it would take too long to", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[721, 729, "LOC"], [733, 738, "PER"], [789, 798, "LOC"], [1350, 1356, "PER"], [1569, 1575, "PER"]]}
{"id": 568, "text": "[Pseudo Ready room]\n\n(We know this is not real, because\nJaneway's hair is swept back and she is wearing a black roll-neck top\nbeneath her uniform, and black leather gloves. Very sinister. Her words\nare also very non-Janeway and there is no comm. badge.)pJANEWAY:\nWhen diplomacy fails there's only one alternative. Violence. Force must\nbe applied without apology. It's the Starfleet way. \nDALETH: Then our philosophies are in agreement. Will you help us? \npJANEWAY: You're asking me to fight your war, destroy your enemy. \nDALETH: I'm asking you to intimidate the Kyrians with your technology.\nHelp me capture their leader. This ship has superior firepower. He\nwon't risk a conflict with you. \npJANEWAY: We risk life and limb so your people can annex Kyrian land.\nSounds like a good deal for you. What do we get? \nDALETH: A way home. \npJANEWAY: You know more about Voyager than you've let on. \nDALETH: Your reputation in this quadrant precedes you. That's why we\nsought you out. \npJANEWAY: I'm listening. \nDALETH: There's a cyclic wormhole five days journey from here. We know\nwhere it is, and we can help you stabilise it. \npJANEWAY: If you're lying. \nDALETH: How far do you have to go? Sixty thousand light years? \npJANEWAY: I want all tactical data regarding your little war. Kyrian\ndefences, position of your own forces, everything. \nDALETH: You'll have it within the hour. \n [Pseudo\nBridge] \n(A Kazon walks through with a phaser rifle. Neelix is in uniform at Tactical.)pNEELIX: Eight Kyrian fighter ships approaching. \npJANEWAY: Arm the assault probes. Fire at will. Hail them. \npTUVOK: Channel open. \npJANEWAY: This is Captain Janeway of the warship Voyager. Break off\nyour attack, or I'll destroy you. \npTUVOK: They are not responding. \npPARIS: They're returning fire. Shields are holding. \npJANEWAY: Chakotay, any luck tracking down their leader? (Chakotay\nhas a different tattoo, one that extends all down the left side of his\nface. Every pronounces his name without the emphasis on the middle\nsyllable.)\npCHAKOTAY: Not yet. We think Tedran has go-ne into hiding.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 18, "LOC"], [56, 65, "PER"], [216, 223, "PER"], [372, 381, "ORG"], [563, 570, "SPEC"], [750, 756, "SPEC"], [864, 871, "SHIP"], [1278, 1284, "SPEC"], [1380, 1393, "LOC"], [1399, 1404, "SPEC"], [1440, 1446, "PER"], [1464, 1472, "LOC"], [1489, 1495, "SPEC"], [1625, 1640, "PER"], [1656, 1663, "SHIP"], [1808, 1816, "PER"], [1856, 1864, "PER"], [2043, 2049, "PER"]]}
{"id": 569, "text": "(A comet flies through space, its tail streaming out towards the Delta Flyer.)[Delta Flyer - aft\ncompartment]\n\n(A piece of it is beamed into a sample jar. The ship shakes.)EMH:\nEnsign Kim, please try and hold us steady. This material is extremely \n[Delta\nFlyer - cockpit]\n\nEMH\n[OC]: Fragile. \nKIM: Sorry, Doc. I'm doing the best I can. \nEMH [OC]: Maybe I should've insisted \n[Delta\nFlyer - aft compartment]\n\nEMH: On\na more experienced pilot, like Mister Paris. \n[Delta\nFlyer - cockpit]\n\nKIM: I'd\ngive anything to trade places with him right now. \nEMH [OC]: Seven, can you join me, please? \nSEVEN: On my way. \nKIM: I don't know if I can take three more days of chasing comets with\nhim.\nSEVEN: The time might pass more easily if we disable his vocal\nprocessor. \n[Delta\nFlyer - aft compartment] \nEMH: I\nthought you might find this interesting. (The EMH puts a small piece of comet under a microscope and calls the image up on a monitor.)\nSEVEN: Preanimate biomatter. \nEMH: Look deeper. \nSEVEN: An undeveloped nucleus contained in a cytoplasmic matrix. \nEMH: And buried deep inside that nucleus, primitive strands of DNA. The\nbeginnings of life, Seven. \nSEVEN: What's your point? \nEMH: When I look at this, I don't see a mere cell. I see the potential\nfor literature and art, empires and kingdoms. \nSEVEN: Perhaps your visual subroutines are malfunctioning. \nEMH: Someday, this cytoplasmic matrix may fall into the primordial sea", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[65, 76, "SHIP"], [79, 90, "SHIP"], [177, 187, "PER"], [249, 260, "SHIP"], [376, 387, "SHIP"], [447, 459, "PER"], [463, 474, "SHIP"], [557, 562, "PER"], [761, 772, "SHIP"], [846, 849, "PER"]]}
{"id": 570, "text": "[Shuttlecraft]\n\n(A standard Starfleet shuttlecraft is flying\nover a lush green forest.) \nCHAKOTAY: Beautiful, isn't it? \nSEVEN: A sensor analysis would have provided the necessary information.\n\nCHAKOTAY: Just admiring the view. \nSEVEN: The conference begins in less than an hour. \nCHAKOTAY: There's always time for Warp Field Dynamics, but you don't\nsee natural beauty like this every day. (Whumph)CHAKOTAY: What was that? \nSEVEN: Some kind of energy barrier directly below us. It spans\nthousands of square kilometres. \nCHAKOTAY: Why didn't our sensors detect it? \nSEVEN: Uncertain. It has an unusual tetrion signature. Species three\none two used a similar technology. There's a power surge coming from\nthe barrier. \nCHAKOTAY: Shields at full. \nSEVEN: They're creating some kind of feedback. We've lost impulse\nengines. \nCHAKOTAY: Go to warp. \nSEVEN: The warp core is offline. \nCHAKOTAY: Warp engines don't just shut down when you scrape an energy\nbarrier. \nSEVEN: It's affecting all our systems. \nCOMPUTER: Warning. Structural failure in thirty seconds. \nCHAKOTAY: We'll have to beam to the surface. \nSEVEN: We can't transport through the barrier. Transfer auxiliary power\nto the weapons array. \nCHAKOTAY: What are you trying to do? \nSEVEN: If I can realign our phasers to the correct frequency, I may be\nable to open a rift. \nCHAKOTAY: Big enough to get a shuttle through, I hope? \nCOMPUTER: Warning. Structural failure in ten seconds, nine, eight. \nSEVEN: Phasers reconfigured.(Chakotay\nfires the phaser and flies the shuttlecraft through the resulting hole.\nThey lose the nacelles as they go through, and beam out as the\nshuttlecraft tumbles to the ground.)\n\n[Jungle]\n\nSEVEN: The barrier's closed again. (Chakotay's leg has been cut. He can barely walk on it.) SEVEN: I", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[28, 37, "ORG"], [620, 641, "SPEC"], [1481, 1489, "PER"], [1709, 1719, "PER"]]}
{"id": 571, "text": "[Holodeck -\nSandrine's] \n KIM:\nGame. \nPARIS: Why don't we make it interesting this time. Let's add some table\nstakes. \nKIM: What kind of stakes? \nPARIS: I don't know. Hmm. Couple of replicator rations, maybe? \nRICKY: Don't do it, Harry. He's hustling you. \nKIM: Wait a minute. Are you saying he deliberately let me win? \nPARIS: That would be dishonest, Harry. \nKIM: I won that game, and I'll beat you again. \nPARIS: How many rations are you willing to bet on that? \nCREWMEMBERS: Go for it, Harry. \nKIM: A week's worth. \nPARIS: Harry, Harry, Harry. Never, ever play with anyone, not even your\nbest friend, if he says let's make it interesting. You want a little\naction, I'll give you a little action. How about an honest game of\nchance? \nRICKY: Never play with anyone, even your best friend, if he offers you\nan honest game of chance, Harry. \nPARIS: One replicator ration is all it takes to play, and the only\nthing you have to do to win is pick a number. Just predict what the\nradiogenic particle count will be at twelve hundred hours tomorrow, and\nif you hit the pot is yours. Minus a small handling fee for the bank,\nof course. \nCREWMAN: I'll take a piece of that. \nJONES: Jones. PARIS: Harry, get a PADD, take down these names and\nnumbers. \nKIM: I'm in too. \nLEWIS: Lewis, twenty one hundred. \n [Engineering]\n\n TORRES:\nEnsign Hogan, still no luck with the warp drive? \nHOGAN: No, Lieutenant. The manifold just won't fire up. We've finally\nnarrowed it down to some kind of a problem in EPS conduit one four one.\n\nTORRES: Was there any indication yesterday that there was something\nwrong? \nHOGAN: Suder was monitoring the EPS flow and the CCF. He says\neverything was fine. \nTORRES: I guess we'll just have to get in there and track it down.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 9, "LOC"], [12, 22, "PER"], [230, 235, "PER"], [353, 358, "PER"], [490, 495, "PER"], [527, 532, "PER"], [534, 539, "PER"], [541, 546, "PER"], [834, 839, "PER"], [1175, 1180, "PER"], [1189, 1194, "PER"], [1269, 1274, "PER"], [1299, 1310, "LOC"], [1322, 1334, "PER"], [1383, 1393, "PER"], [1598, 1603, "PER"]]}
{"id": 572, "text": "[Bridge] \n (Kim\nhas detected strange compounds in space.) \nJANEWAY: Rust?\nKIM: That's right, Captain. High levels of ferric oxide. Corroded iron\nparticles.\nJANEWAY: Would you mind telling me how iron could rust in space without\noxygen?\nKIM: I wish I could.\nJANEWAY: Mister Paris, alter our course to follow that trail of rust.\nOne quarter impulse.\nPARIS: Aye, Captain.\n(Later, on long range sensors.) \nKIM: Captain, look at this. I'm picking up traces of complex\nhydrocarbons in the rust. Benzene, ethylene, acetylene.\nPARIS: That sounds like gasoline.\nCHAKOTAY: Gasoline?\nPARIS: It's a liquid fuel that was used centuries ago on Earth. They\nburned it to drive internal combustion engines.\nJANEWAY: How did it get out here?\nTUVOK: I'm detecting a small object. It appears to be the source of the\nrust and hydrocarbons.\nJANEWAY: Put it on screen. Magnify. \n(They all stare at one of Henry Ford's products, floating in space.) \n [Cargo\nbay] \n (The\npick up has been brought on board.) \nTUVOK: Apparently it is a ground vehicle from mid-twentieth century\nEarth.\nPARIS: It's a 1936 Ford, actually.\nJANEWAY: Mister Paris?\nPARIS: That was the manufacturing date, 1936. Ford was the name of the\ncompany that build it. Antique vehicles are a hobby of mine. \n(He opens the bonnet, sorry, pops the hood, and whistles.) \nPARIS: Internal combustion engine, a reciprocating piston cylinder\ndesign, fuel source was a refined petroleum. Gasoline. \nKIM: So is this an early hover car?\nPARIS: No, you're about a century too early for that. This is about one\nstep ahead of the horse drawn carriage.\nTORRES: Traces of potassium nitrate, ammonium and methane back here.\nJANEWAY: I think you'll find that's manure. Horse manure, if I'm not\nmistaken. Judging from the mud on the wheels, and the alfalfa seedlings", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 7, "LOC"], [12, 15, "PER"], [266, 278, "PER"], [360, 367, "PER"], [407, 414, "PER"], [630, 635, "SPEC"], [928, 937, "LOC"], [1051, 1056, "SPEC"], [1102, 1114, "PER"]]}
{"id": 573, "text": "[Delta Flyer]\n\n(Paris is piloting the Flyer through a very dense asteroid field.)(PARIS: What's the matter, Harry? You\nlook a little pale. \nKIM: I volunteered for a test flight, not a suicide mission.\nPARIS: How can we put the new Delta Flyer through her paces without\ntaking a few risks?\nKIM: Another risk like that and we'll have to rebuild her all over\nagain. There's a vessel coming up fast off our starboard beam. \nPARIS: Shields. \nKIM: Range fifty kilometres. Ten. It's pulling alongside. \nPARIS: Wow, nice ship.\nKIM: It's scanning us.\nPARIS: This is Lieutenant Tom Paris. Please identify yourself. \nIRINA [OC]: Vectored exhaust ports, accelerated driver coils. Your\nvessel must be fast. \nPARIS: Gets us where we want to go. \nIRINA [OC]: Check your scanners. You'll see a comet on the other side\nof the asteroid field. I wonder which of our ships could get there\nfirst? \nPARIS: Sounds like a challenge. \nIRINA [OC]: Are you going to accept?\nKIM: We are not going to race her. \nPARIS: This is a test flight, right?\nKIM: Yeah, but \nPARIS: What better way to test the new ship than to see how it stands\nup to a little competition? We're ready over here. Shall I count to\nthree? (Irina accelerates away.)PARIS: Guess not. She's a lot more manoeuvrable\nthan we are. \nKIM: Not that I'm endorsing this misguided exercise, but maybe we can\neven the odds. New impulse thrusters. \nPARIS: Now that's the spirit, Harry. (A pair of thrusters open up at the rear of the Flyer.)\nKIM: We're catching up. A hundred metres, fifty. PARIS: Bring the backup generators online and reroute power to the\nthrusters. (Irina's ship clips an asteroid and her starboard nacelle starts venting.)PARIS: And it's the Delta Flyer by a nose. \nKIM: Something's wrong with her ship. The cabin's filling up with\nnyocene gas. \nPARIS: Stand by for emergency transport. (A humanoid female with pointed ears and tight leather trousers is beamed aboard, coughing.)\nKIM: Are you all right? \nIRINA: I think so. \nKIM: I told you this wasn't a good idea.\nIRINA: Does that mean you're afraid to try again?\nPARIS: Yeah, Harry, you afraid?\nKIM: No, of course not. It's just that your ship is in no shape for a", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[16, 21, "PER"], [38, 43, "SHIP"], [108, 113, "PER"], [1, 12, "SHIP"], [231, 242, "SHIP"], [557, 577, "PER"], [1182, 1187, "PER"], [1407, 1412, "PER"], [1462, 1467, "SHIP"], [1691, 1702, "SHIP"], [1839, 1847, "SPEC"], [2078, 2083, "PER"]]}
{"id": 574, "text": "[Cargo Bay two]\n\n(Seven wakes from a cacophany of voices.)COMPUTER: Regeneration cycle incomplete. (She\nprowls around the cargo bay, searching for something, then goes out\ninto the corridor. In the Mess hall she sniffs some food then knocks\nother bowls onto the floor. She finds what she is looking for in a\ncabinet - a leg of meat. The reflection in the metal is that of a\nKlingon, knawing on the bone.) \n [Briefing\nroom] \n KIM:\nWhen I checked the overnight sensor logs this little surprise was\nwaiting for me. \nJANEWAY: Maybe I'm not quite awake, but it looks like it's over one\nhundred kilometres wide. \nKIM: One hundred twenty. At first I thought it was an asteroid cluster,\nuntil I picked up a residual warp signature. \nSEVEN: It was a Borg vessel. There are tetryon particles in the debris\nconsistent with the atmosphere inside a Cube. \nCHAKOTAY: Any idea what destroyed it? \nSEVEN: We would need to run close range scans of the hull fragments. \nKIM: Unless we alter course, we'll get our chance. The debris field's\ndirectly ahead. \nJANEWAY: Then I suggest we cut a wide berth. Chances are the Borg will\nsend more vessels to investigate. Alter course to avoid the debris. If\nthat's all. \nNEELIX: Ah, one other piece of business, Captain. It seems we had\nanother incident in the Mess hall last night. \nTORRES: Return of the Midnight Snacker? \nNEELIX: I'm afraid so. \nJANEWAY: Casualties? \nNEELIX: A leg of Kelaran wildebeest I'd prepared for Ensign Ryson's\nbirthday. Since Commander Tuvok has been unable to round up any\nsuspects, I'd like to ask that stronger measures be taken. \nTUVOK: Perhaps an armed security detail. \nNEELIX: I'd like to ask permission to replicate some locking mechanisms\nfor the cabinet doors. \nJANEWAY: Granted. Dismissed. \n [Corridor]\n\n(Seven opens a Jefferies tube access", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 14, "LOC"], [18, 23, "PER"], [198, 207, "LOC"], [374, 381, "SPEC"], [408, 421, "LOC"], [741, 745, "SPEC"], [836, 840, "SHIP"], [1100, 1104, "SPEC"], [1235, 1242, "PER"], [1284, 1293, "LOC"], [1447, 1459, "PER"], [1411, 1429, "SPEC"], [1768, 1773, "PER"]]}
{"id": 575, "text": "[Turbolift]\n\n\n(Chakotay summons a turbolift. The doors open to reveal a crewman and\nwoman in a passionate kiss.) \nCREWMAN: Oh! Sir. We, er. We're just er.\nCHAKOTAY: Yes, I can see that.\n(The man and woman leaves, and Paris walks up with Kes, carrying boxes\nof leafy vegetables.) \nPARIS: What was that all about?\nCHAKOTAY: I'd call it an example of indiscreet shipboard fraternisation.\nPARIS: Really? Sorry I missed it.\nCHAKOTAY: Deck six. \n [Mess\nHall] \n KES:\nThank you for your help, Tom.\nPARIS: Yeah. See you later.\nKES: Right. \n [Kitchen]\n\n KES:\nHere's the cabbage you asked for. Is something wrong?\nNEELIX: What's this?\nKES: A spawn beetle. Oh, they cross-pollinate the Oblissian cabbage.\nHave you ever seen such fascinating striations? Oh, isn't it beautiful?\nNEELIX: I doubt the Captain would think so if she found it crawling\naround in her salad.\nKES: There is something wrong. What is it?\nNEELIX: No, nothing. I'm just very busy. So, you're seeing Tom Paris\nlater?\nKES: What? No, not that I know of.\nNEELIX: He said, see you later. You said, right. Is he helping you in\nthe Airponics bay now?\nKES: He was just helping me carry these.\nNEELIX: How thoughtful.\nKES: Neelix, this is getting ridiculous. You're imagining things that\naren't there.\nNEELIX: You're such an innocent! I see the way he looks at you. I used\nto look at women that way. I know what it means.\nJANEWAY [OC]: Janeway to the senior staff. Please report to the bridge.\n(Paris comes to the serving counter.) \nPARIS: Take care.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[15, 23, "PER"], [217, 222, "PER"], [237, 240, "PER"], [442, 451, "LOC"], [485, 488, "PER"], [533, 540, "LOC"], [631, 643, "SPEC"], [674, 683, "LOC"], [785, 792, "PER"], [956, 965, "PER"], [1171, 1177, "PER"], [1384, 1391, "PER"], [1443, 1448, "PER"]]}
{"id": 576, "text": "[Suder's quarters]\n\n(Suder\nis the sociopath who killed Crewman Darwin because he didn't like the\nway he looked at him. See\n Meld for more\ndetails. He shows Tuvok a seedling in a container.) \nSUDER: Look. And you said they were incompatible. \nTUVOK: You have confirmed the genetic structure? \nSUDER: An entirely new species. I'm going to name it after you. The\nTuvok Orchid. \nTUVOK: That is an honour you should reserve for yourself, Mister Suder.\nYou gave this species life. \nSUDER: And you gave me life. All of this is because of you. Because of\nthe meld. \nTUVOK: The meld may have introduced you to my interest in floriculture,\nbut you have embraced it entirely on your own, and discovered a unique\ntalent within yourself in the process. \nSUDER: I used to think the only talent I had was a talent for killing.\nPlease. It's my way of saying thank you.\nTUVOK: Very well. I accept. \nSUDER: Tuvok, I want to do something for the ship. I'm not asking you\nto let me out of confinement. I accept my punishment. But if I could\njust, just contribute somehow. \nTUVOK: What contribution do you feel you could make from your quarters?\n\nSUDER: I was, I was thinking I might adapt some of the genetic\nengineering techniques I've developed for the orchids to make the\nairponic vegetable garden more productive. \nTUVOK: Your attitude is admirable. I will discuss it with the Captain. \nSUDER: Do you think she'll agree? \nTUVOK: We'll see. Now, shall we begin? Notice your mind working, how it\nplans for the future, visits the past. Notice those thoughts and set\nthem aside. Turn your attention to the white light that is your breath.\n\n[Bridge]\n\nKIM:\nCaptain, we're being hailed on a subspace frequency. \nJANEWAY: Are there ships in the vicinity? \nPARIS: Negative. Tracking the source. Seems like it's coming from an\nunmanned buoy, coordinates one four zero mark three one seven.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 8, "PER"], [21, 26, "PER"], [55, 69, "PER"], [156, 161, "PER"], [360, 365, "PER"], [433, 445, "PER"], [889, 894, "PER"], [1361, 1368, "PER"], [1621, 1627, "LOC"], [1635, 1642, "PER"]]}
{"id": 577, "text": "First Officer's personal log,\nstardate 49005.3. The captain has granted me the use of the\nshuttlecraft so that I may perform the pakra, a solitary ritual\ncommemorating the anniversary of my father's death. \n [Shuttlecraft]\n\n\n(Chakotay lays out his medicine bundle on the floor of the\nshuttlecraft.) \nCHAKOTAY: A-koo-chee-moya. I pray on this day of memories to speak to\nmy father, the one whom the wind called Kolopak. Though I am far from\nhis bones, perhaps there is a spirit in these unnamed skies who will\nfind him and honour him with my song. A-koo-chee-moya. \n [Kazon\nbridge] \n (The\nshuttlecraft is on the viewscreen.) \nHALIZ: There. You see?\nRAZIK: We should teach them the price of displaying their markings in\nour space.\nHALIZ: I'll go.\nRAZIK: Let Kar do it this time.\nHALIZ: He's not ready.\nRAZIK: He thinks he is. He's been demanding a chance for weeks to earn\nhis name.\nHALIZ: Do you really believe he could do this?\nRAZIK: Can you honestly say you knew you were ready for your first\nmission, Haliz? Tell him. Tell him today is the day he will finally be\ncalled Ogla. \n [Shuttlecraft]\n\n\n(Chakotay is shaken from his meditation by a heavy hit.) \nCHAKOTAY: Computer, report.\nCOMPUTER: The shuttlecraft has sustained phaser fire. Minor damage to\naft shields.\nCHAKOTAY: Source?\nCOMPUTER: A Kazon spacecraft closing at one nine five mark six.\nCHAKOTAY: Computer, open a channel to the Kazon vessel. This is\nCommander Chakotay of the Federation Starship Voyager. Why have you\nfired on me? \nKAR [on monitor]: You are in Kazon-Ogla space, Federation.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[52, 59, "PER"], [226, 234, "PER"], [410, 417, "PER"], [567, 579, "LOC"], [756, 759, "PER"], [1004, 1009, "PER"], [1073, 1077, "PER"], [1099, 1107, "PER"], [1297, 1302, "SPEC"], [1391, 1396, "SPEC"], [1413, 1431, "PER"], [1439, 1449, "GPE"], [1459, 1466, "SHIP"], [1524, 1534, "GPE"], [1542, 1552, "GPE"]]}
{"id": 578, "text": "[Transporter Room]\n\n (In\ndeep space, something watches Voyager approach. It is then beamed\naboard, and we get its viewpoint in black and white.) \nTORRES: It's extraordinary. \nTUVOK: I must remind you that it is also a potential security risk. \nTORRES: It's losing power. I'd like to move it to Engineering to see if\nI can repair it before it drains completely. \nTUVOK: I suggest we allow the power to drain. We should take the\nopportunity to examine it while it is idle. Then we can decide if it is\nwise to repair it. \nTORRES: Captain, this thing has a completely unfamiliar power source.\nOnce it stops working it's very possible I won't be able to get it\ngoing again, and we'll have lost an opportunity to study a new\ntechnology. \nJANEWAY: This is a ship of exploration, Mister Tuvok. \n [Engineering]\n\n (Still\nblack and white, from the object's viewpoint.) \nTORRES: The power's surging. If we can't find a way to stabilise it,\nwe're going to lose it. \nKIM: What about an interface with an EPS power conduit? \nTORRES: Well, the energy signatures are incompatible, but it might buy\nus some time. Okay, let's give it a try. Two second burst, five percent\nmaximum output. On my mark. Now. We're losing it. \nKIM: Maybe we're overloading it's systems. \nTORRES: Let's try a longer burst at lower power. \nKIM: Got it. Five seconds at three percent, on your mark. \nTORRES: Now. I think it's working. EPS flow is holding steady. EM field\nleakage is minimal. \nKIM: We'll have to watch the pressure on the connectors. \nTORRES: Let's try to keep it below eighty five percent. \nKIM: Flux capacitance is spiking intermittently, but I don't think\nthat's a problem. \nTORRES: Let's reinforce the power conduit coupling just to be on the\nsafe side. \n(The object zooms in on a monitor to reveal that it is a silver robot.\nAfter the opening titles, we're back to colour and normal viewpoint.) \nTORRES: It's suffered a lot of damage, but I think the EPS charge will\nkeep it running for at least eighteen hours. \nKIM: It's not a cyborg. It's completely robotic. No organic components", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 17, "LOC"], [55, 62, "SHIP"], [294, 305, "LOC"], [527, 534, "PER"], [772, 784, "PER"], [789, 800, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 579, "text": "[Bridge]\n\n(Paris\nrushes onto the bridge.) \nPARIS: Sorry I'm late, but I have a very good excuse. Picture this. I'm\njust getting ready to leave the Mess hall, when Ensign Wildman goes\ninto labour. What else could I do but deliver the baby? Oh, you\nshould've been there, Harry. There is nothing like bringing a new life\ninto the world. I think I missed my calling. What if I told you the\nturbolift got stuck on deck six? \nCHAKOTAY: This is the third time you've been late this week, Mister\nParis. \nPARIS: It won't happen again. \nTUVOK: Commander, I am picking up a distress call on one of the upper\nsubspace bands. \nCHAKOTAY: What's the source? \nTUVOK: A small spacecraft. No weapon systems. One life form aboard.\nExtremely weak life signs. \nCHAKOTAY: Slow to half impulse. \nKIM: According to the bioscanner, it's a Vidiian female. \nJANEWAY: Open a channel. \nKIM: No response. \nCHAKOTAY: She may be too sick. \nPARIS: Or maybe it's some kind of trick. \nTUVOK: Preliminary scans show no other Vidiian ships in this sector. It\nis unlikely that this is a trap. \nJANEWAY: Commander Chakotay, notify the Doctor. Mister Kim, beam the\nwoman to Sickbay. \nKIM: Aye, Captain. \n\n[Sickbay]\n\nKES: Her\nrenal organs are functioning at twenty percent of normal and her\ncardiovascular system is on the verge of collapse. \nEMH: Twenty milligrams of lectrazine. \nKES: Cardiovascular and renal systems are stabilising, but her neural\npatterns are fading. What is it? \nEMH: In her parietal lobe. It looks like some sort of implant. It's a\nvery complex web of bioneural circuitry. Nanofibres. \nKES: Could this be what's causing the problem? \nEMH: On the contrary. According to these readings, the device is\nactually storing her synaptic patterns, processing them and", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 7, "LOC"], [11, 16, "PER"], [147, 156, "LOC"], [163, 177, "PER"], [269, 274, "PER"], [481, 493, "PER"], [534, 543, "PER"], [814, 821, "SPEC"], [989, 996, "SPEC"], [1065, 1083, "PER"], [1096, 1102, "PER"], [1104, 1114, "PER"], [1134, 1141, "LOC"], [1154, 1161, "PER"]]}
{"id": 580, "text": "[Delta Flyer -\ncockpit]\n\n(A card came is in process, for money.)NEELIX:\nHeart, heart, heart. Just one more heart. \nPARIS: You might as well be showing us your hand, Neelix. This is a\ngame of strategy, deception. \nKIM: Never let the opponents know your hand. \nNEELIX: Right. (Paris, who is the dealer, gives Neelix his one card.) NEELIX: Bah.\nCHAKOTAY: Ten. \nKIM: I see your ten, and raise you twenty.\nPARIS: Neelix?\nNEELIX: I'm thinking. Twenty. Another twenty. Ha.\nKIM: If I didn't know any better, I'd say we're being hustled. \nNEELIX: Ensign? \nKIM: Oh, I'm not buying the innocent Talaxian routine. \nNEELIX: I don't know what you're talking about. I've, I've, this is the\nfirst time I've played. What is it called? \nALL: Poker. \nPARIS: Look, why don't we make things a little more interesting. Forget\nthe chips. Let's bet on tomorrow's work detail, all right? Whoever wins\nthis hand gets the morning off. \nCHAKOTAY: I'm in. \nKIM: I'm in. \nNEELIX: Sounds good to me. \nCHAKOTAY: What have you got? \nKIM: Two pair. \nNEELIX: Does that beat a flush? \nKIM: I knew you were bluffing. \nCHAKOTAY: That beats me. Tom? (Tom is staring at a Borg Cube coming straight for them.) CHAKOTAY: Battle stations!\nPARIS: And I had a full house. (The Cube fires at the Flyer.)PARIS:\nI can't shake them. \nCHAKOTAY: Return fire. \nNEELIX: Why didn't our sensors detect them? \nKIM: Looks like they used a dispersal field to mask their approach.\nCHAKOTAY: Warp drive? \nPARIS: No luck. Too much damage to the plasma injectors. \nCHAKOTAY: Harry, get down there and see what you can do. \nNEELIX: Shields down eighteen percent. \nCHAKOTAY: Harry, status?\n\n[Delta", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 12, "SHIP"], [275, 280, "PER"], [307, 313, "PER"], [408, 414, "PER"], [538, 544, "PER"], [584, 592, "SPEC"], [1132, 1141, "SHIP"], [1106, 1109, "PER"], [1112, 1115, "PER"], [1232, 1236, "SHIP"], [1250, 1255, "SHIP"], [1513, 1518, "PER"], [1611, 1616, "PER"]]}
{"id": 581, "text": "[Ready room]\n\n(Janeway is looking out of a window when the doorbell chimes.)JANEWAY:\nCome in. \nTUVOK: You wished to see me. \nJANEWAY: We've known each other for how long?\nTUVOK: Approximately twenty years. \nJANEWAY: We've served on three starships together. I was present at\nyour daughter's Kohlinar. I consider you one of my closest friends.\nTUVOK: And I regard you with the same esteem. \nJANEWAY: I've always been honest with you, but you've been keeping\nsomething from me. \nTUVOK: I don't know what you mean. \nJANEWAY: Don't you? It took exhaustive research, sifting through\nteraquads of data, separating fact from rumour, but eventually I\narrived at the truth. \nTUVOK: Captain? (She activates the replicator, and turns around holding a blue-iced cake with a single lit candle.)\nJANEWAY: Happy birthday. \nTUVOK: Thank you. \nJANEWAY: So, it's not long before you hit the big three digits, huh? \nTUVOK: Indeed. Have you informed anyone else of your discovery? \nJANEWAY: Don't worry, Tuvok, my lips are sealed. Well? You're supposed\nto blow out the candle. \nTUVOK: That is not a Vulcan custom. \nJANEWAY: Humour me. \nCHAKOTAY [OC]: Captain to the bridge. \nJANEWAY: Well?  (Tuvok blows out the candle.)\nTUVOK: It was a fire hazard.(He puts the cake down.) \n[Bridge]\n\nCHAKOTAY:\nWe're receiving a distress call. A small vessel on an intercept course.\n\nJANEWAY: Lifesigns? \nKIM: One. It's Ocampan. \nTUVOK: We're being hailed. (A very old yet familiar woman appears on the viewscreen.)\nJANEWAY: Kes?\nKES [on viewscreen]: Captain Janeway, I need your help. Will you please\ngive me permission to come aboard? \nJANEWAY: Of course. What's happened? \nKES [on viewscreen]: Please, let me come aboard. (Transmission ends.)\nJANEWAY: Prepare the docking port. Tell the Doctor to stand by.\nTUVOK: Her ship is accelerating. It's on a collision course.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 11, "LOC"], [15, 22, "PER"], [673, 680, "PER"], [984, 989, "PER"], [1079, 1085, "SPEC"], [1131, 1138, "PER"], [1172, 1177, "PER"], [1146, 1152, "LOC"], [1256, 1262, "LOC"], [1384, 1391, "SPEC"], [1489, 1492, "PER"], [1515, 1530, "PER"], [1754, 1760, "PER"]]}
{"id": 582, "text": "[Planet surface]\n\n(The sun\nis shining and birds are singing in the trees around an open grassy\narea where two stasis pods are lying. The occupants are wakened by a\nbeeping noise. They open the pods and get out.) \nEMH [OC]: Sickbay to the Captain. This is the Doctor speaking. \nJANEWAY: You've brought us out of stasis. I assume you have news.\n\n[Doctor's\noffice]\n\nEMH:\nYes. Our sensors show your vital signs are normal. How are you feeling?\n\n[Planet\nsurface]\n\nJANEWAY:\nWe're fine. How long were we in stasis?\n\n[Doctor's\noffice]\n\nEMH: A\ntotal of seventeen days. \nJANEWAY [OC]: That long? \nEMH: I wanted to exhaust every possibility of finding a cure. \nJANEWAY [OC]: And? \nEMH: I regret to inform you that I have been unsuccessful.\n\n[Planet\nsurface]\n\nEMH\n[OC]: I have not been able to develop a counteragent for the virus, and\nI have no other options to explore. \nCHAKOTAY: What about keeping us in stasis aboard Voyager? \nEMH [OC]: Something in the planet's environment is shielding you from\nthe effects of the virus. \n[Doctor's\noffice]", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[223, 230, "ORG"], [238, 245, "PER"], [259, 265, "PER"], [345, 353, "PER"], [910, 917, "SHIP"], [1018, 1026, "PER"]]}
