{"id": 1, "text": "THE BOLD FRONT – by Christopher Awuku\n  \n  \n My son, Benjamin, you are of Bajor. Bajor\n must not fall.\n  \n ‘Is Bajor in danger? Tell me, mother, I need to know.\n Your Federation is danger.\n ‘Is the Dominion planning to attack?’\n Those from beyond the Celestial Temple are subdued, for now.\n Pre-empt the ally.\n ‘Pre-empt whom? Mother, I don’t understand!’\n Those whom you tricked into combat.\n  \n  \n  \n  \n  \n Station Log: Stardate 54567. Colonel Kira Nerys reporting.\n  \n Today is a memorable day. Bajor will officially take its place\n among the United Federation of Planets. The signing of the Articles of\n Federation is held here on Deep Space Nine and many dignitaries have", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[20, 37, "PER"], [53, 61, "PER"], [74, 79, "LOC"], [81, 86, "GPE"], [111, 116, "LOC"], [137, 143, "PER"], [167, 177, "GPE"], [198, 206, "GPE"], [251, 267, "LOC"], [327, 333, "PER"], [438, 456, "PER"], [498, 503, "GPE"], [546, 574, "GPE"], [635, 650, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 2, "text": "been invited, including the Federation President. On a more solemn\n note, the first anniversary of the end of the Dominion War took place\n yesterday. We’ll be holding a two-minute silence for those who died to\n protect our freedom.\n  \n  \n  \n “So Mr Bashir,” It was Peregrano, the Columbian\n assassin hired to kill Julian Bashir. Secret agent. “Tell your Prime\n Minister that La Corunnada will not hand over the arms to Britain!”\n Julian, in his customary tuxedo that he always\n wore\n in the holosuite, was in peril. Yes, the holosuite safeties were on,\n but Bashir needed the gun Peregrano held under his right foot.\n “The United Kingdom does not need the arms,” a\n quick\n retort from Julian. “But my Government will not tolerate secret funding\n to our enemies.”\n “Well, Bashir, the Soviet Union is the future.\n We just want to wipe away your ‘stiff-upper-lip’ government!”\n “What the hell is a ‘stiff upper lip’?” the\n assassin didn’t speak. But Julian knew that voice. It was his lover\n after all.\n “Ezri! Ever heard of a little word\n they call ‘privacy’?”\n “Computer end program.”\n “Hey!” \n “Oh come on, Julian! Signing’s today, remember?”\n “How could I forget. You can’t go anywhere\n without bumping into some politician or ambassador.”", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[28, 48, "PER"], [246, 255, "PER"], [265, 274, "PER"], [314, 327, "PER"], [280, 289, "GPE"], [354, 369, "PER"], [375, 387, "ORG"], [419, 426, "GPE"], [430, 436, "PER"], [558, 564, "PER"], [580, 589, "PER"], [623, 637, "GPE"], [685, 691, "PER"], [771, 777, "PER"], [783, 795, "GPE"], [947, 953, "PER"], [1002, 1006, "PER"], [1107, 1113, "PER"]]}
{"id": 3, "text": "That last remark brought a smile to Ezri’s\n face.\n “Speaking of ambassadors, Worf’s coming to the signing. Do you know\n Starfleet gave him his own ship? Some Defiant class vessel. USS\n Everest, I think. I promised to greet him at the airlock.”\n “Worf? Hmm. I guess it would be good to see him\n after…..what is it now? A year after the War ended?” Julian’s lover\n turned to exit the holosuite. “Where are you going?”\n “The Everest docks at 1300. I’ve only got 10\n minutes to get to the airlock.”\n “But my game…it was going so well.”\n “It can wait Julian. Come on already!”\n Bashir heaved a huge sigh. A sign of defeat on\n his part. “Alright Dax. Lead the way.”\n As the two lovebirds left the holosuite they\n noticed\n Quark was not his happy self. The Ferengi was conversing with his\n ever-faithful barfly, Morn. Things were not the same as they used to\n be. Captain Sisko was around. Bajor was independent. And before that no\n hew-marns! Even worse, his idiot brother is the leader of ALL\n Ferengi!\n “So tell me, Morn, it seems an innocent Ferengi\n can’t\n escape the almighty Federation. Andorian, Tellarite, Bolian,\n Vulcan….Hew-marn. They are all here. I mean, fine, they defeated the\n Dominion and the entire Alpha Quadrant must be grateful. This\n situation…all this…is total bullshit!”\n Morn didn’t understand. He raised his finger to\n point out what Quark had just said.\n “Oh, it’s an old hew-marn expression. It means", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[36, 42, "PER"], [77, 83, "PER"], [120, 129, "ORG"], [180, 192, "SHIP"], [246, 250, "PER"], [347, 355, "PER"], [422, 429, "SHIP"], [546, 552, "PER"], [573, 579, "PER"], [640, 643, "PER"], [716, 721, "PER"], [750, 757, "SPEC"], [805, 809, "PER"], [857, 870, "PER"], [883, 888, "LOC"], [926, 935, "SPEC"], [989, 996, "SPEC"], [1012, 1016, "PER"], [1039, 1046, "SPEC"], [1075, 1085, "GPE"], [1087, 1095, "SPEC"], [1097, 1106, "SPEC"], [1108, 1114, "SPEC"], [1117, 1123, "SPEC"], [1125, 1133, "SPEC"], [1187, 1195, "GPE"], [1211, 1225, "LOC"], [1290, 1294, "PER"], [1354, 1359, "PER"], [1393, 1401, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 4, "text": "“Time Bomb” by Walter Chmara\n         “I wanted to let you know that your orders have not changed,”\n said Commander Sisko. “Captain Picard still needs you aboard his ship\n before they arrive at their next destination. Our problem is how we get\n you there. It wouldn’t be practical to divert the *Enterprise* all the\n way here for one person, and at the moment, we really don’t have any\n vessels docked here that could cover the distance required in the time we\n have to get you to the rendezvous point.”\n         “I can see how that would be a problem,” answered Ensign Ro\n Laren. “How about something that could give me a lift to someplace\n closer? Somewhere I could catch a faster transport?”\n         “My first officer is running a computer search right now, looking\n into the possibility. You’ll be notified when a suitable window of travel\n is discovered. Meanwhile, I’d suggest using the time you have with us to\n enjoy the sights and offerings of the merchants around the Promenade.\n Have you ever visited the station before?”\n         “Twice. Once during the occupation and once after. Forgive me,\n Commander, but I’m not very enthusiastic about the thought of spending\n too much time here. Even the architecture of this place brings back bad\n memories.”\n         “I understand. Well there’s not much we can do about  the\n architecture, but we have some highly professional people-pleasers\n working here. If they can’t take your mind off your troubles, no one\n can.”\n         They walked together as they conversed. Presently, a second\n Bajoran woman approached, but she wasn’t wearing a Starfleet uniform.\n          “Major,” Sisko said. “Allow me to introduce you to Ensign Ro\n Laren of the starship *Enterprise*. Ensign, this is my first officer,", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[15, 28, "PER"], [106, 121, "PER"], [124, 138, "PER"], [296, 306, "SHIP"], [563, 579, "PER"], [979, 988, "LOC"], [1107, 1116, "PER"], [1545, 1552, "SPEC"], [1596, 1605, "ORG"], [1626, 1631, "PER"], [1634, 1639, "PER"], [1676, 1692, "PER"], [1710, 1720, "SHIP"], [1723, 1729, "PER"]]}
{"id": 5, "text": "Major Kira Nerys.”\n         Kira only nodded to Ro. “Commander, we may have a ride for the\n ensign pulling in right now. There’s an Odarian trading ship in the\n process of docking at upper pylon three. With a little financial\n incentive, there’s a good chance the captain may loan it to us for the\n round trip.”\n         Sisko smiled at Ro. “It may be that the Prophets have heard you.”\n         The Odarian captain was not a pleasant sight to most humanoids,\n resembling a moss-covered, human-sized platypus. Roughly. It was hard to\n compare them to anything else in the universe.\n         “Let me get this straight,” it responded to Kira’s proposal. “You\n want to pay me to turn my ship around and take it two weeks back in the\n direction I just *came* from? I’d almost take you up on it, since I try\n to never turn down a chance to make a little extra on the side. But I’ve\n just finished a month’s worth of travel in that tub, promising myself at\n least four days of Dabo and drink at Quark’s as a reward for putting up\n with this aged hulk’s grunts and groans. She only barely passes safety\n inspections, which satisfies my boss, but not me. I hope you understand,\n but  all I want right now is to get blotto.”\n         It began to move off, but Kira jumped in front of it. She was\n never one to take a simple “no” for an answer. “Look, what if I offered\n you both?”\n         “What do you mean?”\n         “You can stay here at the station and relax. I’ll pilot your\n ship, myself. I’ll even bring it back in better condition than it is now.\n Where are you going to find a better deal than that?”\n         The Odarian laughed raspingly, giving her a playful slap on the\n back. “You have a deal, Bajoran!”\n         “I don’t like the idea of doing without my first officer for at\n least a month. Especially since I have plenty of other people I can spare", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[0, 16, "PER"], [28, 32, "PER"], [48, 50, "PER"], [53, 62, "PER"], [92, 98, "PER"], [132, 139, "SPEC"], [183, 200, "LOC"], [321, 326, "PER"], [337, 339, "PER"], [400, 407, "SPEC"], [488, 493, "SPEC"], [500, 508, "SPEC"], [635, 641, "PER"], [989, 996, "LOC"], [1251, 1255, "PER"], [1614, 1621, "SPEC"], [1699, 1706, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 6, "text": "for a simple piloting mission,” Sisko told Kira as he sat behind his\n desk.\n         “I doubt I would have gotten any cooperation without any personal\n assurances from me. Would you trust your livelihood to a subordinate when\n you could have someone of a more advanced rank take care of it?”\n         “You have a point I don’t dispute. I still don’t like the idea of\n doing without two of my best people for that long.”\n         “Two? What…?” Kira was perplexed.\n         “Chief O’Brien’s going with you. Odarian traders have a\n reputation for breakdowns that rival the one this station has.”\n         Kira rolled her eyes. “Well. The more the merrier, I always say.”\n         When Ro was summoned to the docking port of upper pylon three for\n boarding, she found the airlock wide open. She stepped through it, into\n the Odarian ship. Inside, she found a group of Bajoran engineers hard at\n work around the core drive of the vessel. They were being supervised by\n none other than a grinning Chief Miles O’Brien.\n         “Hello, stranger!” he greeted her, after wiping the grease off\n his hand and offering it to her.\n         “Chief! I wondered if I’d be bumping into you around here.”\n         “It’s more than just a bump,” interrupted Kira, who entered the\n compartment from the direction of the bow. “He’s coming along for the\n ride. You two know each other, I gather?”\n         “Chief O’Brien served on the *Enterprise* for several years\n before he transferred here,” explained Ro. Turning to O’Brien, “Does this\n mean you’re coming back, Chief?”\n         “Hardly. Commander Sisko felt that this bucket might not hold\n together for the trip, so I’m to make sure it does. Lord knows, that’s\n what I’ve been trying to do with DS-Nine ever since I got here.”\n         “What *would* we do without you, Chief?” Kira said humorlessly,\n patting O’Brien’s shoulder before leaving the compartment for parts", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[32, 37, "PER"], [43, 47, "PER"], [443, 447, "PER"], [473, 488, "PER"], [505, 512, "SPEC"], [602, 606, "PER"], [682, 684, "PER"], [721, 738, "LOC"], [821, 828, "SPEC"], [864, 871, "SPEC"], [991, 1010, "PER"], [1128, 1133, "PER"], [1238, 1242, "PER"], [1384, 1397, "PER"], [1413, 1423, "SHIP"], [1483, 1485, "PER"], [1498, 1505, "PER"], [1544, 1549, "PER"], [1570, 1585, "PER"], [1729, 1736, "LOC"], [1803, 1808, "PER"], [1811, 1815, "PER"], [1843, 1852, "PER"]]}
{"id": 7, "text": "Star Trek: Deep Space Nine- “Spiderweb” by Jehan Jaleel \n                             Rating: PG-13\n       This story takes place during the fifth season of Star Trek: Deep Space Nine\n                               Part I\n           Major Kira Nerys entered Ops with a heavy heart, there were many\n       problems on her mind. The biggest concern at the moment was the recent\n       Dominion/Cardassian alliance which threatened the alpha quadrant and\n       especially Bajor. Now that Bajor’s deadliest enemies had joined forces, Kira’s\n       home planet faced a very grim future indeed she thought as she sat at her post\n       in Ops.\n          Kira did not say a word to the other officers in Ops, rather she just began the\n       work of Deep Space Nine’s commanding officer. Kira was in charge of the\n       station now that Captain Sisko was away overseeing repairs done on the\n       Defiant at Starbase 112. Neither Sisko nor his ship would be back for a week.\n       She missed them both.\n         The Defiant was one of the most powerful ships in the quadrant, and DS9\n       was always more vulnerable to attack when it was away, these days the\n       possibility of a Dominion attack seemed more and more likely. Kira also\n       wished that Sisko would return soon, because she hated the extra work. Fear of\n       Dominion attack, Dukat’s recent betrayal, Odo confessing his love for her, all\n       this made Kira too depressed to run the station.\n          She was glad when Dax interrupted her and said “Kira, you should take a\n       look at this.”\n       “What is it Jadzia?” Kira asked, as she too looked at Dax’s monitor.\n       “I am picking up a subspace echo,” Dax replied “It could be anything from\n       natural stellar phenomena to a ship’s warp signature.”\n       “Well at least it would give us something to do, let’s check it out”\n       “I am getting more information now,” Dax said “it is definitely not natural.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[43, 55, "PER"], [233, 249, "PER"], [258, 261, "LOC"], [383, 391, "GPE"], [433, 447, "LOC"], [470, 475, "LOC"], [486, 493, "LOC"], [531, 537, "PER"], [634, 637, "LOC"], [649, 653, "PER"], [698, 701, "LOC"], [744, 761, "LOC"], [782, 786, "PER"], [832, 845, "PER"], [893, 900, "SHIP"], [904, 916, "LOC"], [926, 931, "PER"], [1013, 1020, "SHIP"], [1077, 1080, "LOC"], [1182, 1190, "GPE"], [1227, 1231, "PER"], [1256, 1261, "PER"], [1330, 1338, "GPE"], [1347, 1354, "PER"], [1372, 1375, "PER"], [1426, 1430, "PER"], [1493, 1496, "PER"], [1523, 1527, "PER"], [1588, 1594, "PER"], [1597, 1601, "PER"], [1630, 1635, "PER"], [1687, 1690, "PER"], [1908, 1911, "PER"], [392, 402, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 8, "text": "Looks like a subspace transmission of some sort. It’s  very weak and distorted.”\n       “Can you filter it out?” Kira asked.\n         Instead of hearing Dax’s reply, Kira heard the message itself which answered\n       her question. It was an automated Federation distress call, and it was so weak\n       it was hard to make out. But what Kira did hear troubled her.\n       “This is the Federation starship Barkman, we have been attacked by Jem’Hdar\n       fighters, our main power has failed. Our main power has failed, we require\n       imm ….”\n                                                        Part II\n         There was a time, not long ago when Julian Bashir would have been\n       overjoyed to be called to the briefing room for a dangerous mission. That was\n       when he had first arrived on this station, now that he was older and had\n       realized how dangerous the universe can be he was not so enthusiastic. In fact ,\n       he almost wished he was not walking to the briefing room right now.\n          Bashir entered the room and saw that all the other senior officers except\n       Sisko and O’Brien were present. They all had solemn expressions on their\n       faces, then again there was not much to smile about these days anyway. Kira\n       was at the head of the table, in Sisko’s absence and Bashir took his seat.\n       “Glad to see you could make it Doctor,” Kira said “Fifteen minutes ago we\n       received a distress call from the USS Barkman, they were attacked Jem’Hdar\n       fighters.”\n       “The Barkman is a Miranda class starship with a crew compliment of fifty\n       three last assigned to map the Trinson nebula,” said Worf.\n       “But that is nowhere near Cardassian space,” Bashir offered.\n       “We know,” Kira replied “and if the Barkman was indeed attacked it could\n       signify a new Dominion offense. The Trinson nebula is nowhere near\n       anybody’s space, and closest Federation or allied outpost to the Barkman is\n       DS9.”\n       “Major, you can’t seriously expect us to mount some kind of rescue,” Bashir\n       said ” Both the Defiant and General Martok’s ship are away. All we have now", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[113, 117, "PER"], [153, 158, "PER"], [166, 170, "PER"], [252, 262, "GPE"], [338, 342, "PER"], [386, 396, "GPE"], [406, 413, "SHIP"], [440, 448, "SPEC"], [655, 668, "PER"], [1023, 1029, "PER"], [1104, 1109, "PER"], [1114, 1121, "PER"], [1300, 1307, "PER"], [1320, 1326, "PER"], [1255, 1259, "PER"], [1380, 1386, "PER"], [1389, 1393, "PER"], [1464, 1475, "SHIP"], [1496, 1504, "SPEC"], [1535, 1542, "SHIP"], [1641, 1655, "LOC"], [1663, 1667, "PER"], [1702, 1712, "SPEC"], [1780, 1787, "SHIP"], [1838, 1846, "GPE"], [1860, 1874, "LOC"], [1927, 1937, "GPE"], [1963, 1970, "SHIP"], [1981, 1984, "LOC"], [1995, 2000, "PER"], [2063, 2069, "PER"], [2093, 2100, "SHIP"], [2105, 2121, "PER"]]}
{"id": 9, "text": "are runabouts, surely there are some starships in the area that could go to the\n       Trinson nebula.”\n       “Unfortunately with the Dominion threat of war closer than ever these days, all\n       Federation starships have been assigned to protect key homewards and solar\n       systems,” Worf said “and the same could be said for our allies in the Klingon\n       and Romulan Empires.”\n       “So  you want us to take a few runabouts into unknown territory with a\n       powerful enemy that is hunting us at every turn”.\n       “Not a few runabouts Doctor, one runabout,” Kira replied “I need the rest of\n       the runabouts to help protect the station and Bajor now that the Defiant is\n       gone.”\n       “I like a challenge,” said Worf with a smile “I volunteer for the mission.”\n       “Excellent, Dax will be in command and Dr.Bashir will join you as well,” Kira\n       said as she got up from her seat “you leave within the hour.”\n       “Nothing like being assigned to a suicide mission to liven up your day,” Bashir\n       said.\n                                      Part III\n           Being the commander on this particular mission, Jadzia Dax had to check\n       up on some last minute details before she went to the runabout. When she\n       finally arrived on the runabout Mahaweli she saw that her entire crew was\n       already there, ready for the mission and waiting for their commander.\n          Lt.Enrique Alvarez was at the runabout’s helm, he was one of the best\n       runabout pilots on the station and Dax wanted him at the helm on this\n       particularly dangerous mission. The science station had been left empty for\n       her, and next to it Bashir sat in his chair with nothing to do at the moment.\n       Then there was Worf who sat at operations, he had an angry look on his face\n       and tried to keep himself busy with his console.\n          Dax walked up to Worf, put her arms around him and kissed him on the\n       cheek. But he just gave her a stern look, which made Dax back away and take\n       her seat at the science station. She knew this was not easy for Worf, the threat", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[87, 101, "LOC"], [135, 143, "GPE"], [198, 208, "GPE"], [290, 294, "PER"], [350, 357, "SPEC"], [369, 376, "SPEC"], [550, 556, "PER"], [573, 577, "PER"], [659, 664, "LOC"], [678, 685, "SHIP"], [737, 741, "PER"], [805, 808, "PER"], [832, 841, "PER"], [866, 870, "PER"], [1020, 1026, "PER"], [1146, 1156, "PER"], [1289, 1297, "PER"], [1418, 1436, "PER"], [1530, 1533, "PER"], [1608, 1623, "LOC"], [1675, 1681, "PER"], [1755, 1759, "PER"], [1771, 1781, "LOC"], [1882, 1885, "PER"], [1899, 1903, "PER"], [2011, 2014, "PER"], [2057, 2072, "LOC"], [2105, 2109, "PER"]]}
{"id": 10, "text": "CHAPTER 3\n “She’s stable,” said the Doctor. “That’s the good news.”\n “All right,” said Chakotay, “What’s the bad?”\n They stood in the Doctor’s office in sickbay, looking out the window at Ensign Kang where she lay on a sickbay bed, still unconscious. Kes was sitting at her bedside watching the biomonitor.\n “It appears the ensign has undergone some rather extensive modifications,” said the Doctor. “In fact, it seems the modification process is ongoing. I have no way to stop it without doing potentially fatal harm to the patient.”\n “What kind of modifications? To what end?” said Chakotay.\n The Doctor shook his head. “To what end, I can’t say. It seems a number of biosynthetic implants have been embedded deep in her tissues.” He turned to his desktop console and called up the results of his medical scans, superimposing the readings over a simple outline diagram of a human body. Lit up at multiple points on the diagram were silhouettes of slender little squid-like creatures, or machines… It was hard to classify the biosynthetic constructs one way or the other. They had heads like worms and many, many tendrils like threads that fanned out through her body. \n “They seem to be hardwired into her nervous system,” the Doctor went on, “sending and receiving signals from her central nervous system. They’re supplementing natural organ functions and regulating hormone levels, stimulating the growth of some cells and inhibiting others. They also seem to be modifying her DNA.”\n Chakotay studied the diagram and the accompanying readings, a sense of disgust and trepidation rising up in him. “This resembles Borg technology. Is there any evidence of nanoprobes at work here?” The desiccated corpse of a Borg drone he’d stumbled upon on an away mission last week was still fresh in his mind. The specter of Borg cubes lurking just outside of sensor range in the murky depths of the Nekrid Expanse had haunted him ever since.\n “Certainly not any of Borg design,” said the Doctor, alleviating his fears but not quashing them completely. “My tests are ongoing, though.”\n Chakotay studied the diagram closer. “What do you make of this one?” he said, pointing at the alien construct occupying the diagram’s skull.\n “That implant is the one that worries me the most,” said the Doctor. “Its processes are threaded throughout her brain. It might influence her cognition and her perceptions, bias her behavior… it could conceivably even be controlling her body. I’ll monitor her engrams for any irregularities when she wakes.”\n Chakotay was quiet for a moment, regarding his unconscious officer. He’d let her down, back on that space station. He hadn’t acted fast enough when that pod had opened. He should have destroyed the thing the moment it made a sound. He should have acted faster when the cables ensnared Ensign Kang. If only he’d been faster, sharper, quicker on his feet…\n He wouldn’t let her down now. The alien space station still had her, even if she was out of the pod. He had to find a way to stop its progress before it finished turning her into… whatever it was turning her into.\n But, he couldn’t let himself forget, he also had a duty to protect the rest of the crew. He tapped his combadge. “Chakotay to Tuvok,” he said.\n “Tuvok here, sir.”\n “Assign two security personnel to sickbay. The Doctor will brief them when they arrive.”\n “Acknowledged,” said Tuvok.\n Chakotay met the Doctor’s gaze, and the Doctor nodded his understanding.\n “Under alien control or not, our crewmember is still in there, Doctor,” said Chakotay. “I know you’ll do everything in your power to help her.”\n “Of course, sir,” said the Doctor.\n Chakotay walked out of the Doctor’s office and crossed sickbay. The doors to the corridor opened as he approached, and standing outside was Chief Vance, looking very dour. That was fast, thought Chakotay. But then he noticed that the security officer wasn’t approaching the door, but apparently dithering in the corridor. “Is there something I can help you with, Chief?” said Chakotay.\n Vance jumped to attention at the sight of his senior officer. “No, sir. I just wanted to know if I could visit the patient.”\n Chakotay felt his eyebrow rising and quickly schooled his facial expression. “You’ll have to ask the Doctor,” he said, and then he passed out into the corridor.\n  \n “…told her how you felt, before?” It was a gentle, feminine voice. Lucy was sure she recognized it.\n “Yes… well… I mean, I think she has the general idea,” said someone else. It was a man’s voice, low and brash, and the connotations of his tenor stirred a sense of attraction, balanced on a knife’s edge with a sense of discomfort.\n Owen, that was the second one. And the first one was Kes, Lucy remembered now.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[36, 42, "PER"], [87, 95, "PER"], [134, 149, "LOC"], [153, 160, "LOC"], [188, 199, "PER"], [219, 226, "LOC"], [251, 254, "PER"], [324, 330, "PER"], [392, 398, "PER"], [584, 592, "PER"], [599, 605, "PER"], [876, 881, "SPEC"], [964, 969, "SPEC"], [1093, 1098, "SPEC"], [1488, 1496, "PER"], [1617, 1621, "SPEC"], [1712, 1716, "SPEC"], [1815, 1819, "SPEC"], [1890, 1904, "LOC"], [1956, 1960, "SPEC"], [1979, 1985, "PER"], [2076, 2084, "PER"], [2527, 2535, "PER"], [2812, 2823, "PER"], [3211, 3219, "PER"], [3223, 3228, "PER"], [3242, 3247, "PER"], [3295, 3302, "LOC"], [3308, 3314, "PER"], [3372, 3377, "PER"], [3380, 3388, "PER"], [3397, 3405, "PER"], [3420, 3426, "PER"], [3517, 3523, "PER"], [3531, 3539, "PER"], [3626, 3632, "PER"], [3635, 3643, "PER"], [3662, 3677, "LOC"], [3690, 3697, "LOC"], [3775, 3786, "PER"], [3830, 3838, "PER"], [3869, 3885, "PER"], [3998, 4003, "PER"], [4011, 4019, "PER"], [4022, 4027, "PER"], [4148, 4156, "PER"], [4249, 4255, "PER"], [4380, 4384, "PER"], [4646, 4650, "PER"], [4699, 4702, "PER"], [4704, 4708, "PER"]]}
{"id": 11, "text": "Off to Lucy’s right, something started beeping. It sounded like a sickbay biomonitor.\n “Doctor!” Kes called, and then she leaned in close to Lucy. “Ensign, are you awake?”\n Lucy opened her eyes and took in the faces around her. Owen stood on her left, looking distinctly uncomfortable. Kes sat on her right, holding Lucy’s hand. A couple other security officers stood guard by the sickbay doors. The Doctor was approaching from his office, his face a mask of concern.\n “Ensign?” said the Doctor, “How are you feeling?”\n Lucy took stock of herself for a moment. The sickbay bed she was lying on was comfortable. The sickbay blanket felt nice on her skin. “I feel alright,” she said. She propped herself up on her elbows, and as her weight shifted, she noticed something about her body was… off. She couldn’t immediately pin down what it was, though.\n The Doctor took a medical tricorder off a nearby shelf and began scanning her. Without lifting his eyes from the device, he tapped his badge and said, “Doctor to the Bridge.”\n “Janeway here, Doctor,” came the captain’s voice. “What’s your status?”\n “Ensign Kang is awake, sir.”\n “Acknowledged, Doctor. Thank you.”\n The Doctor stopped scanning and looked back at his patient.\n “Are you in any pain?” he said.\n Lucy shook her head. “No, I’m good.”\n The Doctor’s concerned expression didn’t waver. “Do you know where you are right now, Ensign?”\n Lucy chuckled a little at the question. “Sickbay. Voyager. The Delta Quadrant.”\n The Doctor bit his lip for a moment and said, “Do you know why you’re in sickbay, Ensign Kang?”\n “Well…” said Lucy, and she glanced around at the others gathered around her bed. The intensity with which the Doctor, Kes and Owen were all looking at her was starting to make her a little bit uncomfortable. The security officers at the door to sickbay were troubling, as well.\n She returned her attention to the Doctor. “I mean after what happened on the space station…” she cast a meaningful glance at Owen. It had been an intense ordeal, and Owen, at least, would know a bit about what she’d been through. “It’s hardly a surprise.”\n The Doctor nodded. He still looked worried. Lucy wondered why. She was fine, now. She felt fine. Did he know something she didn’t?\n The Doctor turned to Owen. “Mr. Vance, I’m sorry, but could you excuse us, please?”\n Owen nodded. “Of course, Doctor,” he said. “I’m glad you’re alright,” he told Lucy.\n She saw the sincerity in his eyes, and it surprised her. She wondered if she hadn’t been too hard on him before. It was obvious she was attracted to the security officer, so why did she have to make things complicated?\n Owen turned and headed towards the doors. Lucy called, “Hey Owen.” He paused and looked back at her. Lucy smiled warmly at him. “Thanks for visiting me,” she said.\n Owen’s eyes grew a little wider. He flashed an uncertain smile and nodded, then left the sickbay.\n Lucy returned her attention to the Doctor, who was studying her face like a bug under a magnifying glass.\n “Ensign, are you aware that your skin pigmentation is changing?” he said.\n “Huh?” said Lucy. Her hand rose to her cheek. “You mean I’m blushing?”\n The Doctor shook his head. “No, that’s not what I mean.”\n Lucy looked from the Doctor to Kes, who was squinting at Lucy’s face now, too. “Your lips are reddening,” she said.\n “Really?” said Lucy. Her fingers moved to her lips. “That’s weird…”\n Kes stood and crossed the sickbay, apparently looking for something. The Doctor sat down on the stool she’d vacated.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[7, 13, "PER"], [88, 94, "PER"], [97, 100, "PER"], [141, 145, "PER"], [148, 154, "PER"], [173, 177, "PER"], [228, 232, "PER"], [286, 289, "PER"], [316, 322, "PER"], [400, 406, "PER"], [470, 476, "PER"], [488, 494, "PER"], [381, 388, "LOC"], [66, 73, "LOC"], [520, 524, "PER"], [565, 572, "LOC"], [615, 622, "LOC"], [854, 860, "PER"], [1002, 1008, "PER"], [1016, 1022, "ORG"], [1027, 1034, "PER"], [1041, 1047, "PER"], [1059, 1068, "PER"], [1100, 1111, "PER"], [1144, 1150, "PER"], [1169, 1175, "PER"], [1259, 1263, "PER"], [1301, 1309, "PER"], [1383, 1389, "PER"], [1393, 1397, "PER"], [1434, 1441, "LOC"], [1443, 1450, "SHIP"], [1452, 1470, "LOC"], [1478, 1484, "PER"], [1547, 1554, "LOC"], [1556, 1567, "PER"], [1584, 1588, "PER"], [1681, 1687, "PER"], [1689, 1692, "PER"], [1697, 1701, "PER"], [1816, 1823, "LOC"], [1884, 1890, "PER"], [1975, 1979, "PER"], [2016, 2020, "PER"], [2111, 2117, "PER"], [2151, 2155, "PER"], [2243, 2249, "PER"], [2260, 2264, "PER"], [2267, 2276, "PER"], [2324, 2328, "PER"], [2349, 2355, "PER"], [2402, 2406, "PER"], [2629, 2633, "PER"], [2671, 2675, "PER"], [2689, 2693, "PER"], [2730, 2734, "PER"], [2794, 2800, "PER"], [2883, 2890, "LOC"], [2893, 2897, "PER"], [2928, 2934, "PER"], [3001, 3007, "PER"], [3087, 3091, "PER"], [3151, 3157, "PER"], [3205, 3209, "PER"], [3226, 3232, "PER"], [3236, 3239, "PER"], [3262, 3268, "PER"], [3337, 3341, "PER"], [3391, 3394, "PER"], [3417, 3424, "LOC"], [3464, 3470, "PER"]]}
{"id": 12, "text": "“Ensign Kang, are you aware of any… out of the ordinary sensations? Any pain or discomfort, anywhere in your body?”\n Lucy shifted her hips and rolled her shoulders, gauging her senses. “No, Doctor. I told you, I’m fine.”\n “You’re not experiencing any nausea? No trembling? No sense of weakness? No fear or anxiety?”\n Lucy shook her head. “Not really…”\n The Doctor sighed. “Don’t you think that’s odd, considering what you’ve just been through?”\n Lucy shrugged. “I mean… I’m alive. That’s what matters, right?”\n The Doctor just shook his head. “Do you have any sense of what was done to you on that station?”\n Lucy considered. It was certainly not something pleasant to contemplate, but for the Doctor’s sake, she tried.\n “Well, at first, I was in a lot of pain, and I was terrified. I thought I was going to die, and what a horrible way it would have been to go.”\n Lucy felt an involuntary shudder, but it seemed out of place to her. The recollection didn’t actually bother her all that much.\n “Then… all of a sudden, the pain stopped. I was literally being stabbed all over my body and twisted around by all these strong cords, and yet, somehow, it didn’t hurt anymore. Maybe the pod used a numbing agent? And then, suddenly, I wasn’t afraid anymore. I still thought I was dying. I guess maybe I was in shock? Or I’d just accepted it as inevitable? But I wasn’t scared at all, just… inexpressibly sad. I thought I’d never get home again.”\n It was hard to convey the experience to the Doctor. It was hard to even remember what it had felt like, to be that sad. She couldn’t really find the feeling inside her anymore.\n “Then, the sadness was gone too. That was the weirdest part. Like, I felt all these slimy tubes sticking into my body, and I could feel it under my skin. I could even feel it in my head. Like something out the worst, most disgusting, horrific nightmare. And all I could gin up in reaction was this big sense of, ‘Wow, this should really be bothering me a lot more than it is.’ But I guess I was just exhausted by that point. By the time the pod let me go, I was beyond ready to just pass out.”\n Lucy’s attention returned to her current surroundings. The Doctor looked at her with compassionate eyes. Kes stood in front of her bed, clutching a hand mirror against her chest. Her face was ashen, and tears were welling up in her wide eyes. She blinked several times to clear her eyes, and then she stepped forward and handed Lucy the mirror. “Here,” she said. “I thought you’d want to see what we were talking about.” The young Ocampan hardly got the words out before she turned away. She wiped her eyes with her hands as she walked quickly to the Doctor’s office, letting the doors close behind her.\n Lucy didn’t know what to make of that reaction. She supposed the story must have been pretty upsetting to hear.\n “Are you upset, that that happened to you?” said the Doctor.\n She shook her head. “It’s over, now.”\n “Are you worried about what the lasting effects might be?”\n Lucy shrugged. “A little, maybe.”\n “And you aren’t in any pain.”\n “I told you, no. Why do you keep asking that?”\n The Doctor took a deep breath. “Ensign Kang… Lucy… currently, inside of your body, there are fifteen biosynthetic constructs of alien design, with countless threads branching out through all of your major organs. They’re already fully integrated with your biology. I can’t remove them. And they’re… changing you.”\n “Wow, that’s… fascinating!” said Lucy. “Are they primarily organic, or do they incorporate organic tissues in an inorganic framework?”\n The Doctor’s eyebrows shot up. “I just told you your body was full of alien implants, Ensign. That isn’t the sort of reaction I was expecting.”\n Lucy reflected for a moment. “Yeah, I guess you’re right. You said they’re in every organ… that must include my brain. Do you suppose they’re changing my behavior, too?”\n The Doctor nodded. “I think that’s a safe deduction, yes,” he said.\n “Then, you must be worried that I could pose a threat to the ship,” she said. She glanced at the security officers by the doors, Crewman Jeffery Thorold and Crewman Megan Steiner. Jeffery was watching her out of the corner of his eye. When he saw her looking at him, his attention returned directly ahead.\n “Keep up the good work, Jeff, Megan,” said Lucy. “Sorry I’ve got you stuck on guard duty. I know it can be pretty dull.”\n “Ensign, would you please focus?” said the Doctor.\n Lucy was surprised at his irritation, though she supposed she shouldn’t have been. She understood the gravity of the situation, even if she was having some trouble feeling it.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 12, "PER"], [117, 121, "PER"], [190, 196, "PER"], [317, 321, "PER"], [357, 363, "PER"], [446, 450, "PER"], [515, 521, "PER"], [609, 613, "PER"], [694, 702, "PER"], [865, 869, "PER"], [1485, 1491, "PER"], [2114, 2120, "PER"], [2173, 2179, "PER"], [2219, 2222, "PER"], [2545, 2552, "SPEC"], [2665, 2673, "PER"], [2719, 2723, "PER"], [2885, 2891, "PER"], [2993, 2997, "PER"], [3111, 3117, "PER"], [3139, 3150, "PER"], [3152, 3156, "PER"], [3455, 3459, "PER"], [3562, 3570, "PER"], [3644, 3650, "PER"], [3703, 3707, "PER"], [3878, 3884, "PER"], [4072, 4095, "PER"], [4100, 4121, "PER"], [4123, 4130, "PER"], [4274, 4278, "PER"], [4280, 4285, "PER"], [4293, 4297, "PER"], [4373, 4379, "PER"], [4415, 4421, "PER"], [4424, 4428, "PER"]]}
{"id": 13, "text": "By: Kristen Jones <rkjones@ipass.net>\n Red Alert\n “Red alert!” Ben Sisko screamed at the people in Ops. “O’Brien, get those\n shields back up, now. We can’t take anymore of a beating.”\n “Aye, sir,” Miles O’Brien said, with pain lacing his voice. An exploding console\n had left him with second degree burns on his face, as well as one useless arm at the\n moment.\n “Where the hell is Bashir?” Sisko questioned. “Somebody find a medic for these\n people!”\n Miles sighed and thought back to how it had all happened.\n Everyone had been in Quark’s taking a well deserved break from the day’s work.\n All, that is, except Julian Bashir. He had been stuck in the infirmary treating an outbreak\n of Andarian flu among the Bolian people. He finally staggered into the bar and plopped\n down in a seat about ten p.m.\n “Oh, gods, why does this always happen to me?” he moaned, head in hands.\n “What do you mean?” Jadzia had asked.\n “Do you want to know what I’ve had to put up with today? A hysterical mother\n and a kid with a fractured arm, a pregnant woman going into false labor, two engineering\n workers falling off the Promenade rail in a drunk stupor, plus I’ve had to treat all these\n cases of Andarian flu and I’m very quickly running out of compatible medicine for the\n Bolians.” He sighed and put his head in his arms.\n Jadzia looked at him in sympathy. “What you need is a stiff drink.\n Unfortunately, you’re a doctor so no can do. But I’ll buy you a synthale anyway.” He\n looked at her gratefully.\n “Miles, come on. We’ve got to get to Ops,” she said after awhile.\n “All right. See you, Julian.” Julian smiled tiredly and stood up to go back to the\n infirmary. It was at that moment that they were attacked.\n “What the-?” Miles wondered and stood up, racing to ops with Jadzia. “Sir,", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[4, 17, "PER"], [63, 72, "PER"], [99, 102, "ORG"], [105, 112, "PER"], [197, 210, "PER"], [381, 387, "PER"], [390, 395, "PER"], [452, 457, "PER"], [532, 539, "LOC"], [612, 625, "PER"], [687, 695, "LOC"], [710, 716, "SPEC"], [897, 903, "PER"], [1108, 1117, "LOC"], [1185, 1193, "LOC"], [1263, 1270, "SPEC"], [1314, 1320, "PER"], [1496, 1501, "PER"], [1532, 1535, "LOC"], [1583, 1589, "PER"], [1592, 1598, "PER"], [1646, 1655, "LOC"], [1718, 1723, "PER"], [1757, 1760, "LOC"], [1766, 1772, "PER"]]}
{"id": 14, "text": "what’s wrong?” he yelled when he reached Sisko.\n “The Klingons have hit us. They decloaked off port side of upper pylon three.\n Then they hit us. Miles, I want you to get to the console and see if you can get us some\n more power to the shields. Dax, start helping Kira get those weapons back on line.\n Bashir-where is Doctor Bashir?” They all looked around, but he was not there.\n “He must be in the infirmary,” Miles said. “Julian, can you hear me? Julian,\n where are you? Computer, locate Doctor Bashir.”\n “Doctor Bashir is in the infirmary.”\n “Dax, you get a team to find him. There are going to be dead people here soon if\n we don’t have a doctor here,” Sisko commanded.\n “Aye, sir. Rogers, Johnson, Smith, you’re with me.” They raced out of ops in the\n direction of the turbolift. “Promenade,” she commanded.\n Miles sighed and worked at getting the weapons systems back online. The blast\n from the console had given him the burns that were making every movement feel like\n agony.\n “O’Brien, how are you coming along?” Sisko asked, his voice strained.\n “Just a few more seconds, sir.” He punched the last command in. “There, do it!\n It’s up!”\n The commbadge chirped. “Benjamin, we can’t find Julian. His communicator’s\n here, but he’s not.”\n “What happened?” Sisko asked.\n “We’re assuming when the Klingons boarded, they must have taken him. The\n nurses and several patients are gone as well.”\n “Well, dammit, don’t just stand there. Find them!” He slammed his hand down\n on the table. “O’Brien, get your people up here. You’ve just become nurses.”\n Miles sighed. This was not something he wanted to be doing right now. “But sir,\n I’m the only person here who can keep these weapons system online. I can get my\n people here, but otherwise, the weapons will fail and the station will be taken over.”\n “All right! Just do something.”\n Julian Bashir awoke with a blistering headache. At first, all he could see were", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[41, 46, "PER"], [54, 62, "SPEC"], [108, 125, "LOC"], [146, 151, "PER"], [245, 248, "PER"], [264, 268, "PER"], [302, 308, "PER"], [318, 331, "PER"], [412, 417, "PER"], [425, 431, "PER"], [450, 456, "PER"], [491, 504, "PER"], [509, 522, "PER"], [547, 550, "PER"], [658, 663, "PER"], [687, 693, "PER"], [695, 702, "PER"], [704, 709, "PER"], [746, 749, "LOC"], [775, 784, "LOC"], [787, 796, "LOC"], [815, 820, "PER"], [987, 994, "PER"], [1023, 1028, "PER"], [1172, 1180, "PER"], [1196, 1202, "PER"], [1263, 1268, "PER"], [1302, 1310, "SPEC"], [1491, 1498, "PER"], [1554, 1559, "PER"], [1837, 1850, "PER"]]}
{"id": 15, "text": "fuzzy images. Then he recognized Nurse Jabara kneeling down beside him.\n “Doctor, are you all right?”\n “I think so. What happened?”\n “We were attacked by the Klingons. You and the rest of us managed to get some\n of the people out of the infirmary when the computer exploded. We’re in Quark’s right\n now.”\n “Well, what am I doing lying on the floor, for goodness sake?” He cried.\n “One of the ensigns panicked and when you tried to calm him down, he hit you\n over the head with a flask of Earth brandy.”\n Julian smiled at this and then winced. “Where is everyone else?”\n “They’re all trying to fight off the Klingon attack. Sisko’s been screaming for\n you for awhile now.”\n “Oh, well I’d better-hey! Where’s my combadge?”\n “You must have dropped on the way out of the infirmary,” Jabara replied.\n “Julian!” came a relieved call from the doorway. Julian looked over and saw\n Jadzia standing there with a couple of engineering technicians from ops.\n “I’m fine, Jadzia, just a sore head. Where is everyone, anyway?”\n “Either in ops or in surrounding parts of the station. Benjamin needs you up there\n right away. They’ve got the engineering crew on skeleton detail to try to fix everything\n before the next attack.”\n “Next attack? You mean they’ve stopped?”\n “Yes, we succeeded in driving them away from the station to regroup. Starfleet\n reinforcements should arrive in a few hours.”\n They raced to ops with Nurse Jabara on their heels.\n “Bashir, where have you been?” Sisko yelled as the turbolift stopped and they\n entered ops.\n “It’s a long story, sir, one we really don’t have time for at the present.” He\n replied.\n “All right, just start treating some of these people,” Sisko said, voice softening.\n Bashir nodded, and went over to Miles. “Hello, what have we here?” he", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[33, 45, "PER"], [74, 80, "PER"], [158, 166, "SPEC"], [284, 291, "LOC"], [488, 493, "LOC"], [504, 510, "PER"], [607, 614, "SPEC"], [623, 630, "PER"], [767, 776, "LOC"], [779, 785, "PER"], [797, 803, "PER"], [845, 851, "PER"], [873, 879, "PER"], [941, 944, "LOC"], [958, 964, "PER"], [1024, 1027, "LOC"], [1068, 1076, "PER"], [1125, 1136, "ORG"], [1324, 1333, "ORG"], [1405, 1417, "PER"], [1436, 1442, "PER"], [1466, 1471, "PER"], [1673, 1678, "PER"], [1703, 1709, "PER"], [1735, 1740, "PER"]]}
{"id": 16, "text": "CHAPTER 5\n “Here we go again,” said Tom. He was seated on Chakotay’s left, in the pilot seat of the shuttlecraft. Tuvok, Torres, and Kim filled out the rest of the party. \n Ahead of the shuttle, the violet eye of the wormhole loomed large. Chakotay found that the experience of having passed through the aperture twice already wasn’t helping his stomach. His guts knew exactly what to expect, and it prepared for the ride by thrashing around inside of him well in advance.\n Chakotay cast a quick glance over his shoulder at the other three occupants of the shuttlecraft. Ensign Kim in the back looked about as green as Chakotay felt. Tuvok looked positively bored, as usual for the Vulcan. Torres was eyeing the wormhole with unwary fascination. She was obviously not prepared for the rough road that lay ahead.\n Chakotay caught her eye and flashed her an enigmatic smile that she clearly couldn’t interpret, and then they passed into the wormhole.\n A slight shimmy rattled through the spaceframe of the shuttlecraft, and then they were out on the other side. That was it. No sudden jolt to the inertial dampeners, and no abrupt torque on the shuttle’s nose cone, either.\n “What, that was it?” said Torres. “I was expecting…” She shrugged.\n Chakotay gave Lieutenant Paris a questioning look.\n “Don’t look at me, sir,” said Tom, “I only wish I could take the credit.”\n Ensign Kim consulted his console. “Variances inside of the wormhole were down in the two millicochrane range,” he said. “Telemetry suggests the wormhole spontaneously stabilized in the last seconds before we made the passage.”\n “And now, the wormhole is returning to its previous degree of instability,” Tuvok reported, consulting his own console. “It would appear that some external force acted momentarily to ensure our safe passage.”\n As Chakotay considered that bit of information, Ensign Kim ran more scans of the space surrounding the abandoned station. Lieutenant Torres tore her attention from the stunning view outside with an effort and turned her attention to her own console.\n “The power output of the station is roughly twice what it was the last time we were here, Commander,” said Ensign Kim.\n “At least,” Torres added. “And the power seems more stable and distributed around the station than what the telemetry from your last mission recorded.”\n “I guess the station’s been doing some straightening up since our last visit,” said Chakotay. He was just considering hailing the station again when his communications board lit up. \n A tone sounded from Ensign Kim’s ops console, and he announced, “Commander, we’re being hailed.”\n “I see that, Ensign,” said Chakotay, and he opened a channel with the press of a button.\n Lieutenant Paris said, “Commander, are you sure that’s such a good idea?” but it was already done.\n Chakotay just regarded Tom with a cocked eyebrow and a slight shrug.\n “Welcome, returning customers!” The voice of the station resembled the voice from the last visit in inflection and tone only. Where before it had been grating and artificial, it now sounded as clear and natural as organic speech.\n It went on, “You’ve reached the Delurididug Deep Space Travel Network and Trade Hub. Due to circumstances beyond our control, the Travel Network is currently unavailable. However, the Trade Hub is open for business! We are currently transmitting your instructions for docking.”\n Chakotay’s console received a packet of data from the station, which the computer was able to compile into a simple, graphically represented set of docking instructions. The voice from the station continued talking without pause.\n “Please be patient while those ships in queue ahead of yours finish their approaches and departures. Visitors will be cleared to dock in the same order that they arrived through the gateways.”\n Chakotay glanced around the empty space around the station and exchanged a look with Lieutenant Paris. Tom shook his head. No one else was out there.\n The automated voice went on, “All forms of faster-than-light travel and remote matter transference are prohibited inside of Hub Space. Any unwarranted act of violence or aggression against the Hub, the Network, the proprietors of the Hub, or other visitors to the Hub or Network is also prohibited. All contracts joined in good faith within the confines of Hub Space are binding. The Hub and its licensed proprietors reserve the right to withhold service from any customer for any reason. The Hub and the Network are committed to upholding the laws of the Delurididug Trade Federation, as well as the laws specific to the nationalities of each customer, subject to the limits of Trade Federation Law. The Delurididug Trade Hub is empowered by the Delurididug Trade Federation to enforce all binding contracts within the limits of Trade Federation law. Violations of binding contracts are subject to summary arbitration, and may result in confiscation of trade goods or formally recognized legal tender, expulsion from Hub Space, arrest pending trial in a Trade Federation Tribunal, or any combination of the above, subject to the judgment of the administration of the Trade Hub and within the limits of Trade Federation Law.\n “For more on the rules, regulations, and policies governing the Trade Hub Station and its surrounding space, please refer to the terms of service that are being transmitted now.” Chakotay studied his console as the computer received another data packet and compiled it into an encyclopedia-sized volume of alien legalese.\n “Tuvok, I’m sending you their rulebook. See if there’s anything in the rules about restricted areas. Maybe we can narrow down the possible locations of the computer core or their power generators, based on where they don’t want us to go. And while you’re at it, see if there’s a procedure in place for filing complaints.”\n “Aye, sir,” said Tuvok.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[36, 39, "PER"], [58, 68, "PER"], [114, 119, "PER"], [121, 127, "PER"], [133, 136, "PER"], [240, 248, "PER"], [474, 482, "PER"], [571, 581, "PER"], [619, 627, "PER"], [634, 639, "PER"], [682, 688, "SPEC"], [690, 696, "PER"], [813, 821, "PER"], [1199, 1205, "PER"], [1241, 1249, "PER"], [1255, 1271, "PER"], [1323, 1326, "PER"], [1368, 1378, "PER"], [1672, 1677, "PER"], [1809, 1817, "PER"], [1854, 1865, "PER"], [1928, 1945, "PER"], [2147, 2156, "PER"], [2164, 2174, "PER"], [2189, 2195, "PER"], [2414, 2422, "PER"], [2534, 2546, "PER"], [2579, 2588, "PER"], [2625, 2631, "PER"], [2639, 2647, "PER"], [2702, 2718, "PER"], [2726, 2735, "PER"], [2802, 2810, "PER"], [2825, 2828, "PER"], [3135, 3186, "LOC"], [3233, 3247, "LOC"], [3287, 3296, "LOC"], [3382, 3392, "PER"], [3807, 3815, "PER"], [3892, 3908, "PER"], [3910, 3913, "PER"], [4082, 4091, "LOC"], [4151, 4154, "ORG"], [4160, 4167, "ORG"], [4192, 4195, "LOC"], [4222, 4225, "LOC"], [4229, 4236, "LOC"], [4315, 4324, "LOC"], [4342, 4345, "LOC"], [4451, 4454, "ORG"], [4463, 4470, "ORG"], [4514, 4542, "ORG"], [4637, 4653, "ORG"], [4663, 4684, "ORG"], [4705, 4733, "ORG"], [4788, 4804, "ORG"], [4976, 4985, "LOC"], [5013, 5038, "ORG"], [5126, 5135, "ORG"], [5161, 5177, "ORG"], [5248, 5265, "LOC"], [5363, 5371, "PER"], [5508, 5513, "PER"], [5847, 5852, "PER"]]}
{"id": 17, "text": "“Respectfully, sir,” said Paris, “Do you really think there’s someone over there that handles complaints?”\n Chakotay shrugged. “We still don’t know the capabilities of the station, especially now that it’s regained so much function. But it’s clearly highly automated, and it seems to put a lot of value in laws and contracts. We might be able to use that to learn more about what’s happening to Ensign Kang, and hopefully, how to reverse it.”\n “You’re not seriously counting on that station to respect Federation laws, are you?” said Torres. “Our Federation, that is.”\n “I’m not counting on anything, Lieutenant,” said Chakotay, “Just exploring all options.”\n Harry shook his head, but he didn’t look up from his console.\n “Something the matter, Ensign?” said Chakotay.\n “No, sir,” said Harry. “Just… I keep thinking about Neelix’s ghost story.”\n Chakotay’s reply was interrupted by the voice of the station. “Thank you for your patience. Your vessel has been cleared to dock. We are sending you an updated flight plan to guide you to your berth. Any deviation from the flight plan is grounds to revoke your boarding privileges and move your vessel to the back of the queue. Repeated or flagrant violations may lead to expulsion from Hub Space.\n “If you prefer, you may turn over guidance to the Trade Hub guidance system, and we will guide your vessel into its berth.”\n “Fat chance,” Tom remarked.\n Chakotay’s console received the flight plan, and he sent it over to Tom. “Just stick to the flight plan, Tom. I’d hate to have to wait in that line again,” he deadpanned.\n Tom gave Chakotay a quizzical glance, and Chakotay favored him with a slight smile. \n With a smirk, Tom turned his attention back to his console and punched a series of instructions into the shuttle’s guidance system. “Aye, sir. Course laid in and plotted.”\n “Take us in,” said Chakotay.\n  \n \n  \n They entered the station through the same port as on their previous visit. Inside the bay, conditions had changed markedly. The atmosphere and gravity were the same, but the illumination had increased significantly, owing to an array of free-floating orbs of yellow-white light that hovered over the shuttle bay like little Suns, giving the space an inviting, almost Earth-like quality.\n Tom set the shuttle down exactly where the flight plan indicated and ran quickly through his power-down checklist while the rest of the crew gave their reports on the station. When they were ready, Tuvok opened the shuttle door.\n And he froze in the doorway.\n His expression betrayed no surprise or confusion, so it took a moment for Chakotay to understand why the security chief had paused in place. Chakotay looked out through the door and found a man standing in the docking bay at the bottom of the shuttle’s shallow ramp, hands spread wide in greeting.\n He looked human, with dusky but not dark features, slightly wavy, short, dark brown hair, the barest hint of points to his ears, the slightest upward angle of his eyebrows, and deep wrinkles in the center of his forehead that might have been the beginning of a cranial ridge. He had a wide smile, and his teeth were perfectly even and dazzlingly white. And, he wore a loose-fitting, flowing three-piece outfit woven from dark gray and deep burgundy fabrics, with curious accents of hardened leather on the shoulders and forearms, as if he were trying to split the difference between a traditional Terran suit, a Vulcan dignitary robe, and ceremonial Klingon armor.\n Tuvok overcame his momentary surprise and brought his tricorder to bear on the stranger.\n “Welcome to the Delurididug Trade Hub,” said the stranger. “I’m your host and point of contact for all of your questions and concerns regarding the station. You can call me Hux.”\n “It’s a projection, sir,” said Tuvok.\n Hux’s smile grew even wider. “Well spotted, Lieutenant!” he said. “When your party is all prepared, I can lead you to any of the publicly available levels of the station.” Turning to Chakotay, he said, “Tell me, how long can we expect to have the pleasure of your company, Commander…”\n “Chakotay,” said Chakotay. He was quietly impressed that the projection was apparently able to read and interpret his provisional rank insignia. Clearly, the station had gathered quite a bit of information on its deep dive through the shuttle’s computer core. He wondered if it didn’t already know each of their names, and was only letting him introduce himself as a matter of politeness.\n Remembering the projection had asked him a question, Chakotay added, “I’m not sure. It will depend on… how we might be able to help each other.”\n Hux nodded. “I look forward to discussing that with you. For now, let’s adjourn to a reception area, shall we?”\n Chakotay glanced back at his away team and verified that they were all ready to proceed.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[26, 31, "PER"], [108, 116, "PER"], [395, 406, "PER"], [502, 512, "GPE"], [547, 557, "GPE"], [601, 611, "PER"], [534, 540, "PER"], [619, 627, "PER"], [660, 665, "PER"], [746, 752, "PER"], [760, 768, "PER"], [787, 792, "PER"], [823, 831, "PER"], [847, 857, "PER"], [1234, 1243, "LOC"], [1296, 1305, "ORG"], [1400, 1410, "PER"], [1468, 1471, "PER"], [1505, 1508, "PER"], [1572, 1575, "PER"], [1581, 1589, "PER"], [1614, 1622, "PER"], [1672, 1675, "PER"], [1850, 1858, "PER"], [2236, 2241, "LOC"], [2257, 2260, "PER"], [2455, 2460, "PER"], [2591, 2599, "PER"], [2622, 2636, "PER"], [2658, 2666, "PER"], [2727, 2738, "LOC"], [2826, 2831, "SPEC"], [3413, 3419, "LOC"], [3428, 3434, "SPEC"], [3466, 3473, "SPEC"], [3482, 3487, "PER"], [3588, 3609, "LOC"], [3745, 3748, "PER"], [3783, 3788, "PER"], [3791, 3796, "PER"], [3835, 3845, "PER"], [3974, 3982, "PER"], [4064, 4073, "PER"], [4078, 4086, "PER"], [4094, 4102, "PER"], [4520, 4528, "PER"], [4613, 4616, "PER"], [4726, 4734, "PER"]]}
{"id": 18, "text": "“Lead the way,” he said.\n Hux led the away team towards the doors at the edge of the docking bay. Chakotay was gratified to see that his officers instinctively arrayed themselves in a rough pentagon, tricorders out and scanning their surroundings, phasers holstered but charged. No one needed to be reminded that they were still boarding a dangerous and unpredictable relic of an ancient and powerful civilization, regardless of the warm welcome they’d received thus far.\n When they reached the doorway, Hux stopped and addressed the party.\n “Now, those of you who have visited the Hub in the past are no doubt familiar with the scanner up ahead. For the rest of you, there’s no cause for alarm. The scanner is completely harmless. It provides the Trade Hub with a set of individualized biometrics in order to tailor our services for each individual. It’s also a security feature. The scanner will catalog your sidearms and any other self-defense implements on your person, as well as any hazardous materials you might be carrying. \n “Now, before you start to worry, allow me to reassure you that the Trade Hub does not make a habit of confiscating instruments of self-defense. However, we do employ a wide variety of neutralizing countermeasures in the event of accidental discharges or attempts at violence between guests. Your safety is among our highest priorities. If there are any questions about that, I’d be happy to answer them.”\n The others looked to Chakotay, and Hux seemed to follow their lead.\n Chakotay supposed it was a safe bet that the station was familiar with their phasers, seeing as it seemed to know everything else about them. He supposed there was no point in playing his cards close to his chest.\n “My away team is equipped with phased nadion beam weapons, calibrated to stun an attacker with non-lethal force. The Trade Hub won’t interfere with their functioning?”\n “Ah! Phasers are a classic, tried-and-true instrument of choice for a civilized society. And with a stun setting functionality! I applaud you on your choice. Humane, non-lethal weapons are truly a distinction of an advanced culture. \n “Of course, the Trade Hub will not interfere with the operation of your weapons. However, if any of them should happen to discharge during your stay in the Trade Hub, our countermeasures will neutralize their effect. The only exception is in the highly unlikely event that a rogue actor somehow manages to circumvent station security and take aggressive actions against members of your party. In such a case, the Trade Hub will not interfere in your legally recognized right to defend yourselves. However, any collateral damage that you might incur in such an event will need to be settled before you depart.”\n Chakotay nodded his understanding. “We’re also carrying subspace transceivers and general purpose handheld scanners. These will also be allowed to operate without interference?”\n “Of course!” said Hux, “So long as your instruments aren’t used to violate Trade Hub regulations or terms of service, we will not interfere with their operation in any way. Now, are there any more questions?”\n Chakotay glanced at the other members of the away team, inviting them to speak up if they could think of anything else to ask.\n “No?” said Hux, “Excellent. Let’s proceed.”\n The projection passed through the doorway. Chakotay waved Tuvok through, and the familiar light show flashed over him as he passed. Chakotay followed after, and the others followed him through, one at a time.\n When they were all through, Hux addressed the away team. “Now then, where would you like to begin? I regret that the inoperable state of the Travel Network has left the Trade Hub with a shortage of licensed vendors, but the Trade Hub still provides innumerable automated services and unique goods of sale that I guarantee, you will not find anywhere else in the galaxy. Based on your consumer history, can I suggest we proceed to the Aug-Tech Parlor, first?”\n Chakotay exchanged nonplussed expressions Tom and B’elanna.\n “What’s that?” said Chakotay.\n “Aug-Tech? Why, it’s our line of trademarked, consumer-grade, biosynthetic augmentation technologies, of course!”\n “Is that where we went on our previous visit?” said Chakotay.\n “Why, yes. Are you interested in augmenting another member of your party? Or perhaps you’re interested in purchasing one of our Aug-Tech augments for your crew? They’re highly customizable, able to fill a vast array of functions with greater efficiency than you’ve ever dreamed possible. Whether you’re in need of soldiers, technicians, recreational specialists…” He finished with a wink, making it all-too-clear what kind of ‘recreation’ he was referring to.\n Chakotay tasted bile. With effort, he restrained his anger.\n “Now, hold on!” said Lieutenant Torres. The same outrage that Chakotay felt was clear on the half-Klingon engineer’s face. Chakotay held up his hand to forestall an imminent outburst. Torres met his eyes and nodded her understanding.\n “Explain these augments to me, please,” said Chakotay.\n “Could you specify?” said Hux, “What exactly would you like me to explain?”\n “Are your augments living, sentient beings? Do they have any rights at all, or are they just… slaves?”\n Hux seemed confused by the question for just a moment before realization dawned. “Ah. I see your confusion,” said Hux. “It seems such practices are illegal in your civilization.”\n Chakotay nodded. “Yes, they certainly are.”\n “Hm. Well then, I’m afraid we can’t sell you any augments after all. It is the policy of the Hub never to facilitate activities that are classified as unlawful in the civilizations of our guests, you see. I’m terribly sorry if that poses any inconvenience.”\n “What if we wished to secure the freedom of your augments?” said Chakotay.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[26, 29, "PER"], [85, 96, "LOC"], [98, 106, "PER"], [504, 507, "PER"], [582, 585, "LOC"], [748, 757, "ORG"], [1101, 1110, "ORG"], [1461, 1469, "PER"], [1475, 1478, "PER"], [1509, 1517, "PER"], [1841, 1850, "ORG"], [2144, 2153, "ORG"], [2284, 2293, "LOC"], [2541, 2550, "ORG"], [2739, 2747, "PER"], [2936, 2939, "PER"], [2993, 3002, "ORG"], [3128, 3136, "PER"], [3267, 3270, "PER"], [3344, 3352, "PER"], [3359, 3364, "PER"], [3433, 3441, "PER"], [3539, 3542, "PER"], [3680, 3689, "ORG"], [3735, 3744, "ORG"], [3945, 3960, "LOC"], [3971, 3979, "PER"], [4013, 4016, "PER"], [4021, 4029, "PER"], [4052, 4060, "PER"], [4230, 4238, "PER"], [4702, 4710, "PER"], [4784, 4801, "PER"], [4825, 4833, "PER"], [4861, 4868, "SPEC"], [4886, 4894, "PER"], [4947, 4953, "PER"], [5043, 5051, "PER"], [5080, 5083, "PER"], [5235, 5238, "PER"], [5349, 5352, "PER"], [5415, 5423, "PER"], [5553, 5556, "PER"], [5784, 5792, "PER"]]}
{"id": 19, "text": "CHAPTER 6\n “Zut! That test was absolute merde!” said Lucy. She was still enjoying her newfound grasp of twentieth-century French. She’d studied Vulcan and Tellar languages in the Academy just to meet the core requirements, but she never really had a good head for languages. And besides, the universal translator was simply too convenient of a shortcut to even bother. She would have been hard pressed, these days, to recall even the more salient Tellarite curse words. But now, French invectives were free-flowing.\n “Whoever wrote that program can brûle en l’enfer! And what are you laughing at, Owen?”\n She whirled about on the security officer who was escorting her back to sickbay.\n Owen pinched his lips tight, trying to hide his mirth and failing. The other security officer, Crewman DeVries, subtly distanced himself from Owen, leaving him to bear the brunt of Lucy’s wrath.\n “Is it funny to you, that the Doctor is going to judge my fitness as a Starfleet officer on the outcome of a badly written holodeck melodrama?”\n After a promising start, the atmospheric Roma carnival setting had dissolved into chaos. A series of contrived plot twists revealed that half the food vendors were actually terrorists. They locked down the fairgrounds and rounded up as many hostages as they could get their hands on. Of course, the task of rescuing everyone fell almost immediately on Lucy. There was never a satisfactory reason given for this. She was simply a stranger in their midst that everyone decided to turn to for leadership. \n By this point, Lucy strongly suspected that someone had taken a beautifully crafted holodeck worldspace and overwritten it with the plot of a haphazard, clichéd action/adventure novel.\n Owen shook his head. “No. You’re right. The Doctor’s program was… merde.” He struggled and failed to hold in a smile.\n “Then what’s so funny?” Lucy shouted.\n “Nothing,” said Owen. “It’s just… nice to see you getting angry.”\n “What?” said Lucy. She shook her head in bewilderment. “Why?”\n “Just…” Owen cast a glance at Bobby DeVries, and lowered his voice to near-inaudibility. “Since what happened… You haven’t once gotten upset about anything.”\n Lucy blinked. “So what?”\n “So it was a really upsetting thing that happened!” he said. “I just… I don’t know if you’re in denial about it or what, but…”\n DeVries cleared his throat, bringing Owen up short.\n “Sorry,” said Owen, “I’m not supposed to talk about that. Let’s just get back to sickbay, ok?”\n Lucy didn’t move. “I’m not in denial,” she said. “I know what was done to me. I feel it, even now. But the worst is long over. I understand why everyone has their doubts, but I wish people would listen to me when I say I’m fine!”\n Owen sighed. “Well, good. I’m glad you’re ok. But I can’t help worrying about you, Lucy.”\n She almost asked “Why,” but the look on his face drew her up short. His concerns were etched into the lines around his ice-blue eyes, and deeper emotions seemed to dwell just under the surface of his gaze.\n Suddenly, Lucy didn’t know what to say. She stared into his eyes for a long moment, looking for a clearer sign of what he was thinking.\n Bobby cleared his throat again.\n Owen cast an annoyed glance at his colleague, then looked back at Lucy. “Your eyes are changing again,” he said.\n “Oh?” said Lucy. “Now what are they doing?”\n Owen smiled. “They’re going back to normal. They’re dark brown again, and the makeup is fading, too.”\n Lucy was relieved to hear it. She glanced down at her arms and saw her porcelain pallor was returning to its natural, olive tones. “Good,” she said.\n Another beat of silence passed, and suddenly it felt awkward.\n “Well, the Doctor’s going to start wondering where we are,” said Owen.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[53, 57, "PER"], [144, 150, "SPEC"], [155, 161, "SPEC"], [179, 186, "ORG"], [447, 456, "SPEC"], [597, 601, "PER"], [677, 684, "LOC"], [687, 691, "PER"], [782, 797, "PER"], [829, 833, "PER"], [868, 874, "PER"], [913, 919, "PER"], [954, 963, "ORG"], [1380, 1384, "PER"], [1547, 1551, "PER"], [1718, 1722, "PER"], [1616, 1624, "LOC"], [1006, 1014, "LOC"], [1762, 1770, "PER"], [1861, 1865, "PER"], [1892, 1896, "PER"], [1956, 1960, "PER"], [2014, 2018, "PER"], [2036, 2049, "PER"], [2165, 2169, "PER"], [2319, 2326, "PER"], [2356, 2360, "PER"], [2386, 2390, "PER"], [2453, 2460, "LOC"], [2468, 2472, "PER"], [2699, 2703, "PER"], [2782, 2786, "PER"], [3007, 3011, "PER"], [3134, 3139, "PER"], [3167, 3171, "PER"], [3233, 3237, "PER"], [3292, 3296, "PER"], [3326, 3330, "PER"], [3429, 3433, "PER"], [3653, 3661, "PER"], [3707, 3711, "PER"]]}
{"id": 20, "text": "“Right,” said Lucy. “Let’s go.” She turned around to head towards sickbay, but at the mention of the Doctor, she remembered the bloodbath that the holonovel had become, and her anger returned in force. “But I swear, if he tries to blame me for the outcome of that terrible program…”\n “I’ll vouch for you,” said Owen. He put a comforting hand on her shoulder, and soothing warmth seemed to suffuse her body from the touch, working wonders for her temper. She was halfway tempted to put her hand over his until he began gently pushing, trying to urge her back into motion. “You did everything that could be expected from a junior science officer.”\n The way he qualified his statement rubbed Lucy the wrong way. She pushed his hand away and turned on him again. “What, you think you could have done better?” she challenged.\n Owen just pointed down the corridor towards sickbay.\n “Hmpf,” said Lucy, and she turned around and marched the rest of the way to sickbay without looking back.\n  \n \n  \n “I’m sorry, Ensign, I can’t clear you for duty yet.”\n “Why?” said Lucy, “Because I couldn’t save some of the hostages?”\n “No, that’s not it,” said the Doctor.\n They were back in the Doctor’s office, and Owen and Bobby were back to guarding the entrance to sickbay. For now, Lucy and the Doctor could converse in private.\n “What was I supposed to do,” said Lucy, “go all Michael Bernam? Maybe that would have worked in that two-bit hack holonovel, but in the real world—”\n “I said…” the Doctor tried to talk over her, but Lucy steamrolled forward.\n “Those sorts of shoot-from-the-hip heroics just start wars and get people killed! I tried to get into their heads. I tried to find their motivations so I could work out a peaceful resolution! Little did I know, they were all just cartoon villains! If you took me to the holodeck just to play a shoot-em-up, why even—”\n “Ensign Kang!” the Doctor shouted, and finally, Lucy broke off her tirade. “Your performance in that… ‘two-bit hack holonovel’ that I wrote…” \n Lucy cringed. \n “…is not the issue. The goal was never to judge you by the outcome of the scenario, but to assess your mental condition by your behavior under unfamiliar and stressful circumstances.”\n Lucy absorbed this fact and struggled to process it. “Is this because I bought a hat, then?”\n The Doctor sighed. “No. It was not any single decision or mistake that you made.”\n “Then please, Doctor,” said Lucy, “explain it to me. I really can’t understand.”\n The Doctor paused to consider. “And how does that make you feel?”\n “Upset,” said Lucy.\n “Upset how?” said the Doctor. “Does it make you sad? Or are you afraid for your career? Your future?”\n “No,” said Lucy, “I’m angry, and I’m frustrated. I had a goal. I was supposed to save those hostages, but it was a total Kobayashi Maru. The only way to break the stalemate would have been to start killing terrorists.”\n “And did that ever cross your mind as a legitimate option?” said the Doctor.\n “Not for a moment,” said Lucy. “Even if we could have killed them all with zero collateral damage, which I highly doubt, and in spite of the fact I didn’t agree with their methods or their goals, it wasn’t my place to pick sides in their conflict. It was a classic Prime Directive scenario.”\n The Doctor paused, momentarily considering her point. “An interesting perspective.”\n “Is that why I failed?”\n The Doctor uttered a frustrated sigh. “I told you, it was nothing specific! There was no ‘right’ answer! Ensign…” He grasped for the right words for a moment before going on, “You can’t feel pain. Your shoe melted into your foot, and you didn’t even limp. And your emotional responses are completely atypical. You showed more concern for the shoe than for your foot, and you demonstrated as much sympathy for the terrorists as for the victims.”", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[14, 18, "PER"], [66, 73, "LOC"], [101, 107, "PER"], [311, 315, "PER"], [621, 643, "PER"], [689, 693, "PER"], [822, 826, "PER"], [866, 873, "LOC"], [889, 893, "PER"], [952, 959, "LOC"], [1003, 1009, "PER"], [1057, 1061, "PER"], [1142, 1148, "PER"], [1173, 1188, "LOC"], [1194, 1198, "PER"], [1203, 1208, "PER"], [1265, 1269, "PER"], [1278, 1284, "PER"], [1347, 1351, "PER"], [1361, 1375, "PER"], [1477, 1483, "PER"], [1512, 1516, "PER"], [1809, 1817, "LOC"], [1859, 1870, "PER"], [1877, 1883, "PER"], [1906, 1910, "PER"], [2002, 2006, "PER"], [2203, 2207, "PER"], [2301, 2307, "PER"], [2394, 2400, "PER"], [2408, 2412, "PER"], [2466, 2472, "PER"], [2543, 2547, "PER"], [2572, 2578, "PER"], [2664, 2668, "PER"], [2774, 2788, "SHIP"], [2942, 2948, "PER"], [2976, 2980, "PER"], [3248, 3254, "PER"], [3358, 3364, "PER"], [3459, 3465, "PER"]]}
{"id": 21, "text": "“I was mediating!” Lucy retorted, but the Doctor went on regardless.\n “You approached them without even trying to work out out a contingency plan or find a weapon for self-defense. They could have shot you where you stood just to make a point!”\n “They were scared!” said Lucy. “They needed someone to hear their demands, or they would have started killing hostages even sooner. Your writing made it obvious that I was the one that would be expected to step forward, so I did. I was just following the plot.”\n “As you saw it, perhaps,” said the Doctor. “But the most serious problem had nothing to do with your choices or your emotions. Ensign, your biosynthetic implants just dropped the entire French language into your head, and you didn’t skip a beat. You hardly even noticed, until I pointed it out. That degree of cognitive synergy speaks to the profound extent to which an unknown alien artificial intelligence has insinuated itself into your brain.”\n “What?” said Lucy. “You don’t think I’m Lucy Kang anymore? What am I then, a Borg?”\n “You’re still you,” said the Doctor, his voice much softer than before. “You’re still Lucille Kang. Your capacity for empathy, your cleverness, your wit, that’s all you. But you’re something more, now, too. That’s what frightens me.”\n “Well then, how long is it going to take, to prove I can be trusted again?” said Lucy.\n The Doctor shook his head. “Hopefully, we won’t have to deal with that. Commander Chakotay is back on that station right now, looking for a way to reverse what was done to you.”\n Lucy tasted something bitter. “Why didn’t anyone tell me?” she said.\n “You’re right, I should have,” said the Doctor. “I was preoccupied with setting up your assessment.”\n Lucy shook her head. “You’re not the only person who could have let me know. The Captain, or Chakotay, or anyone on the senior staff could have told me what they intended to do. I’m just an afterthought in all this, aren’t I?”\n “Far from it, Ensign,” said the Doctor.\n “But what if the cure is just as grisly and invasive as the cause? Will they even ask my permission, or will they just order me to hop back into that pod?”\n “Ensign…”\n Lucy shook her head. “They didn’t even give me a chance, did they? They saw I looked different, they saw I acted different, and immediately they just assumed they had to ‘turn me back’ somehow. I can’t even imagine what that would be like, Doctor! All this trauma and misery that people keep expecting me to feel? Why would I want that?”\n The Doctor looked perplexed. “You don’t want to be… you again, Lucy?”\n “I am me, Doctor! You said it yourself! I’m me, and I’m more! And your bogus test is a far cry from convincing me that that’s a bad thing.”\n The Doctor’s confusion faded, giving rise to a carefully neutral expression. “I’ll be sure to pass that sentiment on to the Captain, then,” he said.\n “Well… good!” said Lucy. “I’m a member of this crew, dammit. I deserve to be heard.”\n The Doctor nodded. “Of course.”\n With that settled, Lucy walked out of the Doctor’s office and back into sickbay. “So, what am I supposed to do now? Sit on a biobed and twiddle my thumbs?”\n The Doctor shook his head. “Your security clearances are still on hold, but you’re clear to visit all unrestricted areas of the ship. You’ll have two security personnel with you at all times outside of your quarters, and your activities will be monitored.”\n Lucy opened her mouth to complain, but the Doctor cut her off. \n “Those are the captain’s orders. Furthermore, you’re to report back to sickbay at oh-seven-hundred hours for a complete medical assessment, so I can monitor the progression of your condition. And keep me informed of any new symptoms you may experience in the meantime. Those are my orders. Are we clear, Ensign?”\n “Yes, Doctor,” said Lucy, making every effort to stifle her resentment. As stacked as the test had seemed, she had to acknowledge that the Doctor knew what he was doing. Whether she agreed with him or not, his judgment must have had some merit, at least from a certain point of view. Continuing to belabor the point would only serve to reinforce his conclusions.\n Lucy turned to the sickbay doors and walked straight through, studiously avoiding eye contact with Owen or Bobby as she passed between them. Without looking back, she knew they had followed her through the door by their soft footsteps on the carpeted deck.\n Lucy pondered what to do with the rest of her day. She couldn’t even enter the BNG labs without her security clearances. She found it a little absurd that she would even contemplate visiting her workplace on a day off, and yet, she yearned to do just that. Voyager only had a couple other technicians that were even qualified to do her job, and they would both be pulling extra shifts for the foreseeable future to cover for her absence. Even if she couldn’t take on any of the work, she would have liked to check in on them and offer some moral support. Maybe she could catch up with Raeger or Kigon in the commissary later to see if they could use any work advice or moral support, but right now they were sure to be in the middle of a shift or deep in a sleep cycle.\n She wasn’t hungry, so there was no reason to visit the commissary right now. She was absolutely sick of holograms, so obviously the Holodeck was out of the question. Lucy supposed she might as well just return to her quarters.\n Crewman Jarvin passed Lucy in the corridor. His step faltered when he saw her, and his eyes darted over her several times.\n “Something the matter, Crewman?” said Lucy.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[19, 23, "PER"], [42, 48, "PER"], [271, 275, "PER"], [544, 550, "PER"], [636, 642, "PER"], [971, 975, "PER"], [998, 1007, "PER"], [1035, 1039, "SPEC"], [1072, 1078, "PER"], [1129, 1141, "PER"], [1359, 1363, "PER"], [1370, 1376, "PER"], [1438, 1456, "PER"], [1545, 1549, "PER"], [1655, 1661, "PER"], [1717, 1721, "PER"], [1798, 1805, "PER"], [1810, 1818, "PER"], [1959, 1965, "PER"], [1977, 1983, "PER"], [2144, 2150, "PER"], [2154, 2158, "PER"], [2394, 2400, "PER"], [2497, 2503, "PER"], [2556, 2560, "PER"], [2574, 2580, "PER"], [2709, 2717, "PER"], [2829, 2836, "PER"], [2874, 2878, "PER"], [2945, 2951, "PER"], [2993, 2997, "PER"], [3016, 3024, "PER"], [3046, 3053, "LOC"], [3135, 3141, "PER"], [3389, 3393, "PER"], [3432, 3438, "PER"], [3469, 3478, "PER"], [3525, 3532, "LOC"], [3758, 3764, "PER"], [3774, 3780, "PER"], [3788, 3792, "PER"], [3907, 3913, "PER"], [4132, 4136, "PER"], [4151, 4158, "LOC"], [4231, 4235, "PER"], [4239, 4244, "PER"], [4390, 4394, "PER"], [4469, 4477, "LOC"], [4647, 4654, "SHIP"], [4975, 4981, "PER"], [4985, 4990, "PER"], [4998, 5008, "LOC"], [5293, 5301, "LOC"], [5327, 5331, "PER"], [5389, 5403, "PER"], [5411, 5415, "PER"], [5536, 5543, "PER"], [5551, 5555, "PER"]]}
{"id": 22, "text": "CHAPTER 7\n “I say we fly Voyager in there and ram a few photon torpedoes up their aft ventral porthole! See how they like that!” Lieutenant Torres raged. \n The senior staff was gathered in the conference room, minus Chakotay, who was still being held captive on the space station. They hadn’t been sitting at the conference table more than a couple minutes before Torres was back on her feet, though, pacing back and forth down the length of the table.\n Janeway regarded the hot-headed engineer patiently, deciding it would be better just to let Torres vent her frustrations and get it out of the way. After all, she was just giving voice to the frustration that pervaded the whole room. They were angry, and they were worried for Chakotay, and everyone needed to acknowledge it—everyone but Tuvok, of course.\n  “The Delurididug Trade Hub holds significant strategic advantages over Voyager,” he Vulcan-splained. “It exists within an isolated region of space, over which it appears to control both ingress and egress. It has far more advanced technology than Voyager, it generates far more power than Voyager, and its immense bulk likely hides defensive systems significantly more formidable than Voyager’s. Such a confrontation is unlikely to end in our favor.”\n Torres waved off his objection. “We don’t even know if the station is armed. We scanned every inch of it, and I didn’t see an operational weapons system.”\n “Indeed,” said Tuvok, “We have been able to discern very little about key functions on the station. We cannot identify a computer core, a power source, or any form of warp field generator. And yet, we have ample evidence that the station has each of these systems. Therefore, the station is either employing technology so foreign and advanced that we cannot recognize it, or it is somehow disguising these systems from our scans. The same could go for weapons.”\n B’elanna shook her head. “It’s unmanned. Whatever advanced technology may or may not be on board is useless if no one is there to operate it.”\n Tuvok arched an eyebrow. “Is it your contention that the A.I. of the station is incapable of autonomous self-defense?”\n B’elanna looked uncertain for a moment. Then she threw her hands up and plopped herself back into her chair. “Oh, how the hell should I know?” she said.\n Tuvok nodded. “Well put, Lieutenant,” he said. “We do not know enough at this time to justify putting Voyager at risk.”\n “So what, then?” said Torres, “Do we abandon Commander Chakotay? Or do we play along? Throw ourselves on the mercy of a long-defunct court and the judgment of a malfunctioning hologram?”\n “Whether or not we take that course should depend on the laws of the court in question. I am still in the process of familiarizing myself with the Delurididug legal code. It is a curious system of governance; a technocratic meritocracy, its laws rigid, yet robust; idiosyncratic, yet imminently logical. Once we have an adequate understanding of their laws, we may be able to formulate an effective defense for Commander Chakotay.”\n “And what if we can’t?” said Harry. “What if we don’t have a case? Then what do we do?”\n “Maybe we can plan a jailbreak,” said Tom.\n “I would calculate our odds of securing Commander Chakotay’s escape as less than one point five percent, given their ability to neutralize our weapons inside of the station,” said Tuvok.\n “And even if we manage to pull it off, we can forget about getting a wormhole to the Federation,” said Harry, “Or curing Ensign Kang.”\n “I’m afraid there are other hurdles where Ensign Kang is concerned,” said the Doctor.\n The others turned to the wall monitor that displayed the Doctor’s image.\n “What’s the status of your patient, Doctor?” said Captain Janeway.\n The Doctor took a moment to consider his response. “Well, physically, her condition is downright superhuman. I’ve been monitoring her vitals and activities remotely since she left sickbay. She spent an hour in the deck eight gymnasium, during which time she performed a complete calisthenics routine at three times standard gravity, ran twenty-five kilometers, and burned over four thousand calories. Her pulse never exceeded one hundred twenty beats a minute, and as far as I can tell from remote sensors, there was none of the lactic acid buildup in her tissues that such a strenuous workout should have produced. Afterward, she ordered an eighteen hundred calorie meal from her personal replicator, and at last check, she appeared to be sleeping. I’ll be able to tell you more about her physical condition in the morning, after her next physical.\n “Psychologically… The results of my assessment were deeply ambiguous. Her problem-solving abilities are excellent, but prior testing suggests this is a pre-existing trait. Her regard for life and her empathic instincts are very strong, but by the same token, her capacity for emotional detachment is lacking. Again, this matches the results of her prior psychological assessments. In these regards, her personality is essentially intact.\n “One item of concern is her lack of cautious reflexes. If she saw a snake by her foot, for instance, she would not jump away from it on instinct. She would register the snake, decide consciously if it were a threat, and reason out an appropriate reaction. By the time she decided what to do, the snake might have already bitten her ankle. Her power of reasoning is excellent, but in emotionally fraught and emergent situations, I’m afraid this cognitive deficit will present a powerful liability.\n “Of even greater concern are the cognitive enhancements that she has begun demonstrating. During the assessment, I chose to deprive the ensign of her universal translator. Seeing as many of the characters in the program spoke only 20th Century French, I thought this would provide an additional challenge. Instead, the ensign learned a new language, fluently, in a matter of minutes—just by being in the presence of people speaking it. The implants are certainly interacting with her brain, providing cognitive enhancements in specialized tasks like language acquisition. As to any other ways they may be affecting her cognition, I can’t yet say.\n “But what concerns me most of all is that the ensign is starting to show a strong reticence towards the notion of reversing her condition.”\n There was a beat of quiet around the conference table as the staff absorbed the Doctor’s meaning. Evidently, none of the others had considered that Ensign Kang might not want to be cured.\n “Well, I guess I can’t really blame her,” said Tom.\n The others all looked at Tom, and he sat forward in his chair.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[25, 32, "SHIP"], [129, 146, "PER"], [216, 224, "PER"], [364, 370, "PER"], [454, 461, "PER"], [546, 552, "PER"], [731, 739, "PER"], [792, 797, "PER"], [817, 838, "LOC"], [883, 890, "SHIP"], [896, 902, "SPEC"], [1059, 1066, "SHIP"], [1101, 1108, "SHIP"], [1197, 1206, "SHIP"], [1264, 1270, "PER"], [1323, 1330, "LOC"], [1435, 1440, "PER"], [1883, 1891, "PER"], [2027, 2032, "PER"], [2147, 2155, "PER"], [2301, 2306, "PER"], [2326, 2336, "PER"], [2403, 2410, "SHIP"], [2444, 2450, "PER"], [2467, 2485, "PER"], [2757, 2768, "SPEC"], [3021, 3039, "PER"], [3072, 3077, "PER"], [3170, 3173, "PER"], [3216, 3236, "PER"], [3356, 3361, "PER"], [3467, 3472, "PER"], [3449, 3459, "LOC"], [3485, 3496, "PER"], [3542, 3553, "PER"], [3578, 3584, "PER"], [3644, 3652, "PER"], [3697, 3703, "PER"], [3711, 3726, "PER"], [3733, 3739, "PER"], [3909, 3916, "LOC"], [5188, 5193, "SPEC"], [5087, 5092, "SPEC"], [5315, 5320, "SPEC"], [5653, 5659, "PER"], [5836, 5842, "PER"], [6211, 6217, "PER"], [6386, 6394, "PER"], [6454, 6465, "PER"], [6542, 6545, "PER"], [6573, 6576, "PER"]]}
{"id": 23, "text": "“Hey, she’s got superpowers,” he said. “She’s faster than a speeding bullet, able to leap tall buildings in a single bound.”\n Tuvok’s eyebrow crawled about halfway up his scalp.\n “Figuratively, I mean,” said Tom. “And she’s unrestrained by negative emotions. That sounds like it would be hard to give up.”\n “Actually,” said the Doctor, “She has quite a few negative emotions. Unfortunately, without the ability to express sorrow about her circumstances, her emotional release seems to come primarily in the form of anger. She’s resentful, Captain. She feels she should have been consulted before Commander Chakotay led a risky away mission on her behalf. She resents being treated with suspicion and kept from resuming her post. So far, her reason and her sense of empathy seem to be working to defuse her anger, but I’m not convinced it will last.”\n Janeway nodded to the Doctor. “Well, for what it’s worth, I think she has a point,” she said. Then she addressed the room. \n “Torres, Kim, get to work analyzing all the data we have on the structure of the station. We need to learn as much as we can about its external hardpoints and its internal structure. Paris, get with Lieutenant Ayala and start on that jailbreak scenario. \n “Tuvok, I’ll need you sorting out their laws and devising our case. Gather all the help you need, from any department. \n “If we can beat their legal system, we will. If we can’t, we go with a jailbreak. And in case that fails, Torres, Kim… once we know everything we possibly can about that station, start working on a way to cripple it. Once we have the upper hand, maybe the station will listen to reason. But that’s our last resort.\n “Does anyone have questions?”\n “What about Ensign Kang, sir?” said the Doctor.\n Janeway rested her chin on her hand a moment, her gaze far away, as she considered the problem. “That is the question, isn’t it?” Finally, she braced her hands against the table and pushed herself up to her feet. “I think it’s time I paid her a visit. Now, let’s get to work, people. You’re dismissed.”\n  \n \n  \n Lucy writhed languidly against the silky fabric of her bedsheets, reveling in the afterglow. Owen rested his head on his hands and stared up at the deckhead, an easy, almost sedated smile on his face. She rolled over to face him, propping herself up on her elbow.\n He cast a sidelong glance her way, and she quirked a questioning eyebrow. He reached out and ran his hand through her hair just above her left ear, gently massaging her scalp with his fingertips.\n “Are you petting me like a dog right now?” said Lucy, although she made no move to stop him. His touch sent happy shivers through her whole body.\n “Just making sure you’re not secretly a Deltan,” said Owen.\n Lucy gave a breathy chuckle. “Why, because you’re afraid my lovemaking has left you incurably insane? Or is it because my hair looks like a wig?” Deltans had a near-human aspect, minus cranial hair. They were also legendary love-makers, with passions so intense they could literally drive a human mad. Or that was the legend, at any rate. Lucy doubted it could be entirely accurate.\n “Definitely the first one,” he said.\n Lucy nearly made a pithy retort about how with her enhancements, anything was possible, but she held back—in part, because she was sick of bringing up the subject, and in part, because she realized it was true.\n “Do you think this might have been a mistake?” she said.\n Owen’s expression sobered. His hand slid from her hair to her cheek, cupping her jawline with his palm. He shook his head. “No.”\n Lucy sighed. She couldn’t help nuzzling into his hand a little bit, but she couldn’t ignore the implications of what they’d just done. She leaned back, breaking contact.\n “What if I’m contagious, somehow?” she asked.\n “The Doctor wouldn’t have let you out of sickbay,” he said.\n Lucy shrugged. “What does he know? I’m infected with technology centuries ahead of ours. The Doctor can only guess what all it can do.”\n Owen considered for a moment. “Well then, at least you won’t be going through it alone anymore.”\n Lucy rolled her eyes. “Come on, that wouldn’t make me feel any better. I’d just feel guilty for dragging you down with me.”\n “Dragging me up, you mean? Your thing comes with enhancements, remember?”", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[126, 133, "PER"], [208, 211, "PER"], [328, 334, "PER"], [539, 546, "PER"], [596, 614, "PER"], [851, 858, "PER"], [873, 879, "PER"], [977, 983, "PER"], [985, 988, "PER"], [1159, 1164, "PER"], [1175, 1191, "PER"], [1233, 1238, "PER"], [1459, 1465, "PER"], [1467, 1470, "PER"], [1712, 1723, "PER"], [1740, 1746, "PER"], [1749, 1756, "PER"], [2061, 2065, "PER"], [2154, 2158, "PER"], [2209, 2217, "LOC"], [2571, 2575, "PER"], [2710, 2716, "SPEC"], [2724, 2728, "PER"], [2731, 2735, "PER"], [2877, 2884, "SPEC"], [3022, 3027, "SPEC"], [3070, 3074, "PER"], [3153, 3157, "PER"], [3423, 3429, "PER"], [3553, 3557, "PER"], [3776, 3782, "PER"], [3812, 3819, "LOC"], [3832, 3836, "PER"], [3925, 3931, "PER"], [3969, 3973, "PER"], [4067, 4071, "PER"]]}
{"id": 24, "text": "“Whatever, you know what I mean.”\n “Well, either way, you’d have no reason to feel guilty. I seduced you, remember?”\n Lucy laughed. “Is that what you call insulting me, and then begging for forgiveness?”\n Owen put on a roguish smile. “That’s my trademark Vance charm.”\n He was so cute when he showed unearned confidence. Lucy leaned closer to him.\n “Oh, that’s what it is?” said Lucy. She brought her face within a couple centimeters of his. She could feel his breath on her cheek.\n “Uh huh,” he said.\n “Yeah?” she said, and she kissed him. He returned her kiss readily, and things progressed quickly from there. Soon, the world seemed to fade away around them, until nothing was left but those points where their two bodies met; hands exploring sensitive flesh, legs brushing legs, interlocking lips, conjoined hips, and nothing in between them but friction and perspiration.\n Afterward, Lucy and Owen both stared up at the deckhead. Lucy felt as blissful and sensuous as ever, but Owen was starting to doze off, his eyelids slowly drifting shut.\n Then, that same nagging doubt popped back into her mind. “Do you think the Doctor will be mad?” she said.\n Owen opened his eyes again and looked at her. “Are you going to tell him?”\n “I have another check-up first thing in the morning,” said Lucy. “I’m sure he’ll figure it out.”\n Owen’s brow furrowed. “Well, he never told you not to have sex, did he?”\n “No,” said Lucy. “But now it seems like kind of a no-brainer, right?”\n Owen shrugged. “Well, what’s done is done. I’ll report to sickbay with you and get checked over, just to be safe, ok?”\n Lucy tried to imagine the Doctor’s reaction when they confessed what they’d done. She smiled. “He’ll definitely be mad. You sure you want to be there when he finds out?”\n “Well, I wouldn’t want you to bear the brunt of it.”\n Lucy shook her head. “I’m not afraid of that.”\n “Of course not,” said Owen. “You’re not afraid of anything.”\n There was a quiet beat. Lucy realized she was getting pretty hungry. \n “You wanna get some—” \n “Sorry.”\n They’d spoken at the same time.\n “For what?” said Lucy. \n “I mean…” said Owen, and he studied her face for a second. Lucy stared back, mildly confused. What had he done this time?\n “Nothing,” said Owen. “Nevermind.”\n Lucy nodded, deciding that if Owen had stuck his foot in his mouth again and she’d missed it, then it was really for the best.\n “You wanna get some kimbap?” said Lucy.\n “What’s that?” said Owen.\n “It’s like sushi,”", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[118, 122, "PER"], [205, 209, "PER"], [255, 260, "PER"], [321, 325, "PER"], [379, 383, "PER"], [889, 893, "PER"], [898, 902, "PER"], [925, 933, "LOC"], [935, 939, "PER"], [983, 987, "PER"], [1124, 1130, "PER"], [1156, 1160, "PER"], [1291, 1295, "PER"], [1330, 1336, "PER"], [1415, 1419, "PER"], [1475, 1479, "PER"], [1533, 1540, "LOC"], [1595, 1599, "PER"], [1621, 1629, "PER"], [1820, 1824, "PER"], [1890, 1894, "PER"], [1954, 1958, "PER"], [2085, 2089, "PER"], [2108, 2112, "PER"], [2152, 2156, "PER"], [2232, 2236, "PER"], [2252, 2256, "PER"], [2282, 2286, "PER"], [2414, 2418, "PER"], [2441, 2445, "PER"]]}
