{"id": 546, "text": "In\nmemory of  Jerome Bixby \n [Quark's]\n\n(Bashir and Ezri are together at a table, talking.\nOdo is with Quark at the bar.) \nQUARK: Have you ever seen anything so disgusting? The way he's\nundressing her with his eyes. And look at his hands. \nODO: What about his hands? \nQUARK: His gestures. They're obscene. You should arrest him. \nODO: You're joking. \nQUARK: He's pitiful. Doesn't he realise she loves me? \nODO: I don't think he does. To be honest, I don't think she does\neither. \nQUARK: Thanks for your support. \nROM: Brother! I just talked to Moogie. She says Grand Nagus Zek has\ndisappeared. \nQUARK: What do you mean, disappeared? \nROM: He left her a note saying he was going on a business safari to\nopen new territories for financial exploitation. \nQUARK: That's our Nagus. \nROM: He said he'd be back in five days. That was twelve days ago! \nQUARK: Twelve? \nODO: Has he done this before? \nROM: Not for this long. Moogie did some checking. No one's heard from\nhim. He could be hurt or even dead. We have to do something! \nQUARK: He probably stopped off on Risa. You know, for a little rest and\nrelaxation. \nROM: Risa? With all those gorgeous women? He wouldn't do that to\nMoogie. \nQUARK: Have you looked at our mother lately? She's not getting any\nyounger. Now do us both a favour and stop worrying about Zek. He'll\nshow up. \nROM: Are you sure? \nQUARK: Goodbye, Rom. Goodbye. Where'd Ezri go? \nODO: Oh, she slipped out the back with Bashir. \nQUARK: They left together? \nODO: I think they were holding hands. \nQUARK: Oh.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[30, 37, "LOC"], [41, 47, "PER"], [52, 56, "PER"], [14, 26, "PER"], [91, 94, "PER"], [103, 108, "PER"], [544, 550, "PER"], [561, 576, "PER"], [770, 775, "PER"], [916, 922, "PER"], [1058, 1062, "LOC"], [1114, 1118, "LOC"], [1174, 1180, "PER"], [1307, 1310, "PER"], [1364, 1367, "PER"], [1386, 1390, "PER"], [1435, 1441, "PER"]]}
{"id": 757, "text": "[Arctic Circle, Earth] \n (It is\nstill a cold, snow-covered landscape that the transport lands in,\ndespite the current global warming predictions. Three figures in thermal suits are scanning for\nsomething.) \nDRAKE: (older man) I think this is the place. (They stare at the\nwreckage.) DRAKE: Take a look around. (A woman uncovers a corpse in the snow.) \nROONEY: Over here!\nDefinitely humanoid, but I don't recognise the species. \nDRAKE: Seems very well preserved. \nMONINGER: (younger, taller man) Getting him out of here's going to be a\ndelicate operation. \nDRAKE: Drake to Arctic One. \nVOICE [OC]: Go ahead. \nDRAKE: Set up a base camp. Get Alpha Team started. \nVOICE [OC]: Acknowledged. \nDRAKE: Contact Starfleet. Tell Commander Williams he owes me a bottle\nof Scotch. \nVOICE [OC]: Sir? \nDRAKE: He'll know what it means. Drake out. \nROONEY: I'm picking up EM traces a few dozen metres under the glacier.\nThere's a lot more here than we're seeing. (she heads off following her\nscanner signals) We've got another one! \n [Base\ncamp] \n (Two\ncybernetic looking corpses are laid out, and a mechanical arm gets put\non a table.) \nDRAKE: I give up. What is it? \nMONINGER: An arm. It's his. \nDRAKE: You're joking. \nMONINGER: From what I can tell, it was integrated into his circulatory\nand nervous systems. He could probably operate it like it was his own\nflesh and blood. \nDRAKE: I met a Vulcan scientist who wore a prosthesis. He lost his\nforearm. It's pretty sophisticated, but it doesn't compare to this. \nMONINGER: Take a look at the eyepiece. Judging by the optics, I'd say\nhe could see most of the EM spectrum. \nDRAKE: Did you run a genetic analysis? \nMONINGER: That's even more interesting. They don't have much in common.\nThey belong to two different species. \nDRAKE: Transmit your findings to Starfleet. Maybe they'll find a match", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 21, "LOC"], [572, 582, "SHIP"], [639, 649, "ORG"], [702, 711, "ORG"], [718, 736, "PER"], [1378, 1384, "SPEC"], [1792, 1801, "ORG"]]}
{"id": 489, "text": "Day 1\n\n [Krenim\nTimeship - Bridge] \n(Above a\ncity built on the usual grid system with travel tubes in mid air, a\nspaceship with six projections is hanging. The projections hold a\nmassive 'jewel' at one end, which magnifies the energy pulse the ship\naims at the city. The city is transformed into woodland and open\nmeadows.) \nOBRIST:\nTemporal incursion is complete. All organisms and man-made objects have\nbeen eradicated. \nANNORAX: Probe the continuum. Has our target event been achieved? \nOBRIST: Negative. Negative target event. I don't understand, sir. We\nspent months making these calculations. \nANNORAX: Time is patient, so we must be patient with it. Eradicating a\nsingle Zahl colony wasn't enough for a total restoration. We have to\nwork on a larger scale. Take us to the Zahl homeworld. Prepare a new\nset of calculations. We must erase the entire species from time. Every\nlifeform, every molecule. \n [Astrometrics\nlab] \n\nJANEWAY: Space, the great unknown, Only now we're going to know it a\nlittle better. Harry? \n(An image of our galaxy from above is divided into grids. Note to the\ninterested, the long wig has finally been discarded and Janeway has\nKate Mulgrew's natural shorter length hair.)\nCHAKOTAY: Before there were maps and globes, let alone radar and\nsubspace sensors, mariners navigated by the stars. We're returning to\nthat tried and true method, but this time there's a difference. \nJANEWAY: Ensign Kim and Seven of Nine have merged Starfleet and Borg\ningenuity to create this new technology.And I'm sure I speak for the\nentire crew when I say, thank you. Now, how the hell does it work? \nSEVEN: Astrometric sensors measure the radiative flux of up to three\nbillion stars simultaneously. The computer then calculates our position\nrelative to the centre of the galaxy. \nKIM: This mapping technology is ten times more accurate than what we've\nbeen using. Seven, will you do the honours? We've plotted a new course\nhome. \nSEVEN: By my estimates this trajectory will eliminate five years from", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": []}
{"id": 667, "text": "Second\nOfficer's personal Log, Stardate 44390.1. Record entry for transmission\nto Commander Bruce Maddox, Cybernetics Division, Daystrom Institute.\nDear Commander Maddox, \n[Bridge]\n\nDATA [OC]: In reference to your most recent letter,\nI agree that your study lacks sufficient primary source information on\nmy programming and operation. Therefore, in response to your request,\nthis correspondence will include a complete record of my activities\nduring a normal day, with particular emphasis on my perceptions of\nfriendship. \n(the dayshift arrive) \nDATA: Commander Riker, you are fifteen minutes early. \nRIKER: Well, it's a very special day. I thought the father of the bride\nwould enjoy being relieved early on the wedding day. \nDATA: Thank you, sir. \nRIKER: Nervous? \nDATA: I cannot become nervous, sir. However, I do sense a certain\nanticipation regarding my role in the wedding. \nRIKER: Anything to report? \nDATA: All systems normal, sir. Sickbay reports that Lieutenant Juarez\nwent into labour at zero four hundred hours. We remain at station\nawaiting the arrival of Starship Zhukov and guest quarters have been\nprepared for Ambassador T'Pel. \nRIKER: Very well. I have the Bridge. \nDATA: Aye, sir. \nRIKER: Begin day watch. \nDATA [OC]: Initially, Commander Maddox, I found it difficult to\nmaintain friendships, since human emotions are often puzzling to me.\n\n[Corridor]\n\nDATA [OC]: Eventually, I developed a programme\nenabling me to predict human emotional responses to specific actions.\n\n[Keiko's quarters]\n\nKEIKO: Come in. \nDATA: It is time for the wedding rehearsal. \nKEIKO: I know. Data, I've decided not to go through with it.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[82, 104, "PER"], [106, 126, "ORG"], [128, 146, "ORG"], [153, 169, "PER"], [173, 179, "LOC"], [552, 567, "PER"], [940, 947, "ORG"], [961, 978, "PER"], [1069, 1084, "SHIP"], [1127, 1143, "PER"], [1175, 1181, "LOC"], [1248, 1264, "PER"], [1491, 1498, "PER"], [1587, 1591, "PER"]]}
{"id": 356, "text": "[Quark's]\n\n(Quark is holding a disc containing something.) \nQUARK: I am merely a businessman. It would take an orator with the\nskills of the late, great Plegg himself, to sing the praises of the\nlate, great Plegg. What Ferengi could resist the honour of owning a\nsmall piece of the man that took a computer chip and turned it into the\nmodular holosuite industry. A small piece of the man that brought\nholographic entertainment to the most remote parts of this quadrant,\ncreating profit centres from societies that could barely afford to feed\ntheir own people. \nODO: How much are you asking? \nQUARK: As I was about to tell my good friend here, a mere three strips\nof latinum. And I'd be taking a loss at that price. \n(His putative customer leaves) \nQUARK: Okay, for you, two strips. Thank you very much. \nODO: Three strips? That's a fair price for Plegg. \nQUARK: I suppose you're interested. \nODO: Humanoid death rituals are an interest of mine. \nQUARK: Death rituals? \nODO: Everybody needs a hobby. Some species burn their dead, others pack\nthem in blocks of ice. Some even surround themselves with the company\nof family corpses. But the Ferengi ritual of chopping up their loved\nones and selling them? I find that irresistible. \nQUARK: I'm very busy here. \nODO: What a fitting and distinguished way to honour the memory of great\nFerengi entrepreneurs. I'm thinking of starting a collection, putting\nup a display case in my office. There'll be a special space in there\nreserved for you, Quark. \nQUARK: I'm sure. \n(Odo holds out three strips of latinum) \nQUARK: You're serious? \nODO: Have you ever known me not to be? \n(Quark fetches a disc of Plegg and reaches for the latinum) \nODO: There is one thing I was curious about. \nQUARK: And what's that \nODO: How do I know it's Plegg? \nQUARK: It says so on the label. \nODO: Isn't there some sort of letter of authenticity? \nQUARK: The Ferengi Seal of Dismemberment is right there. What more do\nyou want?", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 8, "LOC"], [12, 17, "PER"], [153, 158, "PER"], [207, 212, "PER"], [219, 226, "SPEC"], [460, 468, "LOC"], [847, 852, "PER"], [1138, 1145, "SPEC"], [1330, 1337, "SPEC"], [1487, 1492, "PER"], [1514, 1517, "PER"], [1619, 1624, "PER"], [1643, 1648, "PER"], [1773, 1778, "PER"], [1880, 1887, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 602, "text": "Captain's log, stardate 46192.3. We have arrived at Starbase one one\ntwo and are loading relief supplies destined for Tagra Four, an\necologically devastated planet in the Argolis Cluster. We have also\ntaken on a rather unusual passenger.\n\n[Ready room]\n\n PICARD: Welcome to the Enterprise, Miss Rogers.\nI'm delighted to have you aboard. \nAMANDA: (a beautiful young blonde woman) Thank you, sir. \nPICARD: And congratulations. I understand that you were selected for\nthis internship out of hundreds of applicants. \nAMANDA: Yes, sir. I still can't believe they chose me. There were lots\nof other people with better records. \nCRUSHER: Your transcript is very impressive. She's done honours work in\nneurobiology, plasma dynamics, and eco-regeneration. I'd say that's\npretty well rounded. \nAMANDA: That's a nice way of saying that I haven't decided what I'm\ngoing to do with my life. \nCRUSHER: I've arranged to have you work in all the major departments\nwhile you're here, and I'm willing to bet that by the time it's over\nyou'll have a pretty good idea what field you're interested in. \nPICARD: Or at least what fields you're not interested in. \n(doorbell) \nPICARD: Come. \nRIKER: We're bringing up the rest of the cargo now. We should be ready\nto leave within the hour. \nPICARD: Commander, will you escort Miss Rogers to her quarters? I need\nto discuss the Tagran's medical needs with Doctor Crusher. And Miss\nRogers? \nAMANDA: Yes? \nPICARD: You've won yourself a rare opportunity. Avail yourself of it. \nAMANDA: I will, sir. And thank you.\n\n[Corridor]\n\nRIKER: It'll take a few days before you know where\neverything is. If you need any help, you just use one of these comm.\npanels. \nAMANDA: We're on deck seven, section four. \nRIKER: You're right.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[52, 72, "LOC"], [118, 128, "LOC"], [171, 186, "LOC"], [277, 287, "SHIP"], [289, 300, "PER"], [240, 250, "LOC"], [1273, 1282, "PER"], [1300, 1311, "PER"], [1351, 1359, "SPEC"], [1379, 1393, "PER"], [1399, 1410, "PER"], [1693, 1717, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 354, "text": "Last\ntime on Star Trek Deep Space Nine \n BASHIR: I managed to save the Dax symbiont. There\nwas nothing I could do for Jadzia. \n(The Pah wraith leaving Dukat and the wormhole collapsing in on\nitself.) \nWEYOUN: Federation soldiers have landed on Cardassian soil and now\nyou're telling me the wormhole is gone and with it any chance of\ngetting reinforcements from the Gamma Quadrant. \nSISKO: The station's all yours, Major. Let's go home, Jake. \nMARTOK: I need a first officer for a dangerous mission. \nWORF: How dangerous? \nMARTOK: Dangerous enough to assure Jadzia a place in Sto-vo-kor. \nSISKO: I had a vision from the Prophets. I was on Tyree, in the desert,\nand I uncovered a face. The face of a woman. \nSISKO: You had a wife before Mum? \nJOSEPH: Sarah was your mother. \nKIRA: You're to begin an immediate evacuation. \nCRETAK: I'm afraid that's impossible. \nKIRA: Either you remove those weapons, or we will. \nEZRI: Hello, Benjamin. \nSISKO: Do I know you? \nEZRI: It's me. Dax. \nAnd now, the continuation.\n\n [Sisko's restaurant] \nSISKO: Dax? I can't believe it. \nEZRI: I can hardly believe it myself. But I'm Dax. I mean, I'm not\nJadzia Dax. I'm Ezri Dax. But I have all of Jadzia's memories. Not to\nmention Lela's, Tobin's, Emony's, Audrid's, Joran's, Curzon's. Am I\nforgetting anyone? \nSISKO: Torias. \nEZRI: Right. You're probably asking yourself who is this person? How\ndid she get the symbiont? Do I even want another Dax in my life? Does\nshe always talk this much? These are all very good questions and I wish\nI had good answers for you. \nSISKO: The answers can wait. Right now, I'm just glad to see you. \nEZRI: Really? That is so nice of you to say. I'm not usually this\nemotional. It must be the Emony in me. At least I think it's Emony Hi,\nJake.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[118, 124, "PER"], [151, 156, "PER"], [132, 142, "SPEC"], [71, 74, "PER"], [244, 254, "SPEC"], [365, 379, "LOC"], [414, 419, "PER"], [436, 440, "PER"], [557, 563, "PER"], [575, 585, "LOC"], [638, 643, "LOC"], [652, 658, "LOC"], [735, 738, "PER"], [749, 754, "PER"], [925, 933, "PER"], [974, 977, "PER"], [1010, 1028, "LOC"], [1038, 1041, "PER"], [1110, 1113, "PER"], [1131, 1141, "PER"], [1147, 1155, "PER"], [1175, 1181, "PER"], [1209, 1213, "PER"], [1217, 1222, "PER"], [1226, 1231, "PER"], [1235, 1241, "PER"], [1245, 1250, "PER"], [1254, 1260, "PER"], [1296, 1302, "PER"], [1423, 1426, "PER"], [1704, 1709, "PER"], [1739, 1744, "PER"], [1749, 1753, "PER"]]}
{"id": 815, "text": "Commander's log, stardate 48481.2. My senior staff and I have been\nasked to address the annual Starfleet symposium on the current\nsituation in the Gamma Quadrant. I'm looking forward to the opportunity\nand to visiting my sister in Portland.\n\n [Bridge]\n\nDAX: Entering Earth orbit. \nSISKO: Now there's something I never get tired of looking at. \nDAX: If you ask me, the seas could be a little more purple. \nKIRA: That's funny, I was just thinking they weren't green enough. \nBASHIR: I guess it's true what they say. There is no place like home.\nNo matter what colour the water is. \nDAX: We'd better get ready, Benjamin. Dinner tonight with Admiral\nDrazman. \nO'BRIEN: Not Droner Drazman? The commander of the Proxima maintenance\nyards? \nBASHIR: You're more than welcome to come along. The entire senior staff\nwas invited. \nO'BRIEN: Full dress uniform, fine table linens, a different fork for\nevery course? Thanks but no thanks. That's why I stayed an enlisted\nman. They don't expect me to show up for these formal dinners. \nDAX: Major, Constable, would you care to join us? \nKIRA: No, thank you. \nODO: I'd say this is strictly a Starfleet occasion. \nO'BRIEN: Commander, I'm receiving an incoming emergency message. It's\nfrom DS Nine. \nSISKO: On screen. \nQUARK [on viewscreen: Commander, am I glad to see you. \nKIRA: This better be good, Quark. You're on an emergency channel. \nQUARK [on viewscreen: I just received a message from the Grand Nagus.\nHe wanted me to remind you of the critical role he played in\nestablishing contact with the Dominion. \nSISKO: You can assure the Nagus I will mention his assistance\nprominently in my report to Starfleet. \nQUARK [on viewscreen: There is one more thing, Commander. It seems the\nNagus's nephew Belongo is currently being held by Starfleet authorities\non\nAldebaran Three. A slight misunderstanding, I'm sure.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[95, 104, "ORG"], [147, 161, "LOC"], [231, 239, "LOC"], [244, 250, "LOC"], [267, 272, "LOC"], [608, 616, "PER"], [638, 653, "PER"], [669, 683, "PER"], [706, 713, "LOC"], [1026, 1031, "PER"], [1033, 1042, "PER"], [1126, 1135, "ORG"], [1156, 1165, "PER"], [1222, 1229, "LOC"], [1334, 1339, "PER"], [1273, 1282, "PER"], [1431, 1442, "PER"], [1535, 1543, "GPE"], [1572, 1577, "PER"], [1636, 1645, "ORG"], [1695, 1704, "PER"], [1719, 1724, "PER"], [1734, 1741, "PER"], [1769, 1778, "ORG"], [1794, 1809, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 607, "text": "[Quark's]\n\n(Leeta serving is behind the bar when Quark enters\nwith Bajoran Security, carrying boxes.) \nQUARK: Just set them on the bar. Morn, no touching. You know what this\nis? Three cases of syrup of squill. \nLEETA: I love syrup of squill on my groatcakes, but I haven't seen a\njar in over a year. \nQUARK: No one has. \nODO: Does that mean the drought on Balancar is over? \nQUARK: There never was a drought on Balancar. It was all a ploy by\ntheir Agricultural Consortium. They've been stockpiling squill so they\ncould drive the price up. \nLEETA: That's dishonest. \nQUARK: I couldn't agree more. You see, I once did business with the\nnephew of the cousin of the stepsister of a friend of the secretary to\nthe Consortium's chief accountant. Nephew, cousin, stepsister, friend.\nYeah, that's right. And he told me, in passing, that the accountant had\nbought himself a very nice pair of Ferengi rain slippers. \nODO: And if there was a drought, he wouldn't need rain slippers. \nQUARK: My thoughts exactly. So I set up a meeting with this accountant\nand I told him that he either provide me with a shipment of syrup, or I\nwould expose their deception to the entire quadrant. Tomorrow morning,\nwe are having a special on groatcakes, topped with syrup of squill.\nThat is, for everyone who can afford it. What are you standing around\nfor? Get these crates in the storeroom. This stuff is worth its weight\nin latinum. Which reminds me of another little economic episode of\nmine. It happened, say, oh, eleven or twelve years ago, shortly before\nI came on the station \n(Dax, O'Brien and Bashir enter) \nLEETA: Dax, Julian! You're back! I was so worried. \nDAX: I told you we'd be okay. \nLEETA: Then why all the secrecy about your mission? \nO'BRIEN: We weren't supposed to talk about it. \nBASHIR: But now it's okay. The mission's over, we've been debriefed. We\ntook the Defiant behind enemy lines. \nO'BRIEN: We're the first reconnaissance mission into Cardassian space\nsince the Dominion's retreat. The first one to make it back, anyway. \nDAX: And if that isn't reason to celebrate, I don't know what is. \nO'BRIEN: Three synthales.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 8, "PER"], [12, 17, "PER"], [49, 54, "PER"], [67, 83, "ORG"], [136, 140, "PER"], [356, 364, "LOC"], [411, 419, "LOC"], [448, 471, "ORG"], [709, 721, "ORG"], [883, 890, "SPEC"], [1558, 1561, "PER"], [1563, 1570, "PER"], [1575, 1581, "PER"], [1597, 1600, "PER"], [1602, 1608, "PER"], [1855, 1862, "SHIP"], [1937, 1947, "SPEC"], [1964, 1974, "GPE"]]}
{"id": 796, "text": "[Glacier\nsurface] \n(Two figures beam onto an ice planet\nwearing thermal suits. They pick their way carefully across the uneven\nsnow-covered surface until the tricorder beeps.)KIM:\nWe're here! (We pull back to see the faint details of Voyager's hull beneath the ice.)KIM: The glacier fractures are stable. \nCHAKOTAY: We're clear to beam inside. \nTESSA [OC]: Acknowledged. \n [Frozen Corridor] \n KIM:\nNot exactly the way I remember it. (They scrape ice off a wall display and attach a power supply.)KIM: Power grid's been destroyed. Neural\ngel packs frozen solid. Decks nine through fourteen are now deck ten.\nThey've been compacted. \nCHAKOTAY: Looks like they hit the ice at full impulse. The EMH? \nKIM: I'm trying to access Sickbay. The relays aren't responding. I'm\nlosing the interface. Reset the power cell. Come on! \nCHAKOTAY: Let's get moving. Keep an open comm. link. \n [Frozen Bridge] \n(Some emergency lighting is still\nflickering. There are frozen bodies in the frost on the decks and in\nthe Jefferies tubes. Chakotay finds Janeway, but kneels next to Seven.)CHAKOTAY: Chakotay to Tessa. \n [Delta Flyer] \n TESSA:\nGo ahead. \nCHAKOTAY [OC]: I've found her. Lock on to the \n [Frozen Bridge] \n\nCHAKOTAY: Transporter relay and beam her to the lab. \nTESSA [OC]: Stand by. \nCHAKOTAY: Make it quick. This isn't exactly a happy reunion. \n [Delta Flyer] \n TESSA:\nI've got a lock. \n [Frozen Sickbay] \n(Kim coaxes the systems into life.)EMH:\nPlease state the nature of \nKIM: Long time no see. \nEMH: Ensign. \nKIM: I go by Harry now. It's a long story. Where's your mobile emitter?\n\nEMH: What's happened to the ship? The crew? \nKIM: No time. The emitter. \nEMH: It's in here, but", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[234, 241, "SHIP"], [723, 730, "LOC"], [1016, 1024, "PER"], [1031, 1038, "PER"], [1059, 1064, "PER"], [1076, 1084, "PER"], [1088, 1093, "PER"], [1098, 1109, "LOC"], [1338, 1349, "LOC"], [1387, 1394, "LOC"], [1187, 1193, "LOC"], [1398, 1401, "PER"], [1494, 1500, "PER"], [1516, 1521, "PER"]]}
{"id": 644, "text": "Captain's Log, Stardate 2947.3. We have been through a severe ion\nstorm. One crewman is dead. Ship's damage is considerable. I have\nordered a non-scheduled layover on Starbase Eleven for repairs. A full\nreport of damages was made to the commanding officer of Starbase\nEleven, Commodore Stone.\n\n[Stone's Office]\n\n(Kirk is not in his usual gold shirt, but a green\none with gold braiding.) \nSTONE: Maintenance Section Eighteen. The section is working on the\nIntrepid. Reschedule. The Enterprise is on priority one. That makes\nthree times you've read it, Jim. Is there an error? \nKIRK: No. But the death of the crewman. \nSTONE: Regulations, Captain. And the extract from your ship's computer\nlog confirming this sworn deposition? \nKIRK: Kirk to Enterprise. \nUHURA [OC]: Bridge here. Go ahead, Captain. \nKIRK: Where's Mister Spock with that computer log extract? \n[Bridge]\n\nUHURA: He should have been there ten minutes ago,\nsir. \n[Stone's Office]\n\nKIRK: Kirk out. \nSTONE: It's a great pity. The service can't afford to lose men like\nLieutenant Commander Finney. \nKIRK: I agree. I waited until the last possible moment. We were on Red\nAlert. The storm got worse. I had to jettison the pod. \n(The two man transporter alcove in the corner activates.) \nKIRK: What took you so long, Mister Spock? \nSPOCK: Captain, I believe I \nSTONE: I'll take that. \n(As he puts the data card into his computer, the door opens and a\nteenage girl dressed in blue enters.) \nKIRK: Jamie. \nJAMIE: There you are. I just wanted one more look at you. The man who\nkilled my father.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[167, 182, "LOC"], [259, 274, "LOC"], [276, 291, "PER"], [295, 302, "PER"], [313, 317, "PER"], [395, 423, "ORG"], [455, 463, "SHIP"], [481, 491, "SHIP"], [551, 554, "PER"], [637, 644, "PER"], [733, 737, "PER"], [741, 751, "SHIP"], [766, 772, "ORG"], [789, 796, "PER"], [813, 825, "PER"], [860, 866, "LOC"], [926, 933, "PER"], [949, 953, "PER"], [1028, 1055, "PER"], [1273, 1285, "PER"], [1295, 1302, "PER"], [1452, 1457, "PER"]]}
{"id": 411, "text": "Captain's log, stardate 47941.7. The Enterprise is en route to a\nbriefing on the situation in the Demilitarised Zone along the\nCardassian border. Meanwhile, we're celebrating the return of an old\nfriend.\n\n[Ten Forward]\n\nLAFORGE: Ro! \nCRUSHER: Welcome home. \nRO: Thanks. It's good to be back. \nTROI: Congratulations on your promotion, Lieutenant. \nRO: Same to you, Commander. \nTROI: Thank you. \nLAFORGE: Say, I understand that Advanced Tactical Training is a real\npicnic. \nRO: Right. \nCRUSHER: Did you see the buffet? \nTROI: This is real Bajoran foraiga. \nLAFORGE: It wasn't easy to find. \nRO: You shouldn't have gone to all this trouble. Really. \nCRUSHER: We wanted you to know how glad we are to have you back. \n(Picard leaves in the background) \nTROI: So, where are your new quarters? \nRO: Deck four, section eight. \nCRUSHER: What are do you planning to do \nPICARD [OC]: Lieutenant Ro. \nRO: Go ahead, sir. \nPICARD [OC]: Please report to the Bridge. \nRO: Yes, sir. Excuse me.\n\n[Corridor]\n\nRO: Captain. \nPICARD: You seemed a bit overwhelmed by all the attention. \nRO: Well, to tell you the truth, I really want to see everyone. I'd\njust rather do it one at a time. \nPICARD: You look very fit, Lieutenant. Tactical Training seems to agree\nwith you. \nRO: You know me, I enjoy a challenge.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[37, 47, "SHIP"], [98, 144, "LOC"], [206, 217, "LOC"], [229, 231, "PER"], [334, 344, "PER"], [364, 373, "PER"], [537, 544, "SPEC"], [714, 720, "PER"], [873, 886, "PER"], [792, 816, "LOC"], [943, 949, "LOC"], [994, 1001, "PER"], [1193, 1203, "PER"]]}
{"id": 581, "text": "[Ready room]\n\n(Janeway is looking out of a window when the doorbell chimes.)JANEWAY:\nCome in. \nTUVOK: You wished to see me. \nJANEWAY: We've known each other for how long?\nTUVOK: Approximately twenty years. \nJANEWAY: We've served on three starships together. I was present at\nyour daughter's Kohlinar. I consider you one of my closest friends.\nTUVOK: And I regard you with the same esteem. \nJANEWAY: I've always been honest with you, but you've been keeping\nsomething from me. \nTUVOK: I don't know what you mean. \nJANEWAY: Don't you? It took exhaustive research, sifting through\nteraquads of data, separating fact from rumour, but eventually I\narrived at the truth. \nTUVOK: Captain? (She activates the replicator, and turns around holding a blue-iced cake with a single lit candle.)\nJANEWAY: Happy birthday. \nTUVOK: Thank you. \nJANEWAY: So, it's not long before you hit the big three digits, huh? \nTUVOK: Indeed. Have you informed anyone else of your discovery? \nJANEWAY: Don't worry, Tuvok, my lips are sealed. Well? You're supposed\nto blow out the candle. \nTUVOK: That is not a Vulcan custom. \nJANEWAY: Humour me. \nCHAKOTAY [OC]: Captain to the bridge. \nJANEWAY: Well?  (Tuvok blows out the candle.)\nTUVOK: It was a fire hazard.(He puts the cake down.) \n[Bridge]\n\nCHAKOTAY:\nWe're receiving a distress call. A small vessel on an intercept course.\n\nJANEWAY: Lifesigns? \nKIM: One. It's Ocampan. \nTUVOK: We're being hailed. (A very old yet familiar woman appears on the viewscreen.)\nJANEWAY: Kes?\nKES [on viewscreen]: Captain Janeway, I need your help. Will you please\ngive me permission to come aboard? \nJANEWAY: Of course. What's happened? \nKES [on viewscreen]: Please, let me come aboard. (Transmission ends.)\nJANEWAY: Prepare the docking port. Tell the Doctor to stand by.\nTUVOK: Her ship is accelerating. It's on a collision course.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 11, "LOC"], [15, 22, "PER"], [673, 680, "PER"], [984, 989, "PER"], [1079, 1085, "SPEC"], [1131, 1138, "PER"], [1172, 1177, "PER"], [1146, 1152, "LOC"], [1256, 1262, "LOC"], [1384, 1391, "SPEC"], [1489, 1492, "PER"], [1515, 1530, "PER"], [1754, 1760, "PER"]]}
{"id": 495, "text": "[Varro ship - Tal's\ncabin] \n(In an enormous, long modular spaceship, Harry Kim is fraternising enthusiastically with a young woman.)KIM: We\nshouldn't be here. \nTAL: Don't worry. Nobody saw us leave. (She removes his comm, badge.(\nKIM: Hey, I need that. What if somebody tries to call? TAL: Shush. (A door opens and closes nearby.)KIM: What was that? \nTAL: Don't worry. Come here.(She rips off  his uniform jacket, pushes him down onto the bed and straddles him to kiss his chest.)\n\nCaptain's log, supplemental. After two weeks we're close to repairing the Varro's\nwarp drive. Then there's the Varro crew. I'm starting to think they'd\nrather give up warp travel than accept help from strangers.\n\n[Varro\nship - Central control]\n\nJIPPEQ:\nI thought we agreed Central Control would be off limits. (He is a middle-aged male. Janeway has been getting her hands dirty, and wipes them on a cloth.)\nJANEWAY: We did, but I need to access your warp assembly. \nJIPPEQ: That technology's classified. \nJANEWAY: We have to reconfigure the assembly if we're going to finish\nthis job. \nJIPPEQ: Then consider it finished. \nJANEWAY: We've come this far. \nJIPPEQ: You've turned our ship upside down for two weeks, and I've yet to\nsee any results.\nJANEWAY: You might check the antimatter injectors. \nJIPPEQ: Back online. \nJANEWAY: All you need now is a jolt of antimatter from Voyager's\nengines and you'll be back in business, but I need access to your warp\nassembly. You know, I can understand why you're distrustful of other\nspecies. Frankly, we've had a rough time in the Delta Quadrant\nourselves. But our two species have made remarkable progress working\ntogether to repair your engines. We've come a long way since you\nignored our opening hails. Let's not throw all that away. \nJIPPEQ: I'll admit we do share some things in common. \nJANEWAY: We're both on long journeys, looking for allies. In many ways,\nwe're like cousins. \nJIPPEQ: Cousins? \nJANEWAY: Well, distant cousins. Think about it. Four hundred years ago\nyou started out the same way we did, a single starship, a small crew,\nfacing the unknown. And now, centuries later, you've grown into a\ngenerational ship with a history and culture all your own. When I look", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 12, "LOC"], [14, 25, "LOC"], [69, 78, "PER"], [556, 563, "SHIP"], [593, 598, "SHIP"], [696, 706, "LOC"], [709, 724, "LOC"], [755, 770, "LOC"], [819, 826, "PER"], [1355, 1364, "SHIP"], [1553, 1567, "PER"]]}
{"id": 333, "text": "[Corridor]\n\n NEELIX:\nOh Captain, do you have a minute? \nJANEWAY: Just about a minute. I'm on my way to the shuttlebay. \nNEELIX: I thought last night went well, didn't you? \nJANEWAY: Extremely well. Everyone had a lot of fun. \nNEELIX: I was thinking of making it a regular feature, say once a\nmonth? \nJANEWAY: It's certainly worth a try. \nNEELIX: And Captain, you were especially good last night. \nJANEWAY: Thanks, Neelix. It's been a while. \nNEELIX: You'd never know. Now, Captain, I, do you think, I mean, I, I,\nI was wondering if \nJANEWAY: What is it, Neelix? \nNEELIX: Could you possibly keep Mister Tuvok busy on the bridge that\nevening? \nJANEWAY: I'm sure something could be arranged. Our secret, Neelix. \nNEELIX: We never had this discussion. \n [Shuttlecraft\nSacajawea] \n\n(Heading towards a brown planet.) \nCHAKOTAY: Harry's clarinet solo was okay. I could have done without\nTuvok's reading of Vulcan poetry. But the highlight of the evening was\ndefinitely Kathryn Janeway portraying the Dying Swan. \nJANEWAY: I learned that dance when I was six years old. I assure you,\nit was the hit of the Beginning Ballet class. \nCHAKOTAY: I don't doubt it. If Neelix has another talent night I hope\nyou reprise it. \nJANEWAY: Oh, no. Not until certain other people take their turn. The\nship's First Officer for instance. \nCHAKOTAY: Me? Get up in front of people and perform? I don't think so. \nJANEWAY: Come on, Chakotay, there must be some talent you have that\npeople would enjoy. Maybe I could stand with an apple on my head and\nyou could phaser it off. \nCHAKOTAY: Sounds great. If I miss I get to be Captain. Atmospheric\nturbulence. We might be in for a rough landing. \nJANEWAY: Funny, a minute ago there wasn't any indication of rough\nweather. \nCHAKOTAY: I'm reading even more severe storms near the surface. \nJANEWAY: Ion lightning. Maybe we'd better try the fifth planet instead\nand come back here when things have cleared up.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 9, "LOC"], [24, 31, "PER"], [107, 117, "LOC"], [350, 357, "PER"], [414, 420, "PER"], [554, 560, "PER"], [473, 480, "PER"], [595, 607, "PER"], [620, 626, "LOC"], [701, 707, "PER"], [751, 773, "SHIP"], [796, 808, "LOC"], [822, 827, "PER"], [880, 885, "PER"], [899, 905, "SPEC"], [962, 977, "PER"], [993, 1003, "PER"], [1154, 1160, "PER"], [1286, 1299, "PER"], [1405, 1413, "PER"], [1596, 1603, "PER"]]}
{"id": 348, "text": "On Stardate 43997, Captain Jean-Luc Picard of the Federation Starship\nEnterprise was kidnapped for six days by an invading force known as the\nBorg. Surgically altered, he was forced to lead an assault on Starfleet\nat Wolf 359.\n\n[Saratoga - Bridge]\n\nLOCUTUS [on viewscreen]: Resistance is futile. You\nwill disarm your weapons and escort us to sector zero zero one. If you\nattempt to intervene, we will destroy you. \nCAPTAIN: (a Vulcan) Red alert. Load all torpedo bays. Ready phasers.\nMove us to position alpha, Ensign. \n(The space battle begins) \nOPS OFFICER: (woman) They've locked on. \nSISKO: Reroute auxiliary power. \nOPS OFFICER: Our shields are being drained. Sixty four percent. Forty\ntwo. \nCAPTAIN: Recalibrate shield nutation. \nTACTICAL: (Bolian) Modulation is having no effect. \nOPS OFFICER: Shields have failed. \nSISKO: Full reverse. \nCAPTAIN: Maintain all Argh! \n(Everything goes BOOM) \nSISKO: Damage report. Damage report! \nCOMPUTER: Warning. Damage to warp core. Containment failure in five\nminutes. \nTACTICAL: Direct hit decks one through four. \nSISKO: Let's get the civilians to the escape pods, Lieutenant. \nTACTICAL: Aye, sir. \n[Corridor]\n\nSISKO: Leave everything. Get to your assigned\nevacuation area now. \nCOMPUTER: Warning. Damage to warp core. Containment failure in four\nminutes. \n(They come to a woman) \nSISKO: Doran. \nTACTICAL: I'll take care of her. You go on. \nSISKO: Have you seen Jennifer? \n[Sisko's quarters]", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[19, 42, "PER"], [50, 60, "GPE"], [70, 80, "SHIP"], [142, 146, "SPEC"], [204, 213, "ORG"], [217, 225, "LOC"], [229, 246, "LOC"], [342, 362, "LOC"], [427, 433, "SPEC"], [495, 509, "LOC"], [511, 517, "PER"], [1035, 1057, "LOC"], [1098, 1109, "SHIP"], [1111, 1121, "PER"], [1146, 1154, "LOC"], [1203, 1218, "LOC"], [1334, 1339, "PER"], [1408, 1416, "PER"], [1420, 1436, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 384, "text": "[Infirmary]\n\n(Odo enters, walking very carefully, and groaning.)\n\nBASHIR: Good morning, Constable. And what can I do for you today? \nODO: It's my back. \nBASHIR: Let's take a look. \nODO: It happened this morning when I got out of bed. \nBASHIR: Hmm. \n(It's painful to sit on the bed.) \nODO: I have Alvanian spine mites, don't I? \nBASHIR: Actually \nODO: I'll be in pain for the rest of my life. \nBASHIR: Odo, you have a pinched nerve. \nODO: Really? \nBASHIR: It comes from bad posture. \nODO: Me? Ridiculous. You've never seen anyone sit so straight. \nBASHIR: Exactly. You carry yourself too rigidly. \nODO: This is how I've always carried myself. \nBASHIR: You haven't always have a spinal column. You're not a\nchangeling anymore. Now that you're a humanoid, you have to learn to\nrelax. \nODO: That's what you said last week. \nBASHIR: And? \nODO: And it helped. That and the prune juice. \nBASHIR: There, you see? I know what I'm talking about. \n(Bashir gives Odo a hypo in the lower back.) \nQUARK: Back trouble? \nODO: It's none of your concern, Quark. \nQUARK: Bad posture. \nODO: Will you get out of here. \nBASHIR: What you need is a stretching regimen. Worf's morning exercise\nclass should be just the thing. \nQUARK: Forget that. I've got a holosuite programme that'll take care of\nhim. Three Orion slave girls strap you \nODO: Quark. \nQUARK: Go ahead, suffer. \nODO: What do you want? \nQUARK: A Yridian I've been dealing with sold me something that might\ninterest you. \nODO: I don't think so.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 10, "LOC"], [14, 17, "PER"], [88, 97, "PER"], [296, 316, "SPEC"], [401, 404, "PER"], [938, 944, "PER"], [951, 954, "PER"], [1037, 1042, "PER"], [1145, 1149, "PER"], [1285, 1290, "SPEC"], [1319, 1324, "PER"], [1386, 1393, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 847, "text": "Captain's log, Star date 1312.4. The impossible has happened. From\ndirectly ahead, we're picking up a recorded distress signal, the call\nletters of a vessel which has been missing for over two centuries. Did\nanother Earth ship once probe out of the galaxy as we intend to do?\nWhat happened to it out there? Is this some warning they've left\nbehind?\n\n[Briefing room]\n\nSPOCK: Your move, Captain. \nKIRK: We should have intercepted by now. The Bridge said they'd call. \nSPOCK: I'll have you checkmated your next move. \nKIRK: Have I ever mentioned you play a very irritating game of chess,\nMister Spock? \nSPOCK: Irritating? Ah, yes. One of your Earth emotions. \nKIRK: Certain you don't know what irritation is? \nSPOCK: The fact one of my ancestors married a human female \nKIRK: Terrible having bad blood like that. \nKELSO [on monitor] Bridge to briefing lounge. Object is now within\ntractor beam range. \nKIRK: No visual contact, Mister Kelso? \nKELSO [on monitor]: No, sir. It's too small to be a vessel. It only\nreads about one metre in diameter. \nSPOCK: Not large enough even for a lifeboat. \nKELSO [on monitor] Small enough to bring it aboard, sir, if you want to\nrisk it. \nKIRK: Lock onto it, Mister Kelso.\n\n[Transporter room]\n\nSCOTT: Materialiser ready, sir. \nKIRK: Bring it aboard. Old-style ship recorder that could be ejected\nwhen something threatened the ship. \nSPOCK: More like destroyed the ship in this case. Look at it. Burnt,\npitted. \nKIRK: Let's hope its tapes are intact. We'll feed it through Mister\nSpock's computer. \nSCOTT: Yes, sir. It's begun transmitting, sir.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[216, 221, "LOC"], [351, 364, "LOC"], [440, 446, "LOC"], [385, 392, "PER"], [585, 597, "PER"], [640, 645, "LOC"], [924, 936, "PER"], [1191, 1203, "PER"], [1207, 1223, "LOC"], [1504, 1516, "PER"]]}
{"id": 613, "text": "Captain's log, stardate 46682.4. The Enterprise is docked at the\nRemmler Array, where it will undergo a routine procedure to eliminate\naccumulated baryon particles. In preparation for the sweep, we are\nevacuating the ship.\n\n[Corridor]\n\nCREWWOMAN [OC]: Attention personnel on decks\nfourteen and fifteen. Your transporter\nroom assignment has been changed. Report to transporter room three. \nTROI: Captain. We're still behind schedule on decks seven and eight.\nShall I tell Arkaria Base there'll be a delay? \nPICARD: No. Open up the transporters in Cargo bay two and divert\neveryone from deck seven to there. That should put it back on track. \nTROI: Right. \nCREWMAN [OC]: All beta shift Engineering personnel are requested to\nreport to main Engineering prior to disembarking. \nCRUSHER: Captain. Arkaria Base does not have the medical storage units\nI have requested. I have seven living tissue samples that won't survive\nthe baryon sweep anymore than you or I would. I've tried to reason with\nthem, but \nPICARD: All right, all right. Have Commander LaForge transport a stasis\nunit from the astrophysics lab. You should be able to convert it to\nstore tissue samples. \nCRUSHER: Thank you, Captain. \nCREWWOMAN [OC]: All science personnel. Please check in with your\nsection chief for station-side duty assignments. \nRIKER: Captain. (comes out of turbolift) I was just heading for deck\nseven. I've put the auto-shutdown sequence on hold until we get back on\nschedule. \nPICARD: Oh, I think we can resume the sequence. Counsellor Troi is\ntaking care of the situation on deck seven. \nRIKER: Aye, sir.\n\n[Turbolift]\n\nDATA: Captain. \nPICARD: Bridge. \nDATA: It has been quite a day, has it not? \nPICARD: Yes, it has.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[37, 47, "SHIP"], [65, 78, "LOC"], [395, 402, "PER"], [471, 483, "LOC"], [546, 559, "LOC"], [684, 695, "ORG"], [738, 749, "LOC"], [783, 790, "PER"], [792, 804, "LOC"], [1035, 1052, "PER"], [1183, 1190, "PER"], [1315, 1322, "PER"], [1372, 1382, "LOC"], [1508, 1523, "PER"], [1609, 1616, "PER"], [1627, 1633, "ORG"], [1591, 1600, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 553, "text": "[Sisko's\nquarters]\n\n(Sisko is sitting on his couch, looking straight at\nus.) \nSISKO: Captain's personal log, stardate five one seven, er, five one\nseven four? Computer, what day is it? \nCOMPUTER: Stardate 51721.3. \nSISKO: It's only been two weeks. I need to talk about this. I have to\njustify what's\nhappened, what I've done, at least to myself. I can't talk to anyone\nelse. Not even to Dax. Maybe if I just lay it all out in my log, it'll\nfinally make sense. I can see where it all went wrong. Where I went\nwrong. I suppose it started two weeks ago, \n [Wardroom]\n\nSISKO [OC]: While I was posting the weekly casualty\nlist in the wardroom. Every Friday morning for the past three months,\nI've posted the official list of Starfleet personnel killed, wounded or\nmissing in the war. \n(Everyone looks for names they know. Don't look too closely, names are\nrepeated. Captain Margaret Clark is there six times.) \nSISKO [OC]: It's become something of a grim ritual around here. Not a\nweek goes by that someone doesn't find the name of a loved one, a\nfriend or an acquaintance on that damned list. \n(Dax finds a name.) \nSISKO [OC]: I've grown to hate Fridays. \nSISKO: Who is it, Dax? \nDAX: Leslie Wong. \nSISKO: The skipper of the Cairo? \nDAX: She was an instructor at the Academy when I was a sophomore. \nBASHIR: Do you know what happened to the Cairo? \nSISKO: Just that she disappeared on patrol in the Romulan neutral zone.\nI'll look into it. \nDAX: Don't bother. I'm sure it's the same old story. The Jem'Hadar\ncrossed the Romulan border and caught them by surprise. It's only about\nthe hundredth time it's happened. \nBASHIR: I can't believe the Romulans allow them to violate their\nterritory so brazenly. Why do they get away with it? \nSISKO: The Romulans have a treaty of non-aggression and friendship with", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 17, "LOC"], [21, 26, "PER"], [387, 390, "PER"], [554, 562, "LOC"], [720, 729, "ORG"], [861, 883, "PER"], [1091, 1094, "PER"], [1170, 1173, "PER"], [1181, 1192, "PER"], [1221, 1226, "SHIP"], [1263, 1270, "ORG"], [1337, 1342, "SHIP"], [1395, 1415, "LOC"], [1494, 1503, "SPEC"], [1516, 1523, "SPEC"], [1639, 1647, "SPEC"], [1741, 1749, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 576, "text": "[Suder's quarters]\n\n(Suder\nis the sociopath who killed Crewman Darwin because he didn't like the\nway he looked at him. See\n Meld for more\ndetails. He shows Tuvok a seedling in a container.) \nSUDER: Look. And you said they were incompatible. \nTUVOK: You have confirmed the genetic structure? \nSUDER: An entirely new species. I'm going to name it after you. The\nTuvok Orchid. \nTUVOK: That is an honour you should reserve for yourself, Mister Suder.\nYou gave this species life. \nSUDER: And you gave me life. All of this is because of you. Because of\nthe meld. \nTUVOK: The meld may have introduced you to my interest in floriculture,\nbut you have embraced it entirely on your own, and discovered a unique\ntalent within yourself in the process. \nSUDER: I used to think the only talent I had was a talent for killing.\nPlease. It's my way of saying thank you.\nTUVOK: Very well. I accept. \nSUDER: Tuvok, I want to do something for the ship. I'm not asking you\nto let me out of confinement. I accept my punishment. But if I could\njust, just contribute somehow. \nTUVOK: What contribution do you feel you could make from your quarters?\n\nSUDER: I was, I was thinking I might adapt some of the genetic\nengineering techniques I've developed for the orchids to make the\nairponic vegetable garden more productive. \nTUVOK: Your attitude is admirable. I will discuss it with the Captain. \nSUDER: Do you think she'll agree? \nTUVOK: We'll see. Now, shall we begin? Notice your mind working, how it\nplans for the future, visits the past. Notice those thoughts and set\nthem aside. Turn your attention to the white light that is your breath.\n\n[Bridge]\n\nKIM:\nCaptain, we're being hailed on a subspace frequency. \nJANEWAY: Are there ships in the vicinity? \nPARIS: Negative. Tracking the source. Seems like it's coming from an\nunmanned buoy, coordinates one four zero mark three one seven.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 8, "PER"], [21, 26, "PER"], [55, 69, "PER"], [156, 161, "PER"], [360, 365, "PER"], [433, 445, "PER"], [889, 894, "PER"], [1361, 1368, "PER"], [1621, 1627, "LOC"], [1635, 1642, "PER"]]}
{"id": 735, "text": "Captain's log, stardate 41636.9. As feared, our examination of the\nseven year overdue Federation freighter, Odin, disabled by an asteroid\ncollision, revealed no survivors. However, three escape pods were\nmissing, suggesting the possibility of survivors.\n\n[Bridge]\n\nLAFORGE: Ready to begin orbit of Angel One,\nCaptain. \nPICARD: Make it so, Mister La Forge. What kind of place is this, Data? \nDATA: Angel One is a class M planet, sir, supporting carbon based flora\nand fauna, sparsely populated with intelligent life forms. It is\nsimilar in technological development to mid-twentieth century Earth. \nLAFORGE: Kind of like being marooned at home. \nRIKER: Assuming any of the survivors made it this far. Admittedly, it\n'is the closest planet to the\nOdin, but to travel distance we did in two days at warp one would have\ntaken the Odin escape pod five months. \nDATA: Five months, fourteen days, eleven hours, two minutes \nRIKER: Thank you, Data. \nDATA: And fifty seven seconds. \nTASHA: Captain, we're receiving an audio signal from Angel One. \nPICARD: Starfleet are adamant that we maintain excellent diplomatic\nrelations with this planet. Mister Data, is there any other pertinent\ninformation before we reply? \nDATA: Angel One has evolved into a constitutional oligarchy. It is\ngoverned by a parliamentary body consisting of six elected Mistresses,\nand headed by a female they refer to as The Elected One.\nTROI: It sounds like my own planet. \nWORF: Klingons appreciate strong women. \nPICARD: How current is this information, Mister Data? \nDATA: A Federation vessel last visited this planet sixty two years ago,\nCaptain. \nPICARD: Counsellor, as this is a female dominated society, you might\nwish to make the initial contact. \nTROI: Thank you, sir. \nPICARD: Open hailing frequencies. \nTASHA: Hailing frequencies open, sir. \nTROI: This is Counsellor Deanna Troi from the USS Enterprise. \nBEATA: [OC]: I am Beata, The Elected One. How may we assist you,\nCounsellor?", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[108, 112, "SHIP"], [256, 262, "LOC"], [298, 307, "LOC"], [309, 316, "PER"], [339, 354, "PER"], [384, 388, "PER"], [397, 406, "LOC"], [745, 749, "SHIP"], [826, 830, "SHIP"], [935, 939, "PER"], [981, 988, "PER"], [1027, 1036, "LOC"], [1047, 1056, "ORG"], [1135, 1146, "PER"], [1213, 1222, "GPE"], [1445, 1453, "SPEC"], [1521, 1532, "PER"], [1607, 1614, "PER"], [1625, 1635, "PER"], [1832, 1854, "PER"], [1864, 1878, "SHIP"], [1946, 1956, "PER"], [1899, 1921, "PER"]]}
{"id": 842, "text": "[Bridge]\n\n SULU: The reading's growing stronger, Captain.\nComing from a star system directly ahead. \nUHURA: It's not a signal, sir. It does not seem to even exist, and yet\nit's affecting all my channels. \nKIRK: Well? \nSPOCK: Someone or something is attempting to attract our attention. \nKIRK: Someone or something has succeeded. Our distress signal relays\nhave been activated. We've been given a direction to follow, but how?\nWhat's causing it? \nSPOCK: I do not know. Not even a Vulcan can know the unknown, Captain.\nWe are hundreds of light years past where any Earth ship has ever\nexplored. \nSULU: Planet dead ahead, Captain. Becoming visual. \n(There's a yellow and gold planet on the viewscreen.) \nSPOCK: Class M planet, Captain. \nKIRK: Close to Earth conditions. \nSPOCK: With two very important exceptions. It's much older than Earth,\nand about a half million years ago, its atmosphere was totally ripped\naway by some sort of cataclysm. The planet has evidently been dead\nsince then. Sensors detect no life of any kind. \nSARGON [OC]: All of your questions will be answered in time, Captain\nKirk. \nKIRK; Are your hailing frequencies open? \nUHURA: No, sir. \nSARGON [OC]: I am Sargon. It is the energy of my thoughts which has\ntouched your instruments and directed you here. Now with this closer\ndistance I can speak to you at last. \nKIRK: Who are you, Sargon? \nSARGON [OC]: Please assume a standard orbit about our planet, Captain. \nKIRK: Is that a request or demand? \nSARGON [OC]: The choice is yours. I read what is in your mind. Words\nare unnecessary. \nKIRK: The planet is dead. There's no possibility of life there as we\nunderstand life. \nSARGON [OC]: And I am as dead as my planet. Does that frighten you,\nJames Kirk? For if it does, if you let what is left of me perish, then\nall of you, my children, all of mankind must perish, too.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 7, "LOC"], [49, 56, "PER"], [479, 485, "SPEC"], [508, 515, "PER"], [563, 568, "LOC"], [619, 626, "PER"], [724, 731, "PER"], [749, 754, "LOC"], [1086, 1098, "PER"], [1178, 1184, "PER"], [1354, 1360, "PER"], [1425, 1432, "PER"], [1713, 1723, "PER"]]}
{"id": 565, "text": "Captain's Log, stardate 5029.5. Responding to a distress call from our\nscientific colony on Triacus. We are beaming down to investigate.\n\n[Planet surface]\n\n(On the ground, beneath a purple sky, adults are\nlying motionless. Kirk, McCoy and Spock investigate. One man gets up\nfrom behind a rock.) \nKIRK: Professor Starnes? (the man has a phaser, and looks terrified.)\nIt's Kirk. \n(The man collapses without speaking.) \nMCCOY: He's dead, Captain. \nKIRK: He didn't seem to know me. \n(Kirk takes the dead man's tricorder, then goes over to a woman and\nremoves a vial from her mouth.) \nMCCOY: Cyalodin. \nKIRK: Self-inflicted. \n(Kirk replays the tricorder.) \nSTARNES [OC]: Must destroy ourselves! Alien upon us. The enemy from\nwithin. The enemy! \nKIRK: All this. Self-inflicted. Mass suicide. \n(The sound of children playing, then the kids run into the scene.\nThere's a girl, three small boys and one older boy.) \nMARY: You missed me. \nSTEVE: I did not. \nTOMMY: Hi. Who are you? \nKIRK: Kirk of the starship Enterprise. \nTOMMY: I'm Tommy Starnes. This is Mary, Steve, Ray, and Don. \nMARY: Come on. Play with us. Come on. (They make a circle and dance\naround Kirk.) Ring around the rosy,\npocket full of posy. Ashes, ashes, we all fall down! Ring around the\nrosy, pocket full of posy. Ashes, ashes, we all fall down! \nCaptain's log, supplementary. We have buried the\nmembers of the Starnes exploration party. Everyone has been deeply\naffected by what has happened here, with some important exceptions.\n\n[Planet surface]\n\n(Grave markers with just surnames stand behind one", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[92, 99, "LOC"], [223, 227, "PER"], [229, 234, "PER"], [239, 244, "PER"], [302, 319, "PER"], [371, 375, "PER"], [435, 442, "PER"], [480, 484, "PER"], [622, 626, "PER"], [979, 983, "PER"], [1000, 1010, "SHIP"], [1024, 1037, "PER"], [1047, 1051, "PER"], [1053, 1058, "PER"], [1060, 1063, "PER"], [1069, 1072, "PER"], [1150, 1154, "PER"]]}
{"id": 408, "text": "Captain's log, stardate 4307.1. Approaching Starbase Six for a much\nneeded period of rest and recreation. \n[Bridge]\n\nKIRK: The crew has performed excellently, but is\nexhausted. And I, too, am looking forward to a nice period of rest on\nsome lovely planet. \nUHURA: Captain. There was a message from Starbase Six. Heavy\ninterference. All I get is Intrepid and what sounded like a sector\nco-ordinate. \nSPOCK: Interesting. No indications of magnetic storms in this sector. \nKIRK: Try another channel, Lieutenant. \nUHURA: Aye, sir. \nMCCOY: The Intrepid is manned by Vulcans, isn't it? \nKIRK: Yes, that's right, Bones. \nUHURA: Enterprise calling Starbase Six. Enterprise calling Starbase\nSix. Come in. Come in. \n(Spock suddenly jerks upright, his face a picture of horror.) \nKIRK: Spock? \nMCCOY: What is it, Spock? Are you in pain? \nSPOCK: Captain, the Intrepid. It just died. And the four hundred\nVulcans aboard, all dead. \nMCCOY: Come on, Spock, let's go down to Sickbay. \nSPOCK: Doctor, I know what I know. \nKIRK: Get to the Sickbay. \nSPOCK: Captain. \nKIRK: No, no, no. That's an order. \nSPOCK: Yes, sir. \n(McCoy leads him away.) \nUHURA: Captain, I have Starbase Six readable now. Switching to audio,\nsir. \nKIRK: Kirk here. Go ahead. \nSTARBASE [OC]: You will divert immediately to sector three nine J. \nKIRK: Sir, the Enterprise just completed an exhausting mission. We're\non our way in for R and R. There must be another starship in that\nsector. \nSTARBASE [OC]: Negative. This is a rescue priority. We've lost all\ncontact with solar system Gamma Seven-A, which the Intrepid was\ninvestigating. And we've just lost contact with the Intrepid. Report", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[44, 56, "LOC"], [108, 114, "LOC"], [264, 271, "PER"], [497, 507, "PER"], [345, 353, "SHIP"], [539, 547, "SHIP"], [561, 568, "SPEC"], [606, 611, "PER"], [621, 631, "SHIP"], [640, 652, "ORG"], [654, 664, "SHIP"], [673, 685, "ORG"], [298, 310, "ORG"], [707, 712, "PER"], [775, 780, "PER"], [802, 807, "PER"], [834, 841, "PER"], [847, 855, "SHIP"], [892, 899, "SPEC"], [935, 940, "PER"], [976, 982, "PER"], [959, 966, "LOC"], [1022, 1029, "LOC"], [1039, 1046, "PER"], [1104, 1109, "PER"], [1135, 1142, "PER"], [1210, 1214, "PER"], [1151, 1163, "ORG"], [1278, 1297, "LOC"], [1315, 1325, "SHIP"], [1538, 1551, "LOC"], [1563, 1571, "SHIP"], [1628, 1636, "SHIP"]]}
{"id": 353, "text": "[Quark's]\n\n(A buxom young Bajoran woman comes over to Bashir's\ntable.) \nLEETA: Excuse me. You're Doctor Bashir, aren't you? \nBASHIR: That's right. \nLEETA: I'm Leeta. I've been meaning to come by the Infirmary to see\nyou. (cough, cough.) \nBASHIR: Oh, dear. How long have you had that cough? \nLEETA: A few days now. \nBASHIR: May I? (puts his hand on her back) Cough for me. \n(Leeta forces a couple more fake coughs.) \nBASHIR: Hmm. \nLEETA: Is it serious, Doctor? \nBASHIR: No, but it's a good thing you came to me when you did. We need\nto start your treatment immediately. (to waiter) Bring me a Fanalian\ntoddy, very hot. Make that two. I'm feeling a bit of a cough coming on\nmyself. \nLEETA: I'm sorry to hear that, Doctor. \nBASHIR: No, please, call me \nDAX: Julian. \nBASHIR: Hi. \nDAX: I'm Jadzia. \nLEETA: Leeta \nBASHIR: Before I forget, here's the immunological data you asked for. \n(Bashir hands Dax a PADD which says Go Away.) \nDAX: How nice of you to put it together for me so quickly. I think I'll\ngo over it right now. Oh, by the way, I hear the Lexington's docking\nhere for a few days. \nBASHIR: The Lexington? \n(Dax leaves.) \nBASHIR: Excuse me for just one second. Stay there.\n\n [Promenade]\n\nBASHIR: Jadzia. Do you happen to know when the\nLexington is coming in? \nDAX: Three weeks. Don't you have a friend aboard? \nBASHIR: Do I? \nDAX: The medical officer. Elizabeth Lense? \nBASHIR: Elizabeth Lense. You know, I think she may have been in my\nclass at Starfleet Medical.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 8, "LOC"], [26, 33, "SPEC"], [54, 60, "PER"], [97, 110, "PER"], [159, 164, "PER"], [199, 208, "LOC"], [374, 379, "PER"], [452, 458, "PER"], [712, 718, "PER"], [755, 761, "PER"], [786, 792, "PER"], [802, 807, "PER"], [881, 887, "PER"], [894, 897, "PER"], [1048, 1057, "SHIP"], [1102, 1111, "SHIP"], [1115, 1118, "PER"], [1183, 1192, "LOC"], [1203, 1209, "PER"], [1242, 1251, "SHIP"], [1359, 1374, "PER"], [1385, 1400, "PER"], [1453, 1470, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 293, "text": "[Captain's\nmess] \n(Archer pours red wine into T'Pol's glass.) ARCHER: Say when. (At about one inch.) \nT'POL: When. \nARCHER: I didn't know you drank wine. \nT'POL: Under the circumstances I'll allow myself a small indulgence. \nTUCKER: Make mine a large indulgence. \nARCHER: To our Science Officer. It's been one year to the day since you\nofficially joined our crew. \nTUCKER: Here's to many more. \nT'POL: I appreciate the sentiment but I'm simply carrying out my\nassignment. \nARCHER: That's no small accomplishment considering the previous record\nfor a Vulcan serving on a human ship was two weeks. \nT'POL: Ten days. \nARCHER: I've been filling out your annual crew evaluation. Just a\nformality. \nT'POL: I understand. The High Command has requested my evaluation of\nyou. Just a formality. \nARCHER: There's something in your record I've been meaning to ask you\nabout. While you were stationed in Sausalito you took a five-day leave.\n\nT'POL: Yes? \nARCHER: You went to an old mining town in Pennsylvania, Carbon Creek?\nSeems like an odd place to take a vacation. \nT'POL: Vulcans don't take vacations. \nARCHER: Then, if I may ask, why'd you go there? \nT'POL: Is this part of my evaluation? \nARCHER: Just curious. \nT'POL: It was a personal matter. \nTUCKER: You had a personal matter in Carbon Creek, Pennsylvania? \nARCHER: Trip, if she doesn't want to tell us. \nTUCKER: Seems a little unfair. We tell her plenty of stories. \nT'POL: You'd like me to tell you a story? \nTUCKER: If it's a good one. \nT'POL: I went to Carbon Creek because I wanted to visit the site of\nFirst Contact between humans and Vulcans. \nARCHER: Then you were about three thousand kilometres off. That took\nplace in Montana. \nT'POL: Actually, it didn't. \nTUCKER: Every school kid knows that Zephram Cochrane met the Vulcans in\nBozeman, Montana, on April 5th, 2063. I've been there. There's a", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 15, "LOC"], [19, 25, "PER"], [279, 294, "PER"], [550, 556, "SPEC"], [718, 730, "ORG"], [891, 900, "LOC"], [984, 996, "LOC"], [998, 1010, "LOC"], [1064, 1071, "SPEC"], [1277, 1303, "LOC"], [1505, 1517, "LOC"], [1578, 1584, "SPEC"], [1589, 1596, "SPEC"], [1677, 1684, "LOC"], [1752, 1768, "PER"], [1777, 1784, "SPEC"], [1788, 1804, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 313, "text": "[Akritirian prison]\n\n(A\nklaxon sounds, attracting raggedy men from various cubby holes.) \nMAN [OC]: New man coming! \nMAN 2 [OC]: New prisoner. \nMAN [OC]: Get out of my way! \nMAN 2 [OC]: There is a new man coming. \nMAN 3 [OC]: Here he comes. \nMAN 2 [OC]: Hurry up. \nMAN [OC]: New prisoner! \nMAN 2 [OC]: Hey, something's coming. \n(An iris opens at the top of a chute and a person slides down, landing\nwith a thump. Laughter from the assembled men, who suggest taking his\nboots or killing him. A grizzled man pushes through the crowd.) \nPIT: Get out of my way. \n(He pulls Harry Kim, for it is he, to his feet. A fight starts, and Kim\nmanages to get in a few punches of his own before he is kicked to the\nground.) \nMAN: Kill him, kill him. \n(A fair haired man intervenes.) \nKIM: Tom. \n(Paris punches Kim in the stomach. He goes down.) \nPIT: Nobody touch him. He's mine. \n(Pit starts to drag Kim away by the foot.) \nKIM: Wait. This is a mistake. I don't belong here! \nPIT: You don't? Well, I'll just take you home then. All right? \nPARIS: This one's mine. \nPIT: I say he's not. \nPARIS: He's the reason that I'm here. He was my partner in a bombing.\nWe killed forty seven patrollers at Akritiri. Forty seven! And then\nthis scum confessed to the Tribunal and gave them my name. So I'm\ntelling you again, he's mine. \nPIT: I'm keeping him. \n(Paris gets a knife to Pit's throat.) \nPIT: Take him. For now.\n\n[Paris'\nhovel]\n\nKIM: Did\nyou have to hit me so hard? \nPARIS: Trust me. Around here, you don't want anybody thinking you're", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 18, "LOC"], [569, 578, "PER"], [627, 630, "PER"], [775, 778, "PER"], [782, 787, "PER"], [796, 799, "PER"], [868, 871, "PER"], [887, 890, "PER"], [1180, 1188, "LOC"], [1239, 1247, "ORG"], [1333, 1338, "PER"], [1355, 1358, "PER"], [1397, 1409, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 812, "text": "[Airlock]\n\nKIRA: Now remember, I want him treated like a\nvisiting head of state. Full communications and computer access, any\nassistance he may need from the station's crew. \nDAX: You should have told us know he was coming sooner. I think we have\na red carpet in storage somewhere. \nKIRA: Dax, this is important. Tekeny Ghemor led the dissident movement\nagainst Cardassia's Central Command. And now that Dukat and the\nDominion have taken over, there is no one better qualified to lead the\nopposition. \nDAX: Besides, he's practically your father. \nWORF: Your father? Ghemor is a Cardassian. \nKIRA: It's a long story. \nDAX: The Cardassians once kidnapped Kira and surgically altered her to\nlook like Ghemor's missing daughter. (link to Second Skin) \nKIRA: It was part of a plan to expose him as the leader of the\ndissident movement. \nWORF: Cardassian politics are very complex. \nDAX: I think they like it that way. \nKIRA: Ghemor may be the only hope left for Cardassia. He deserves our\nhelp. \n(Kira has her back to the airlock.) \nGHEMOR: That's a lot of faith to put in one man. \n(Kira spins round.) \nGHEMOR: I hope I won't prove too great a disappointment. \nKIRA: Legate Ghemor. It's good to see you. \nGHEMOR: How many times must I tell you, Nerys? If you won't call me\nfather, Tekeny will do. \nKIRA: Welcome to Deep Space Nine, Tekeny. This is our science officer,\nLieutenant Commander Jadzia Dax, and our strategic operations officer,\nLieutenant Commander Worf. \nGHEMOR: That's quite a reception for an old man. Ah, I see you're\nwearing the bracelet I gave you. \nKIRA: Not exactly permitted under the uniform code, but \nGHEMOR: It looks good on you. It was a pleasure meeting both of you,\nbut if you don't mind, I'm afraid the journey here was a little\ndraining. \nKIRA: Oh, I'll show you to your quarters. \n(Kira and Ghemor leave.)", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 8, "LOC"], [289, 292, "PER"], [313, 326, "PER"], [374, 389, "ORG"], [362, 371, "GPE"], [404, 409, "PER"], [418, 426, "GPE"], [566, 572, "PER"], [578, 588, "SPEC"], [626, 637, "SPEC"], [653, 657, "PER"], [698, 704, "PER"], [838, 848, "SPEC"], [920, 926, "PER"], [957, 966, "GPE"], [992, 996, "PER"], [1079, 1083, "PER"], [1163, 1176, "PER"], [1241, 1246, "PER"], [1277, 1283, "PER"], [1311, 1326, "LOC"], [1328, 1334, "PER"], [1365, 1396, "PER"], [1436, 1461, "PER"], [1809, 1813, "PER"], [1818, 1824, "PER"]]}
{"id": 653, "text": "[Bridge]\n\nSPOCK: On mark eight and closing. \nKIRK: Steady as she goes. Phaser crew, stand by. \n(There's a strange object on the viewscreen.) \nCHEKOV: Range, forty five thousand kilometres, Captain. \nSPOCK: Fascinating. \nCHEKOV: Range, forty three thousand kilometres and closing. \nKIRK: Sensor readings? \nSPOCK: A mechanical device of unknown properties. I read no life forms\naboard. \nKIRK: Analysis, Science Officer? \nSPOCK: Obviously, it intends to intercept us. It has made several\ncourse changes corresponding with our own. \nCHEKOV: Thirty eight thousand and closing. Thirty five thousand and\nclosing. \nSPOCK: Unclear whether it intends to attack or merely communicate with\nus. \nKIRK: Thank you, Science Officer. Come to one eight one mark seven. \nCHEKOV: Aye, aye, sir. \n(The object swings back into the centre of the viewscreen.) \nKIRK: It's staying with us. \nSPOCK: Indeed. \nKIRK: Full stop, Mister Chekov. Hold your position. \nCHEKOV: Aye, sir. \nMELKOT [OC]: Aliens, you have encroached on the space of the Melkot.\nYou will turn back immediately. This is the only warning you will\nreceive. \nSPOCK: Vulcan, Captain. \nKIRK: English. \nCHEKOV: It was Russian, sir. Every word. \nUHURA: No, Captain. It was Swahili. \nKIRK: Interesting. Telepathy. \nSPOCK: Unquestionably. Most impressive. \nKIRK: Our orders are very clear. We're to establish contact with the\nMelkotians at all costs. \nSPOCK: True telepaths can be most formidable, and we have been warned. \nKIRK: What previous contacts have been made with the Melkotians? \nSPOCK: No recorded contacts. If they ever ventured into space, they\nevidently withdrew immediately.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 7, "LOC"], [189, 196, "PER"], [401, 416, "PER"], [700, 715, "PER"], [899, 912, "PER"], [1015, 1021, "SPEC"], [1106, 1112, "SPEC"], [1114, 1121, "PER"], [1193, 1200, "PER"], [1360, 1370, "SPEC"], [1511, 1521, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 771, "text": "Captain's log, stardate\n50074.3. We have detected evidence that a wormhole recently appeared\nand then disappeared in a nearby solar system. We're on our way there\nto investigate.\n\n[Bridge]\n\n(At\nKim's station.) \nKIM: Based on the residual neutrino levels, I'd estimate it's been at\nleast six months since the wormhole's last appearance. \nCHAKOTAY: From the dispersal pattern of the interstellar plasma, it\nlooks like it isn't fixed. Seems to be travelling through space. \nJANEWAY: It may not be fixed on this end, nut if it's shown up in the\nsame location more than once, it's possible its exit point is constant,\nand it's wagging around the Delta Quadrant like the tail on a dog. \nPARIS: Approaching the last known co-ordinates of the wormhole,\nCaptain. \nJANEWAY: All stop. Mister Kim, initiate continuous neutrino scans. \nKIM: Aye, Captain. \nJANEWAY: Mister Tuvok, scan the planets in this system for life signs.\nMaybe there's someone around here who can give us some helpful\ninformation. \nTUVOK: I am picking up an M-class atmosphere on the second planet,\nhumanoid life signs. However, metallurgic analysis indicates a\npre-industrial civilisation, a Bronze Age level of technology. Curious,\nCaptain. \nJANEWAY: What is? \nTUVOK: I'm detecting evidence that these people have had contact with\nthe Alpha Quadrant. \nJANEWAY: What kind of evidence? \nTUVOK: It is a modulated energy discharge that appears to be consistent\nwith the recent use of a replicator. \nKIM: If they've got a replicator, it could mean the wormhole leads to\nthe Alpha Quadrant, and that someone's travelled through it. \nJANEWAY: I appreciate your enthusiasm, Ensign, but before we indulge in\ntoo much speculation, let's see if we can back up your assumptions with\nsome facts. Commander Chakotay, I want you and Lieutenant Paris to go\ndown that planet and have a look around. Launch a high resolution\nreconnaissance probe to gather information about the local population's\ndress and appearance. \nCHAKOTAY: Aye, Captain.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[181, 187, "LOC"], [194, 207, "LOC"], [641, 655, "LOC"], [745, 752, "PER"], [774, 784, "PER"], [833, 840, "PER"], [852, 864, "PER"], [1193, 1200, "PER"], [1296, 1310, "LOC"], [1530, 1544, "LOC"], [1627, 1633, "PER"], [1744, 1762, "PER"], [1779, 1795, "PER"], [1978, 1985, "PER"]]}
{"id": 343, "text": "[Moon surface]\n\n(A\nrock-strewn open area.) \nCHAKOTAY: Anything? \nTORRES: Not really. The polyferranide deposits are contaminated with\nastaline. \nTUVOK: Commander, there's something over here I think you should see. \nCHAKOTAY: (to Torres) Pack it up. We'll find better quality somewhere\ndown the line. \nTORRES: That line is going to be cut short when our nacelles burn\nthemselves up if we don't find it soon. \nCHAKOTAY: What have you got, Lieutenant? \nTUVOK: There have been other visitors to this moon recently. \nNEELIX: What do you think this is? Some kind of message? \n(Chakotay kneels by circle of stones with markings on the ground inside\nit. He traces the spiral and remembers - )\n\n[Memory\n- Central American jungle]\n\n(The\nsame spiral and lines carved into a piece of dead wood.) \nKOLOPAK: I don't want you to go wandering off. \nYOUNG CHAKOTAY: I'm not. I'm just looking at something. \nKOLOPAK: Antonio. \n(Kolopak speaks the local language to their one of their guides.\nAntonio replies in the same language.) \nKOLOPAK: He says you're quite a scout, a kep-o-ne. \nYOUNG CHAKOTAY: I was just looking at a lizard when I saw it. \nKOLOPAK: Well, it was your eyes that saw it. No one else's did. That's\nthe important thing. Come. I want you to understand this. It's a\nblessing to the land, an ancient healing symbol. A chamozi. They\nprobably cut this down for firewood. \nYOUNG CHAKOTAY: The Rubber Tree People? \nKOLOPAK: Well, the closest thing to the ancient Rubber Tree People that\nwe'll ever see. The people in this tribe are their descendants, just\nlike we are. But they never left this jungle, and they rarely\nintermarry with other tribes. \nYOUNG CHAKOTAY: And they still use firewood instead of magnesite fuel\nlike everyone else. \nKOLOPAK: Chakotay, they have chosen to live like this for centuries.\nThat's why we are travelling on foot and not using a transporter. We", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 13, "LOC"], [152, 161, "PER"], [230, 236, "PER"], [438, 448, "PER"], [572, 580, "PER"], [697, 720, "LOC"], [900, 907, "PER"], [911, 918, "PER"], [975, 982, "PER"], [1744, 1752, "PER"]]}
{"id": 352, "text": "[Promenade\n- upper level]\n\n(People are arriving through the airlock below and\nbeing met.) \nMAN: Here they are. Welcome. \nWOMAN: Thank you. \nPADD: Recording. \nJAKE: Character sketches for possible stories. A Bolian tries to\nimpress a dabo girl by wearing a toupee. A thief disguises himself as a\nMonk so he can swindle a Ferengi. A woman travelling alone. She's come\na long way. \n(The woman looks up at Jake. Their eyes meet. Jake looks away and she\nwalks off.)\n\n [Security office]\n\n(A woman in a purple dress is waiting for Odo,\ncrying.) \nODO: Lwaxana? \nLWAXANA: Oh, hello, Odo. \nODO: You've been crying. \nLWAXANA: I can't help it. \nODO: Why? \nLWAXANA: Because. \n(She stands up to show off her big belly.) \nLWAXANA: I'm pregnant. \n(After the titles, Odo has picked his jaw up off the floor.) \nLWAXANA: It's a miracle. I never thought I could have another baby. \nODO: Then those were tears of happiness? \nLWAXANA: I won't let him do it, Odo. \nODO: Who? What? \nLWAXANA: My husband, Jeyal. He wants to take my baby. That's why I ran\naway. \nODO: Please, Lwaxana, try to be calm. Now tell me, why would your\nhusband want to take your baby from you? \nLWAXANA: He's Tavnian. \nODO: And? \nLWAXANA: They believe in strict separation of the sexes. Boys are\nraised by men, girls by women. Why, those poor children aren't even\ntold the other sex exists until they're sixteen. \nODO: And your child is male?", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 24, "LOC"], [207, 213, "SPEC"], [320, 327, "SPEC"], [295, 299, "SPEC"], [402, 406, "PER"], [425, 429, "PER"], [464, 479, "LOC"], [524, 527, "PER"], [544, 551, "PER"], [574, 577, "PER"], [750, 753, "PER"], [936, 939, "PER"], [980, 985, "PER"], [1050, 1057, "PER"], [1159, 1166, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 340, "text": "[Bridge]\n\n(Voyager is cruising when it is hit by weapons fire.)JANEWAY:\nReport. \nPARIS: A ship just decloaked off our port stern. \nJANEWAY: Can you identify them? \nKIM: They re-cloaked. \nTUVOK: That disruptor blast had a Klingon signature. \nJANEWAY: Evasive manoeuvres. Hail them. \nTUVOK: No response. Port shields are down to fifty percent. (We get a glimpse of a vessel usually seen in the Original Series.)\nKIM: They've re-cloaked again. Tetryon readings indicate it's a D-Seven\nClass cruiser. \nPARIS: D-Seven? They were retired decades ago. \nTUVOK: If their technology is antiquated\nCHAKOTAY: Perhaps a metaphasic scan might be able to penetrate their\ncloak. \nJANEWAY: Do it. \nCHAKOTAY: Bridge to Astrometrics. \n[Astrometrics\nlab]\n\nCHAKOTAY\n[OC]: Initiate a metaphasic sweep. \nSEVEN: I've detected a vessel. Transferring the trajectory to tactical.\n\n[Bridge]\n\nTUVOK: I\nhave them. \nJANEWAY: Fire phasers. \n[Klingon\nBridge] \nMORAK:\nOur cloak has failed. \nKOHLAR: Divert emergency power to shields.\nMORAK: Forward emitters are offline. The Federation ship is hailing\nagain.\nKOHLAR: Answer them. \nT'GRETH: Captain! \nKOHLAR: It may give us more time to get the cloak back on online.\nVisual. \nJANEWAY [on viewscreen]: This is Captain Kathryn Janeway of the\nFederation starship Voyager. Stand down.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 7, "LOC"], [11, 18, "SHIP"], [221, 228, "SPEC"], [474, 495, "SHIP"], [691, 697, "ORG"], [701, 713, "ORG"], [717, 733, "LOC"], [855, 861, "LOC"], [910, 924, "LOC"], [1106, 1113, "PER"], [1224, 1247, "PER"], [1275, 1282, "SHIP"], [1041, 1051, "GPE"], [1255, 1265, "GPE"]]}
{"id": 843, "text": "[Planet\nsurface] \n (Kirk and Spock are standing by a large purple\nboulder.) \nSPOCK: Our scanner survey was correct, Captain. There it is. Pure\ntritanium. \nKIRK: Fantastic. 20 times as hard as diamond. \nSPOCK: Twenty one point four times as hard, to be exact. \nKIRK: Thank you, Mister Spock. (into communicator) Scotty, you can mark\nthis vein as confirmed. Inform Starfleet I recommend that they dispatch\na survey vessel immediately. \n(Unseen by the landing party, a cloud of smoke is coming out of another\nrock and heading for them.) \nSCOTT [OC]: Acknowledged, Captain. They'll send one fast enough for\nthis rich a find. \nSPOCK: We won't be able to break it, Captain. I'll phaser off a\nspecimen. \n(He does so, and the smoke retreats.) \nKIRK: Lesley. \n(He is handed a pair of tongs to pick up the sample with.) \nKIRK: Do you smell that? A sweet odour like honey. It was years ago, on\nanother planet. A thing with a an odour like that. \nSPOCK: We're in the growing season in this hemisphere of this planet.\nThere are doubtless many pollen aromas. \nKIRK: Rizzo. \nRIZZO: Yes, sir? \nKIRK: Take your men. Make a swing around our perimeter. Scan for\ndikironium in the atmosphere. Set your phasers on disrupter-B. If you\nsee any gaseous cloud, fire immediately. You're on Red Alert. Make a\nsweep. \nSCOTT [OC]: Ready to beam back aboard, Captain? \nKIRK: Negative, Scotty. We're checking something out. \nSCOTT [OC]: The USS Yorktown is expecting to rendezvous with us in less\nthan eight hours, Captain. That doesn't give us much time. \nKIRK: Acknowledged. Continue standing by. Kirk out. \nSPOCK: Captain, dikironium exists only in laboratory experiments. \nKIRK: It's gone. I could have been wrong. The last time I caught an\nodour like that was eleven years ago. \n[Clearing]\n\n(The three red-shirts have run into a clearing.) \nRIZZO: Seemed to read dikironium for a minute, and then I lost it. It's", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[20, 24, "PER"], [29, 34, "PER"], [116, 123, "PER"], [277, 289, "PER"], [311, 317, "PER"], [363, 372, "ORG"], [561, 568, "PER"], [659, 666, "PER"], [742, 748, "PER"], [1052, 1057, "PER"], [1329, 1336, "PER"], [1355, 1361, "PER"], [1410, 1422, "SHIP"], [1484, 1491, "PER"], [1568, 1572, "PER"], [1586, 1593, "PER"]]}
{"id": 618, "text": "Captain's log, Stardate 42402.7. We are travelling in the Omega Sagitta\nsystem traversing between twin planets that form the Coalition of\nMadena. Both worlds is populated by a humanoid race which colonised the\nplanets two centuries ago, and which now co-exist under a precarious\nbut successful treaty.\n\n[Bridge]\n\nWORF: Unidentified vessel approaching. \nDATA: Sensor readings show it to be a small class-nine vessel, probably\nan interplanetary cargo ship. \nWORF: One life sign aboard, sir. It appears to be humanoid. \nDATA: I have its call sign now, sir. \nWORF: Confirmed. Armed with lasers only. \nDATA: Its cargo holds are empty. The readout shows its guidance system\nis malfunctioning. The pilot is attempting to hold course manually. \nRIKER: I recommend we set the Enterprise on an intercept course in case\nhe needs emergency assistance. \nPICARD: Make it so, Mister Crusher. \n(The little ship comes up astern of the majestic vessel) \nRIKER: We're in position now, Captain. \nPICARD: Open hailing frequencies. \nWORF: Hailing frequencies open. \nPICARD: On viewer. This is the USS Enterprise. Captain Jean Luc Picard.\n\nOKONA [on viewscreen]: (bending over, bottom towards us) And this is\nthe cargo carrier Erstwhile. Captain Okona at your service, sir.\nThere's no need for your phasers, Captain. I'm harmless and not quite\nyet ready for mercy killing. \nPICARD: You were never considered a danger to us, Captain. \nOKONA [on viewscreen]: Oh, that's a shame. I can remember when I was at\nleast considered a risk. \n(Okona is a handsome, long-haired pirate of a man, and he sits down to\nface us) \nOKONA [on viewscreen]: I'm the owner and operator of this craft and\nsince we both know that you've already scanned it, you know I'm alone\nand empty, which is truly a rare occasion for a man of my charm and\ntalent. \nPICARD: Mute main viewer. Counsellor?", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[58, 78, "LOC"], [125, 144, "ORG"], [767, 777, "SHIP"], [861, 875, "PER"], [966, 973, "PER"], [1079, 1089, "SHIP"], [1091, 1114, "PER"], [1204, 1213, "SHIP"], [1215, 1228, "PER"], [1285, 1292, "PER"], [1401, 1408, "PER"], [1510, 1515, "PER"], [1831, 1841, "PER"]]}
{"id": 728, "text": "Captain's Log: Stardate 4372.5. On a top-secret diplomatic mission, the\nEnterprise has entered the Tellun star system.\nMaintaining communications blackout, we have taken aboard Petri,\nAmbassador from Troyius, the outer planet, and are now approaching the\ninner planet Elas.\n\n[Turbolift]\n\nKIRK: Some desk-bound Starfleet bureaucrat cut\nthese cloak-and-dagger orders. \nSCOTT: Aye, but why the secrecy? This star system's under Federation\ncontrol. \nSPOCK: It's in a border area, Mister Scott. The Klingons also claim\njurisdiction. \nSCOTT: From what I've seen, it's not worth fighting about. Why are we\nhere, Captain? \nKIRK: My orders are to co-operate with Ambassador Petri in all matters\npertaining to his mission here. \nUHURA [OC]: Bridge to Captain Kirk. \nKIRK: Scotty. (Scott presses the intercom button) Kirk here. What is\nit? \nUHURA [OC]: Captain, I have a signal from the Elasians. They're ready\nto beam aboard, and they demand an explanation for the delay. \nKIRK: Demand? What delay? All right. Beam them aboard. \nSPOCK: Sounds typical of the Elasians. The scientists who made the\ninitial investigation reported the men were vicious and arrogant. \nMCCOY: That's just the negative part, Mister Spock. I've been over\nthose records. Now the women, they're supposed to be something very\nspecial. They're supposed to have a kind of subtle, mystical power that\ndrives men wild. \n[Corridor]\n\n(The Ambassador is a skinny humanoid with orange\nhair and grass green skin.) \nKIRK: Ambassador Petri, would you drop all this nonsense and tell me\nwhat this is about? \nPETRI: That must wait until the Dohlman is aboard. \nKIRK: Dohlman? What the devil is a Dohlman? \n[Transporter room]", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[72, 82, "SHIP"], [99, 117, "LOC"], [177, 182, "PER"], [200, 207, "LOC"], [268, 272, "LOC"], [276, 285, "LOC"], [310, 319, "ORG"], [425, 435, "GPE"], [476, 488, "PER"], [494, 502, "SPEC"], [654, 670, "PER"], [731, 737, "LOC"], [741, 753, "PER"], [762, 768, "PER"], [771, 776, "PER"], [806, 810, "PER"], [842, 849, "PER"], [876, 884, "SPEC"], [605, 612, "PER"], [1048, 1056, "SPEC"], [1191, 1203, "PER"], [1379, 1387, "LOC"], [1391, 1405, "PER"], [1474, 1490, "PER"], [1590, 1597, "PER"]]}
{"id": 554, "text": "[Bridge] \n\n(Enterprise is flying close to a massive star.) \nT'POL: It's losing mass at an extraordinary rate. \nREED: How long before it goes supernova? \nT'POL: A hundred years, maybe two. \nARCHER: Too bad we won't be around. It's going to be one hell of an\nexplosion. \nT'POL: Speak for yourself. I might very well be around. \nTUCKER: Can't forget Vulcan longevity, Captain. A hundred years from\nnow? How old would that make you? \nARCHER: No earth ship has ever been within ten light years of a\nhypergiant. How much farther can we move in? \nT'POL: Our hull temperature is approaching eleven hundred degrees. It\nwould be unsafe to get any closer. \nARCHER: Then we'll have to run our scans from here. Tell Astrometrics\nto get going. I'm sure they're champing at the bit. \nREED: We may not be able to get any closer, but someone else has. \nARCHER: You found a ship? \nREED: Bearing two six one mark four. They must be at least twenty\nthousand kilometres farther in than we are. \nARCHER: Let's see her. (A ship comes up on the viewscreen.) ARCHER: Recognise\nit? \nT'POL: No. \nARCHER: Hail them. \nHOSHI: The interference is pretty heavy, sir. \nARCHER: Then try audio. This is Captain Archer of the starship\nEnterprise. I assume you've detected us. \nDRENNIK [OC]: Captain Drennik. Where have you travelled from? \nARCHER: The Sol system. And you? \nDRENNIK [OC]: We come from a system called Vissia, more than twenty\nfive light years from here. We saw you arrive yesterday. I assume\nyou're here to study the hypergiant. \nARCHER: My species has never seen one up close. \nDRENNIK [OC]: It is quite a sight. Have you measured its rate of\nnucleosynthesis? \nARCHER: I'm afraid we haven't developed the technology to do that. \nDRENNIK [OC]: If you don't mind eliminating the development stage, I'd\nbe more than happy to help you modify your sensors. \nARCHER: Thank you. I'm not sure we have anything to offer you in\nreturn. \nDRENNIK [OC]: You could invite us to visit your ship. Meeting new\nspecies is one of our primary goals.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 7, "LOC"], [12, 22, "SHIP"], [347, 353, "SPEC"], [365, 372, "PER"], [441, 446, "LOC"], [703, 715, "ORG"], [1168, 1182, "PER"], [1199, 1209, "SHIP"], [1263, 1270, "PER"], [1316, 1326, "LOC"], [1381, 1387, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 867, "text": "Captain's log, Stardate 43779.3. The Enterprise is preparing detailed\nexospheric charts of the Hayashi system. Although tedious, this\nendeavour is the first step toward planet colonisation.\n\n[Bridge]\n\nDATA: Captain, sensors report the USS Hood is\nclosing on an intercept course at high warp. \nPICARD: That's odd. We weren't notified of a rendezvous. \nRIKER: They seem to be in an awful hurry. \nWORF: Sir, we are being hailed on a secured channel by Captain DeSoto. \nPICARD: On screen. \nDESOTO [on viewscreen]: Sorry to sneak up on you like that, Jean Luc \nPICARD: Robert, why didn't you inform us? \nDESOTO [on viewscreen]: Out here, you never know who's listening. Keeps\nyou on your toes, anyway. Hey, Will. Will, you getting soft on that\nluxury liner? \nPICARD: So, old friend. How are you? \nDESOTO [on viewscreen]: Well, you know, they send you Galaxy Class boys\nout here to the far reaches. Me, I'm just hauling my butt back and\nforth between starbases. \nPICARD: But not today. \nDESOTO [on viewscreen]: No, not today. Starfleet's got new orders for\nyou. This is top priority. They need the fastest ship in the fleet and\nthe best people. That is you. \nPICARD: If time is so important, why didn't they transmit the orders by\nsubspace? \nDESOTO [on viewscreen]: They're worried about Romulan eavesdropping on\nthis one. And we've got a passenger for you. Hard to send by subspace. \nPICARD: What sort of passenger? \nDESOTO [on viewscreen]: Mission specialist. He'll bring your orders\naboard with him. His name is Tam Elbrun. \nRIKER: As in Tam Elbrun of the Ghorusda disaster? \nDESOTO [on viewscreen]: The same. What can I say? Your orders are to\ncooperate fully with him. Best of luck, folks. Hood out. \nDATA: Sir, the Hood is slowing to impulse. \nPICARD: Mister Data, come with me. \nTROI: Captain, let me come with you to greet Tam. \nPICARD: You know him? \nTROI: I do. He was at the university on Betazed when I studied\npsychology there.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[95, 109, "LOC"], [192, 198, "LOC"], [37, 47, "SHIP"], [207, 214, "PER"], [235, 243, "SHIP"], [449, 463, "PER"], [546, 554, "PER"], [564, 570, "PER"], [702, 706, "PER"], [708, 712, "PER"], [1020, 1029, "ORG"], [1282, 1289, "SPEC"], [1509, 1519, "PER"], [1535, 1545, "PER"], [1553, 1561, "LOC"], [1689, 1693, "PER"], [1715, 1719, "PER"], [1752, 1763, "PER"], [1786, 1793, "PER"], [1825, 1828, "PER"], [1894, 1901, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 740, "text": "[OC]: Previously on Enterprise \n\n(Scenes of fighting fires and injured crew.) \nARCHER [OC]: We're in bad shape, I can't deny that.\n\nDEGRA: Perhaps my crew can help. \n(Over shots of T'Pol's dreams and anger outbursts.) \nT'POL [OC]: My emotions are growing more difficult to control. \nPHLOX [OC]: You used trellium for three months. \nPHLOX [Sickbay]: You\nmay have to learn to live with these emotions. \nDEGRA [Ready room]:\nThese are the coordinates of the Council chamber. \nARCHER: It'll take us weeks to get there. \nDEGRA: There's a shorter route. A subspace corridor. I'll meet you at\nthe far end in three days. \nARCHER: See you in three days. \n [T'Pol's quarters] \n (It's dark. A candle is burning.) \nT'POL: (a very old woman) Come in. The probe? \nLORIAN: We couldn't stop it from entering the vortex. It's on it's way\nto Earth. \nT'POL: Seven million people. \nLORIAN: Everything is happening as it did before. \nT'POL: Then you have no choice. You must find Jonathan Archer. \n [T'Pol's quarters] \n (Our young woman is trying to meditate by\ncandlelight when the doorbell chimes.) \nT'POL: Come in. \nTUCKER: I'm sorry about to bother you. I'm having a little trouble\nfalling asleep. I think my insomnia 's come back. \nT'POL: You're here for neuro-pressure. \nTUCKER: It's been weeks since our last session. We've all been under a\nlot of stress lately. I thought it might do us both some good. \nT'POL: I think we should discontinue these treatments. \nTUCKER: Why? \nT'POL: You've become quite skilled with the postures I've shown you. \nTUCKER: You told me it takes years to master neuro-pressure. I'm not\nthat quick a study. \nT'POL: I've taught you all I can. \n(Tucker sits down in front of her.) \n\nTUCKER: Look, truth is I'm sleeping fine. I ain't come for\nneuro-pressure, I came because I'm worried about you. \nT'POL: Worried?", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[181, 186, "PER"], [339, 346, "LOC"], [408, 418, "LOC"], [454, 469, "LOC"], [647, 663, "LOC"], [823, 828, "LOC"], [958, 973, "PER"], [978, 994, "LOC"], [1656, 1662, "PER"]]}
{"id": 388, "text": "[Bridge]\n\nSPOCK: Captain, we've reached the designated\nposition for scanning the coded directive tape. \nKIRK: Good. (puts it into a decoder) We both guessed right.\nNegotiations with the Klingon Empire are on the verge of breaking down.\nStarfleet Command anticipates a surprise attack. We are to proceed to\nOrgania and take whatever steps are necessary to prevent the Klingons\nfrom using it as a base. \nSPOCK: Strategically sound. Organia is the only Class M planet in the\ndisputed area, ideally located for use by either side. \nKIRK: Organia's description, Mister Spock. \nSPOCK: Inhabited by humanoids. A very peaceful, friendly people living\non a primitive level. Little of intrinsic value. Approximately Class D\nminus on Richter's scale of cultures. \nKIRK: Another Armenia, Belgium. \nSPOCK: Sir? \nKIRK: The weak innocents who always seem to be located on the natural\ninvasion routes. \nSULU: Captain, the automatic deflector screen just popped on. Body\napproaching. \nKIRK: Configuration, Mister Sulu. \n(Everyone is thrown about as the Enterprise is hit by multiple weapons\nfire.) \nKIRK: Phaser banks, lock on. Return fire. Maintain firing rate. One\nhundred percent dispersal pattern. \nSPOCK: We've hit him, Captain. He's hurt. \nKIRK: Damage control, report to the first officer. \nSULU: Captain, the other ship doesn't register. Only drifting debris.\nWe got him. \nKIRK: All hands, maintain general alert. Hold battle stations. Damage\nreport, Mister Spock. \nSPOCK: Minor, Captain. We were most fortunate. Blast damage in decks\nten and eleven, minor buckling in the antimatter pods, casualties very\nlight. \nKIRK: Maintain surveillance, Mister Sulu. \nSULU: No contact, Captain. He blew up all right. \nKIRK: Well, we've been anticipating an attack. I'd say what we've just\nexperienced very nearly qualifies. \nSPOCK: Yes. It would seem to be an unfriendly act.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 7, "LOC"], [17, 24, "PER"], [186, 200, "GPE"], [236, 253, "ORG"], [306, 313, "LOC"], [430, 437, "LOC"], [472, 485, "LOC"], [367, 375, "GPE"], [534, 541, "LOC"], [557, 569, "PER"], [767, 774, "LOC"], [776, 783, "LOC"], [893, 900, "PER"], [989, 1000, "PER"], [1036, 1046, "SHIP"], [1208, 1215, "PER"], [1287, 1294, "PER"], [1442, 1454, "PER"], [1471, 1478, "PER"], [1520, 1540, "LOC"], [1634, 1645, "PER"], [1666, 1673, "PER"]]}
{"id": 540, "text": "T'POL\n[OC]: Previously on Enterprise \n\n DEGRA [Command\nCentre]: (referring to a sphere) How to you plan to get\ninside? \nARCHER: We're pretty sure we've found a way in. I'm sending a crew in a\nshuttlepod. \nT'POL: The Spheres are controlled by a network of artificial\nintelligence. This section houses the redundant memory core. It should\ncontain a significant amount of information. \nARCHER: We're hoping that'll include data on the Sphere Builders. \n([Inside the Sphere, MACO\nHawkins is grabbed and killed by the Sphere defence mechanism.) \nREED: Hawkins! \nDEGRA [Ready room]: I'll\nbe at your side no matter what happens. \nDOLIM [Xindi Council Chamber: We've\ntaken control of the weapon. We're going to launch it. \nDEGRA [Council Chamber, earlier]: Wait! \n(He tries to stop Dolim and he and Archer get hit) \nDOLIM [Degra's quarters]: We\nhave an image of your ship firing. \nDEGRA: They left me no choice. \nDOLIM: You've left me no choice. (stabs him in the chest) The crew of\nthat ship are the last Xindi you'll ever betray. \nHUMANOID [Xindi Council Chamber]: The\nweapon cannot be launched without three of the codes. \nDOLIM: Do you really believe we haven't considered that? \nARCHER [Bridge]:\nHoshi! \n(She's beamed away.) \n [Reptilian Interrogation room]\n\n HOSHI: Why am I here? What do you want? \nDOLIM: We were impressed with your linguistic abilities. Aquatic is\ndifficult to master. I've heard it spoken my entire life but still, it\ndoesn't come easily to me. \nHOSHI: Maybe you should have applied yourself more. \nDOLIM: We have some encoded data we need translated. \nHOSHI: I'm not a cryptologist. \nDOLIM: I have confidence in your abilities.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[47, 61, "LOC"], [432, 447, "SPEC"], [630, 651, "LOC"], [722, 737, "LOC"], [774, 779, "PER"], [791, 797, "PER"], [815, 822, "PER"], [998, 1003, "SPEC"], [1035, 1056, "LOC"], [1193, 1198, "PER"], [1355, 1362, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 833, "text": "[Quark's]\n\n(After hours tongo with Quark and his staff.) \nDAX: Sell at twenty. \nQUARK: Is that a joke? \nDAX: Do I look like I'm joking? \nQUARK: Evade. \nDAX: Exchange at fifteen. \n[Quark's cafe]\n\n(Up on the first level, there are spectators.) \nWORF: She has him. \nO'BRIEN: She's down fifty strips. \nWORF: Not for long. \nO'BRIEN: What makes you so sure? \nWORF: Jadzia is playing a very deep game. Her strategy will become\napparent any moment now. \nO'BRIEN: I see. You have absolutely no idea how this game is played, do\nyou? \nWORF: No. But I have developed a new appreciation for it. \nO'BRIEN: Since when? \nWORF: Since I married a tongo player. But one thing I am certain about,\nshe will defeat the Ferengi bartender. \nO'BRIEN: I don't know about that. Quark's on a roll. In the last month,\nhe's won two hundred and six straight games. \nWORF: Would you care to make a wager on the outcome? \nO'BRIEN: I wouldn't want to bet against a man's wife. \nWORF: If you are afraid, I \nO'BRIEN: Name your stakes. \nWORF: One bottle of bloodwine against one bottle of scotch whiskey. \nO'BRIEN: Done. \nDAX: A sale at fifty and a purchase at one hundred. \n[Quark's]\n\nQUARK: Pretty big talk for a woman who's lost fifty\nstrips. \nDAX: Are you afraid I can't cover my bets? \nQUARK: Perish the thought. I just hate to kick somebody when they're\ndown. I'll buy at a hundred and confront. \nDAX: Well, if you're going to kick me, I'm going to have to kick back.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 8, "LOC"], [35, 40, "PER"], [180, 192, "LOC"], [359, 365, "PER"], [697, 704, "SPEC"], [751, 756, "PER"], [1139, 1146, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 658, "text": "[Bridge]\n\n (The Enterprise is gliding past a red planet\ntowards a blue one.) \nSPOCK: Passing outer planet, Zeon. \nKIRK: We want the inner one, Ekos. Plot a standard orbit, Mister\nChekov, and take us in. \nCHEKOV: Aye, sir. \nKIRK: Lieutenant Uhura, raise John Gill on Starfleet communications. \nUHURA: Aye, aye, sir. \nMCCOY: Starfleet's been trying for six months. If he's alive, isn't it\nunlikely that he'd receive us now? \nKIRK: I don't know, Bones. We're here to find out what's happened\nbecause I don't know. \nSPOCK: I never met John Gill, but I studied Earth history from the text\nhe prepared. \nKIRK: I knew him very well. He was my instructor at the Academy. \nSPOCK: What impressed me most was his treatment of Earth history as\ncauses and motivations rather than dates and events. \nUHURA: Captain, no response on any Starfleet channel. \nCHEKOV: Spacecraft approaching from inner planet. \nKIRK: From Ekos? \nSPOCK: Yes, but it must be a Zeon ship. Zeons do have a crude\ninterplanetary capability. Reaction powered. A small rocket. It is on\nan intercept course. That would mean it has sophisticated detection\ndevices which neither Zeon nor Ekos should have. \nKIRK: Have you raised anyone, Lieutenant? \nUHURA: Nothing, sir. \nSPOCK: Captain, it's an unmanned probe which seems to be carrying a\nwarhead. \nKIRK: Stand by phasers. \nCHEKOV: Phasers ready. \nKIRK: Range, Mister Chekov? \nCHEKOV: Two thousand kilometres, closing fast. \nKIRK: Fire. \n(A big ball of fire fills the viewscreen. Fire in a vacuum? Never\nmind.) \nSPOCK: Fascinating. A thermonuclear warhead. \nMCCOY: That's generations ahead of where these people should be\ntechnically. How'd they manage that? \nKIRK: Maybe they had help. Maximum orbit. Take us out of range of their", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 7, "LOC"], [16, 26, "SHIP"], [107, 111, "LOC"], [143, 147, "LOC"], [172, 185, "PER"], [229, 245, "PER"], [253, 262, "PER"], [266, 275, "ORG"], [323, 334, "ORG"], [443, 448, "PER"], [531, 540, "PER"], [556, 561, "LOC"], [654, 661, "ORG"], [715, 720, "LOC"], [793, 800, "PER"], [821, 830, "ORG"], [903, 907, "LOC"], [939, 943, "SPEC"], [950, 955, "SPEC"], [1132, 1136, "SPEC"], [1141, 1145, "SPEC"], [1232, 1239, "PER"], [1365, 1378, "PER"]]}
{"id": 674, "text": "Last\ntime on Star Trek: The Next Generation \n\nRIKER: My friend tells me you might know about the man we're looking\nfor. \nYRANEC: There was a group of aliens sitting at this table. He was\nasking them questions. One of them took out a weapon and fired. He was\nvapourised. \nRIKER: This is about justice. The Captain died in a bar fight for\nnothing. \n(the kidnap of Riker from the ruins) \nBARAN: Those ruins have been studied for centuries. There's nothing new\nto learn from them.\nRIKER: Then what were you doing there? \nPICARD: Baran wouldn't last five minutes as captain if he didn't have\nthat control device. \nTALLERA: That almost sounds like a prelude to mutiny. \nPICARD: They captured me to find out how much I knew about their\noperation. \nRIKER: Then you became a member of their crew? \nPICARD: I convinced them I was a smuggler. Will, these are not common\nthieves. They are stealing Romulan artefacts from archeological sites\nthroughout this sector. \nDATA: Mister Worf, prepare to drop shields. \nWORF: Sir, we would be totally defenceless. \nDATA: I am aware of that. \nBARAN: Fire. \n\nAnd now, the conclusion. \n[Bridge]\n\n(the weapons fire definitely hits the starboard\nnacelle) \nWORF: Direct hit to the port nacelle. Only minimal damage. Hit to the\nstarboard nacelle. Still, no appreciable damage. \nTROI: Will must've done something to their weapons. \nDATA: I believe you are right, Counsellor. It is now up to us to play\nalong. Release inertial dampers and cut power to decks thirty one\nthrough thirty seven. \nGIUSTI: Aye, sir. \nDATA: Set phasers to twenty five percent. Return fire.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[305, 312, "PER"], [362, 367, "PER"], [525, 530, "PER"], [832, 836, "PER"], [886, 893, "SPEC"], [960, 971, "PER"], [1113, 1119, "LOC"], [1384, 1394, "PER"]]}
{"id": 664, "text": "Captain's log, Stardate 42686.4. We are en route to Starbase Montgomery\nfor engineering consultations prompted by minor readout anomalies.\n\n[Engineering]\n\nDATA: I would consider them insignificant. \nRIKER: What if you're wrong? Sorry. But what if it is more than a mere\ndiscrepancy? \nLAFORGE: Then I'd say we have a problem. \nPICARD: Agreed. We'll have Starbase Montgomery give us an independent\nreading. \nDATA: Even if the molecular level controls have failed, we can still\nrecrystallise the dilithium without outside help. \nLAFORGE: Don't worry, Data. My ego isn't at stake here. \nDATA: Perhaps we can reprogram the system to correct the readout\nvariables \nPICARD: Well, that's certainly another option, but as we're stopping at\nStarbase Montgomery anyway, we'll let them do the analysis. \nRIKER: I don't recall Starbase Montgomery on the mission itinerary \nPICARD: I think we could all use a twelve hour layover. Besides, I've\njust received some personnel transfer directives. Priority matter, \nRIKER: Boarding or disembarking? \nWESLEY [OC]: Captain Picard. We're within hailing range of Starbase\nMontgomery \nPICARD: Go to half impulse power. (to Riker) Will you join me in the\nObservation lounge when you're done?\n\n[Observation lounge]\n\nRIKER: Captain? \nPICARD: Number One, I've just been recollecting the arrival of a new\nFirst Officer on board the Enterprise, and a manual docking confidently\nachieved. I may have been somewhat miserly in my congratulations then,\nso let me make up for it now. The Captain of the Starship Ares is\nretiring. Congratulations. You've been selected as his replacement. \nRIKER: The Ares. She's in Vega-Omicron sector. \nPICARD: And they have picked up indications of an intelligent life\nform, though nothing confirmed. \nRIKER: Obviously, Starfleet will want to know more.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[52, 71, "LOC"], [141, 152, "LOC"], [353, 372, "LOC"], [731, 750, "LOC"], [814, 833, "LOC"], [1045, 1059, "PER"], [1091, 1110, "LOC"], [1181, 1199, "LOC"], [1220, 1238, "LOC"], [1248, 1255, "PER"], [1266, 1276, "PER"], [1327, 1340, "PER"], [1354, 1364, "SHIP"], [1504, 1532, "PER"], [1616, 1620, "SHIP"], [1631, 1650, "LOC"], [1771, 1780, "ORG"]]}
