{"id": 704, "text": "[Launch bay]\n\n      (A shuttlepod has just returned from a planet. It's crew are not in uniform and they have foreheads with \n      distinctive lines across them and no eyebrows.) \n      HOSHI: I need to spend more time in the gym. \n      ARCHER: If I knew there were going to be so many hills I would have picked a different city to explore. \n      REED: It was worth every step, sir. The architecture alone. \n      HOSHI: I could have spent all day in that temple.\n      \n [Decon chamber]\n\n(Everyone peels off their fake foreheads.)       REED: With your permission, Captain, I'd like to write \n      the report to Starfleet. It was my first visit to a pre-warp culture. Seems only fitting. \n      HOSHI: I don't suppose it has anything to do with the tactical situation down there. \n      REED: Am I that obvious? \n      ARCHER: I can't think of a better man for the job. (Phlox looks through the observation window.) \n      PHLOX: Welcome home. \n      ARCHER: Any unexpected guests? \n      PHLOX: Not a single parasite, spore or virus. I take it your expedition was productive? \n      ARCHER: Very. \n      PHLOX: You're done here.\n      \n [Locker room]\n\n      ARCHER: You know, as interesting as that was, it's always good to get home. \n      REED: The speaker at the political rally, what was his name? Chancellor Kultrey? \n      HOSHI: Kultarey. \n      REED: You could write a book about him alone. His speech reminded me of Winston Churchill before the Second World War. \n      (He starts hunting through his pockets.) \n      ARCHER: Something wrong? Malcolm? \n      REED: My communicator. \n      ARCHER: What about it? \n      REED: It's gone. \n      \n [Launch bay]\n\n      (Hoshi is checking down the back of the pods seats as Archer looks underneath outside.) \n      REED: It's not in decon. Any luck? \n      ARCHER: None yet. \n      REED: What about the launch bay crew? Could they have found it while they were securing the pod? \n      ARCHER: I've already spoken to them.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[617, 626, "ORG"], [569, 576, "PER"], [876, 881, "PER"], [1308, 1326, "PER"], [1342, 1350, "PER"], [1431, 1448, "PER"], [1793, 1798, "LOC"], [476, 489, "LOC"], [1863, 1878, "ORG"], [1, 11, "LOC"], [1144, 1155, "LOC"], [1661, 1671, "LOC"], [1734, 1740, "PER"], [1558, 1565, "PER"]]}
{"id": 705, "text": "[Sickbay] \n(Archer\nwheels T'Pol in on a trolley.) \n\nARCHER: She's coming to! \nT'POL: Let me go. Let me go! (She tries to strangle Archer.) \nARCHER: Stop. \nT'POL: I'll kill you. \nARCHER: We're not going to hurt you. \nT'POL: You liar! No! Get away from me. (T'Pol screams as she's strapped down.)\n\nPHLOX: The damage is more severe than I expected. \nARCHER: Can you reverse it? \nPHLOX: I'm not certain. T'Pol (tries to dodge the hypospray.) \nT'POL: What's he doing? \nARCHER: It's all right. He's trying to help you. \nT'POL: He's trying to kill me! You killed the others. Murderers! Get\naway! (She screams until Archer holds her head and she is finally sedated,\nthen she is rolled into the Imaging Chamber.) \n One\nDay Earlier \n [Command\nCentre] \n TUCKER:\nI talked with Chef at dinner. He's a little worried about the crew.\nPeople are skipping meals. He figures they're either too busy or the\nstress of this mission is starting to get to them. \nARCHER: I haven't had much of an appetite myself. \nTUCKER: Movie night's been on hold since we entered the Expanse. Maybe\nwe should start it up again? \nARCHER: There'll be plenty of time for movies after we've dealt with\nthe Xindi. \nTUCKER: No one hates the Xindi more than I do, Captain, but I'm telling\nyou this crew needs a little R and R. Unless you want Phlox to start\nmedicating people, we gotta, we've gotta find a way to boost morale. \nARCHER: What did you have in mind? \nTUCKER: I was thinking about a comedy. One of the classic Hope and\nCrosby pictures. \nARCHER: Good choice. \nT'POL: Captain. \nARCHER: We've been reviewing some of these Xindi star charts. Trip\nthought they might be able to help us figure out if there are any more\nspatial anomalies in the region. \nT'POL: I would have helped you do that.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 8, "LOC"], [26, 31, "PER"], [130, 136, "PER"], [256, 261, "PER"], [608, 614, "PER"], [686, 701, "LOC"], [765, 769, "PER"], [809, 817, "ORG"], [1165, 1170, "SPEC"], [1198, 1203, "SPEC"], [1220, 1227, "PER"], [1299, 1304, "PER"], [1254, 1258, "GPE"], [1478, 1482, "PER"], [1487, 1493, "PER"], [1534, 1541, "PER"], [1587, 1592, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 706, "text": "[Shuttlepod]\n\n Tthe shuttlepod is flying through a very crowded\nsystem and Tucker is in the back, doing something to a piece of\nequipment.) \nTUCKER: Chief Engineers log, supplemental. This turned out to be the\nperfect spot to test the autopilot upgrades. The gas giant has dozens\nof moons. It's like a gravitational jigsaw puzzle. Watch out, Travis.\nThese modifications are working so well, pretty soon we won't need\npilots anymore. \nARCHER [OC]: Archer to Shuttlepod one. \nTUCKER: Captain? \nARCHER [OC]: Looks like you're about to have some company, Trip.\nSensors are picking up a small (Fizzle, crackle.) \nTUCKER: Say again, Captain. I'm picking up a lot of interference. \nARCHER [OC] There's a small vessel approaching your position. \n(Tucker dashes to the pilot seat to see a small ship heading for him.) \nTUCKER: This is Commander Charles Tucker. (It fires at him and passes\nclose overhead, then returns for another strafing run.) TUCKER: Tucker to\nEnterprise. Mayday. I'm losing power. Mayday! If you can hear me, I'm\nmaking an emergency landing, thrusters only. I take it back, Travis. I\ncould use a flesh and blood pilot right about now. \n [Bridge] \n HOSHI: Enterprise to Shuttlepod One. Commander\nTucker, do you read me? \nTRAVIS: Malcolm? \nREED: I detected weapons fire and then both ships just disappeared. \nARCHER: Last known position? \nREED: Approximately fifty thousand kilometres, bearing zero zero\nthree mark two seven, I think. I can't be more specific. It's the\ndamned interference. \nT'POL: Many of these moons have atmospheres that contain selenium\nisotopes. That's most likely what's affecting our sensors. \nARCHER: Trip's a good pilot. If he was near one of those moons he most\nlikely set down on it. How many are there? \nT'POL: Sixty two. \nARCHER: Then we'd better start looking. Travis. \nTRAVIS: Yes, sir. \nARCHER: We'll scan every moon, even if we have to do it with\nbinoculars. Keep hailing him. \n [Shuttlepod] \n (Tucker opens the hatch and comes out into a night\nscene with insects chirping. There's rock and a dead tree. He goes back", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 11, "LOC"], [20, 30, "SHIP"], [75, 81, "PER"], [342, 348, "PER"], [447, 453, "PER"], [457, 467, "SHIP"], [482, 489, "PER"], [551, 555, "PER"], [627, 634, "PER"], [739, 745, "PER"], [826, 850, "PER"], [954, 964, "SHIP"], [944, 950, "PER"], [1085, 1091, "PER"], [1149, 1155, "LOC"], [1166, 1176, "SHIP"], [1180, 1194, "SHIP"], [1196, 1212, "PER"], [1239, 1246, "PER"], [1635, 1639, "PER"], [1938, 1944, "PER"], [1923, 1933, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 707, "text": "ARCHER\n[OC]: Previously, on Enterprise\n\n FORREST [United\nEarth Embassy]: We only want to be your partners, to work\ntogether in common cause. \n(BOOM!)\nARCHER [OC]: Admiral Forrest has been killed. \nPHLOX [Sickbay]: The\nDNA on the bomb's controls was left by this woman, T'Pau. \nSOVAL [Corridor]: The\nanswers you need are on Vulcan, and however far you have to take this\ninvestigation, you have my support. \nT'POL [Ready room]: This\nis a desert called the Forge. The route's the one Surak supposedly\nfollowed. \nTUCKER [Conference room]: The\nguard recognised the person who brought in the bomb we found in the\nrubble. \nSTEL: T'Pau. \nSOVAL: No. It was you. \nARCHER [Cave]: What's\na katra? \nT'POL: Syrrannites claim it's the essence of a Vulcan mind. \n(Over the shot of the dying Arev grabbing Archer's face.) \nT'POL [OC]: That it can be transferred from the body before death. \nSOVAL [Corridor]:\nV'Las was involved with the attack on your embassy. He's responsible\nfor blaming it on the Syrrannites. \n[Vulcan High Command]\n\nV'LAS: Before we announce our decision, is there\nanything you wish to say? \nSOVAL: My actions were taken in the best interest of Vulcan and the\nHigh Command. \nV'LAS: Keeping secrets from us is in our best interest? \nSOVAL: Had I revealed my abilities as a melder, my years of service\nwould not have been possible. \nKUVAK: Your accomplishments have been noteworthy. \nV'LAS: They don't justify deception. \nSOVAL: Deception has never been a stranger to this room. \nV'LAS: I caution you. \nSOVAL: One of our own members was responsible for bombing the Earth", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[50, 70, "LOC"], [204, 211, "LOC"], [284, 292, "LOC"], [163, 178, "PER"], [269, 274, "PER"], [323, 329, "LOC"], [413, 423, "LOC"], [454, 459, "LOC"], [481, 486, "PER"], [517, 532, "LOC"], [622, 627, "PER"], [662, 666, "LOC"], [693, 704, "SPEC"], [733, 739, "SPEC"], [775, 779, "PER"], [789, 795, "PER"], [892, 897, "PER"], [983, 994, "SPEC"], [998, 1017, "LOC"], [1164, 1176, "ORG"], [1149, 1155, "GPE"], [1567, 1572, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 708, "text": "[Holodeck - Doctor's\nFamily Programme Beta-Rho] \n (A\nhouse with a large living area, and a fire burning in a hearth set into\nthe corner.) \nCHARLENE: Jeffrey, Belle, you're going to be late if you don't hurry.\nCome on now. Line up next to the door, children. Your father's ready to\nleave for work. All right, show me your fingernails. Very nicely done.\nAre your shoes polished? Perfect. I'm very pleased, children, and I'm\nsure your father will be too. \n(How very idealistic 1950s USA.) \nBELLE: I want to be first to say goodbye to daddy. Jeffrey always goes\nfirst. \nJEFFREY: You were first yesterday. \nCHARLENE: Now, children, little birds in their nest get along. \nJEFFREY: You're right, mother. I'm sorry, Belle, you can go first. \nBELLE: No, it's really your turn. I did go first yesterday. \nJEFFREY: Here he comes. \nCHARLENE: All right, now. Bright, happy faces. \nEMH: The coffee was quite good this morning. \nCHARLENE: I'm so glad you like it. I replicated a new blend from Paxau\nthree. \nEMH: I'll be home at the usual time. \nCHARLENE: Now don't let them overwork you. You should save yourself for\nthe important things. Others can do the busy work. \nEMH: I couldn't agree more. \nJEFFREY: I hope you have a good day, Father. I'll have my homework\nfinished by the time you get back. \nEMH: I'll look forward to reviewing it, Jeffrey. And is my little angel\ngoing to get an A on her history exam today? \nBELLE: Of course I will, daddy, and can we do some algebra problems\nwhen you get home? \nEMH: Gladly. \nCHARLENE: And don't forget, you're going to ask some of your friends\nfrom work to have dinner with us. I'd like to meet them. \nEMH: I haven't forgotten. Well, goodbye all. \nALL: Goodbye, daddy. \n [Sickbay]\n\n KES:\nHow's the new holo-family, Doctor? \nEMH: They're everything I could have hoped for.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 9, "LOC"], [149, 156, "PER"], [158, 163, "PER"], [480, 483, "LOC"], [538, 545, "PER"], [708, 713, "PER"], [979, 990, "LOC"], [1327, 1334, "PER"], [1747, 1753, "PER"]]}
{"id": 709, "text": "Captain's log, stardate\n50537.2. Routine scans of an uninhabited star system have revealed the\npresence of gallicite, a very rare substance, on the fourth planet. \n[Bridge]\n\nTORRES:\nIf these readings are right, we're looking at a yield of nearly a\nkiloton. That would be enough gallicite to completely refit the warp\ncoils. \nPARIS: They sure could use it with all the damage they've taken the\npast two years. \nCHAKOTAY: Is there anyone in the area who might consider this their\nproperty? \nTUVOK: They are indications that a colony once existed on the planet's\nsurface. However, it appears to be long abandoned. \nJANEWAY: All right, let's stake a claim. I'll leave this in your hands,\nB'Elanna. Use whatever resources or personnel you need. You might want\nto talk to Mister Neelix. I believe he spent some time working in a\nmining colony. \nTORRES: Aye, Captain. \n[Engineering]\n\nTORRES:\nThese tunnels are clearly artificial. Someone else must've been\ninterested in digging up this gallicite. \nVORIK: That should make it easier to access the deposits. \nTORRES: True, but we have to be careful. There's been a lot of seismic\nactivity down there. Look, theses tunnels are completely collapsed. We\nshould bring Tom Paris on the away team. He's had quite a lot of rock\nclimbing experience. \nVORIK: I have spent several summers exploring the Osana caverns, which\ninvolved some quite treacherous climbing. \nTORRES: Great. You two can be our safety experts. \nVORIK: Have we completed our preparations to your satisfaction? \nTORRES: We're done here, yes. \nVORIK: Let me take this opportunity to declare koon-ut so'lik, my\ndesire to become your mate. \nTORRES: What? \nVORIK: In human terms, I am proposing marriage. Do you accept? \nTORRES: This is, er, a little sudden, isn't it? Besides, I thought that\nVulcan marriages were arranged. Don't you already have somebody back\nhome?", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[684, 692, "PER"], [766, 779, "PER"], [1205, 1214, "PER"], [1334, 1347, "LOC"], [1791, 1797, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 710, "text": "[Holodeck -\nSandrine's] \n (Kes\nenters. It is dark and quiet.) \nKES: Hello? Anybody here? Neelix?\n(The lights come on.) \nALL: Surprise!\nNEELIX: Surprise! Happy birthday, my sweet.\nJANEWAY: Happy birthday, Kes.\nNEELIX: Imagine, two years old today. If you ask me, you don't look a\nday over one.\nKES: Why was everyone hiding?\nPARIS: Oh, it's an old Earth custom called a surprise party.\nJANEWAY: Sorry if we startled you.\nKES: No, I liked it. It was very exhilarating.\nNEELIX: Now, how about a glass of my special birthday punch? Garçon?\n(The bartender is the EMH, in beret and smock.) \nEMH: On the rocks or straight up?\nKES: Doctor! I'm so glad you're here.\n(Sandrine drapes herself over the EMH's shoulders.) \nSANDRINE: My new bartender. Handsome, isn't he?\nEMH: I'm here in an official capacity, of course. In case of a medical\nemergency.\nKES: Emergency?\nEMH: Surprises have been known to cause acute hyperventilation,\noesophageal spasms and in extreme cases, even coronary arrest. One can\nnever be too careful. \n [Bridge]\n\n KIM:\nI've completed the sensor diagnostic, Lieutenant. All systems are fully\noperational.\nTUVOK: Very good, Ensign.\nKIM: And I've recalibrated the accelerometer relays.\nTUVOK: Acknowledged.\nKIM: Is there anything else I can do for you, sir?\nTUVOK: I presume this notable impatience is due to your desire to\nattend the festivities in Holodeck two.\nKIM: Yes, sir.\nTUVOK: May I remind you that your duty shift does not officially\nterminate for another thirty four minutes? However, I believe the\nholodeck power conduits would benefit from a routine inspection.\nKIM: Yes, sir! I'll get right on it.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 9, "LOC"], [27, 30, "PER"], [89, 95, "PER"], [204, 207, "PER"], [346, 351, "LOC"], [623, 629, "PER"], [657, 665, "PER"], [1015, 1021, "LOC"], [1133, 1139, "PER"], [1358, 1370, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 711, "text": "Captain's log, stardate\n48579.4. The crew has been scanning constantly for anomalies that might\nhelp us shorten our journey home. Ensign Kim has reported an exciting\ndiscovery. A subspace disturbance which may be a wormhole. \n [Bridge]\n\n\n(Janeway enters. Tuvok and Chakotay are at Kim's station.) \nJANEWAY: Let's see what you have, Mister Kim.\nKIM: There. It's registering only on subspace bands. We don't even have\nit on long range sensors yet.\nJANEWAY: Verteron emanations. Tunnelling secondary particles. It\ncertainly looks like a wormhole.\nCHAKOTAY: But is it stable enough for us to enter, and if it is, where\ndoes it lead?\nTUVOK: There is, of course, a seventy five percent chance the wormhole\nwill not lead to the Alpha Quadrant.\nJANEWAY: Very true. But you can also say there's a one in four chance\nit will. Those aren't bad odds. Any analysis yet, Ensign?\nKIM: Too far away. We'd have to be within a thousand kilometres to get\na detailed analysis. That would mean a significant course change.\nJANEWAY: Well, Mister Kim, if there's even the possibility of finding a\nwormhole, I think we can afford a detour. Lieutenant, input the\ncoordinates and change course.\nPARIS: Aye, Captain. And may I suggest, if this works, we petition the\nFederation Astronomical Committee to officially designate this the\nHarry Kim Wormhole.\n(Later.) \nPARIS: Captain, we're approaching the coordinates of the wormhole.\nJANEWAY: On screen. Are we in visual range?\nKIM: Affirmative, Captain, and the anomaly is still registering on\nsubspace bands.\nPARIS: Sensors also indicate it's there.\nJANEWAY: Magnify. Increase to highest magnification.\nCHAKOTAY: If that's a wormhole, it must be the smallest one on record.\nJANEWAY: Mister Kim, are you able to analyse it?\nKIM: Aye Captain. It's virtually microscopic. The aperture is only\nabout thirty centimetres in diameter.\nPARIS: I guess it's a little too small for us to fly through.\nTUVOK: However, it might be large enough to act as a conduit for a\nmessage.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[130, 140, "PER"], [228, 234, "LOC"], [239, 246, "PER"], [255, 260, "PER"], [265, 273, "PER"], [281, 294, "LOC"], [332, 342, "PER"], [721, 735, "LOC"], [857, 863, "PER"], [1017, 1027, "PER"], [1181, 1188, "PER"], [1240, 1273, "ORG"], [1705, 1715, "PER"], [1754, 1761, "PER"], [1466, 1473, "PER"], [1307, 1325, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 712, "text": "[Forest - night]\n\n(A pair of men with weapons are tracking something in the dark. They find it.)NAMON:\nDon't move.(It is Chakotay.) \n \n[Camp - night] \n(They bring him back to the camp with a gag over his mouth and hands tied behind his back..)BRONE:\nWhat's this? \nNAMON: We found him in the trunks, a hundred footfalls past Grove Yellow.\nBRONE: Arms? \nNAMON: None, sir. \nBRONE: These colours? \nNAMON: We didn't ask. \nBRONE: He's no Krady beast, is he? \nNAMON: No, sir, but he doesn't bear Vori colours either. \nBRONE: Hmm. His glimpse is too tame to be a Kradin. \nNAMON: I hadn't fathomed that, sir. \nBRONE: Well, fathom it now. He's no nemesis, is he? \nNAMON: I'm not certain what he is, sir. \nBRONE: Weren't you drilled to fathom the nemesis? \nNAMON: Yes, sir. \nBRONE: And we abhor none but the nemesis, do we? \nNAMON: No, sir. None but the nemesis! \nBRONE: Then set him loose. Didn't you hear, Novice?\nCHAKOTAY: Thanks. \nBRONE: Go take provisions.\nNAMON: I'm sorry, sir. \nBRONE: Go. \nCHAKOTAY: I take it you're in charge here. \nBRONE: Team Leader Brone, Fourth Vori Defence Contingent. \nCHAKOTAY: Commander Chakotay of the starship Voyager. \nBRONE: I'm very sorry for my defenders. They're new to the clash and\nglimpse the nemesis all around them. \nCHAKOTAY: The clash. You're at war? \nBRONE: You've strayed into the fullness of it. \nCHAKOTAY: That explains why my shuttle came under fire. \nBRONE: One of my defenders glimpsed a vessel falling in Grove Yellow.\nIt must have been yours. Why fly so close to this sphere? \nCHAKOTAY: I was on a survey mission. I picked up traces of omicron\nradiation in your atmosphere so I slowed down to take a look. As soon\nas I did that, I came under attack. I lost helm control and had to make\nan emergency transport to the surface. \nBRONE: It'll be the Kradin that fired at you.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 7, "LOC"], [121, 129, "PER"], [136, 140, "LOC"], [324, 336, "LOC"], [432, 443, "SPEC"], [489, 493, "SPEC"], [555, 561, "SPEC"], [897, 903, "PER"], [1038, 1055, "PER"], [1057, 1087, "ORG"], [1100, 1118, "PER"], [1126, 1142, "SHIP"], [1450, 1462, "LOC"], [1792, 1798, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 713, "text": "[Mess hall]\n\n(Rock\nand roll music is blaring from a jukebox. Neelix is handing out snacks.) \nTORRES: Now, these are delicious. \nKIM: Leave some for the rest of us. \nTORRES: Hey, I'm eating for two. \nPARIS: Great party, Neelix. \nNEELIX: Everybody seems to be enjoying it. \nPARIS: Yeah, except the Doc. \nNEELIX: Those are for eating, not scanning. \nEMH: What exactly are they? \nNEELIX: Cheese pirogues. Zefram Cochrane's favourite. \nEMH: They have absolutely no nutritional value. \nNEELIX: This is a party, Doctor. Sometimes you have to forget about\nnutrition. \nEMH: You could include a vitamin supplement when you replicate them. \nNEELIX: Replicate? I made them myself. \nJANEWAY: You two have outdone yourselves. I've never seen First Contact\nDay celebrated quite like this. When I was your age, all it meant was a\nday off from school. \nNAOMI: Neelix and I thought we should make it more fun. \nJANEWAY: Well, you certainly succeeded. \nNAOMI: When is Commander Tuvok making his presentation? \nNEELIX: Well, now's as good a time as any. Captain? (Neelix hands Janeway the tray of\nsnacks.)\nNEELIX: May I have everyone's attention, please? In honour of the three hundred\nand fifteenth anniversary of his ancestors' arrival on Earth, I've\nasked Mister Tuvok to recite the first words spoken to humans by a\nVulcan. Commander. \nTUVOK: Is this really necessary? \nNEELIX: You promised. \nTUVOK: Very well. Live long and prosper. (Applause.)\nNEELIX: And now, for some more of Zefram Cochrane's favourite music.\nHey, come on, Mister Vulcan. \nTUVOK: Vulcans do not dance. \nNEELIX: But it's tradition. \nTUVOK: There is no tradition, Mister Neelix. This ceremony is entirely\nyour invention.\nJANEWAY: This is an official ship function, Commander. Don't make me\norder you to dance. (Chakotay enters.)\nCHAKOTAY: Sorry to interrupt, but I've got some interesting news.\nNeelix, you might want to hear this. Long range sensors have detected", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 10, "LOC"], [61, 67, "PER"], [219, 225, "PER"], [296, 299, "PER"], [401, 416, "PER"], [949, 964, "PER"], [1034, 1041, "PER"], [1057, 1064, "PER"], [1044, 1050, "PER"], [1221, 1226, "LOC"], [1239, 1251, "PER"], [1300, 1306, "SPEC"], [1464, 1479, "PER"], [1536, 1543, "SPEC"], [1618, 1631, "PER"], [1765, 1773, "PER"], [1849, 1855, "PER"], [1719, 1728, "PER"]]}
{"id": 714, "text": "[Corridor]\n\n(Janeway's\nlong hair and bun is back.) \nPARIS [OC]: Paris to the Captain. \nJANEWAY: Janeway here. \nPARIS [OC]: I've done an analysis of our route through Botha space.\nWhenever you have a minute to check it out. \nJANEWAY: I'm on my way to Engineering. I'll be with you as soon as I'm\ndone. \nPARIS [OC]: Aye, Captain. \nNEELIX: Ah, Captain, the computer told me I'd find you on deck eleven\nsection four B, starboard side, and sure enough, here you are. \nJANEWAY: What can I do for you, Neelix? \nNEELIX: I assumed you'd want to talk to me. \nJANEWAY: About? \nNEELIX: About the Botha. We're headed for their space and as I've told\nyou, they're going to have to be handled very carefully. \nJANEWAY: I understand, and of course I want your counsel, but right now\nI'm late for a meeting. \nNEELIX: I wouldn't put this off too long. We're getting closer, you\nknow. \nJANEWAY: Yes, I know. And I will be with you as soon as I can.\n\n[Engineering]\n\nJANEWAY:\nSorry, I'm late. What do you have? \nTORRES: I think we're about ready to make our first attempt, Captain. \nJANEWAY: If you're successful, will the Doctor be able to move freely\naround the entire ship? \nKIM: Not exactly. The holoemitters would be set up in certain key\nareas, the Bridge, Engineering. We'll be able to transfer him to those\nlocations. \nJANEWAY: In the same way we can now transfer him to the holodeck. \nTORRES: Exactly. But if he tries to move into an area where there's no\nemitter field, he'll dematerialise. \nKIM: I have the holoprojector online. We're ready to start. \nJANEWAY: Proceed. I don't have much time. \nTORRES: Engineering to Sickbay. Doctor, we're ready here.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 9, "LOC"], [13, 20, "PER"], [64, 69, "PER"], [77, 84, "PER"], [96, 103, "PER"], [166, 171, "SPEC"], [250, 261, "ORG"], [319, 326, "PER"], [341, 348, "PER"], [387, 429, "LOC"], [495, 501, "PER"], [584, 589, "SPEC"], [1052, 1059, "PER"], [1102, 1108, "PER"], [1234, 1240, "LOC"], [1242, 1253, "LOC"], [1362, 1370, "LOC"], [1608, 1615, "LOC"], [1593, 1604, "LOC"], [1617, 1623, "PER"]]}
{"id": 715, "text": "[Sandrine's]\n\n NEELIX:\nHe hasn't left me with a single shot.\nGAUNT GARY: In that case, pal, call a safety.\nNEELIX: Safety?\nPARIS: it's a defensive strategy. Since you can't make a shot, the idea\nis to leave the cue ball somewhere on the table where Tuvok can't make\na shot either.\nNEELIX: Oh, I don't know. It sounds cowardly.\nGAUNT GARY: Suit yourself pal, but if you leave Vulcan Slim over here\nwith an open shot he's got a very good chance of running the table.\nNEELIX: All right. Safety. \n(Neelix sends the cue ball round two bumpers without touching another\nball. That'd be a foul stroke in snooker.) \nNEELIX: Ah ha ha! Mister Vulcan, let's see you reason your way out of\nthis conundrum. This safety business is a lot more satisfying than I\nimagined. I've left him with an impossible shot.\nTUVOK: The shot may be difficult, Mister Neelix, but to say that it is\nimpossible is an exaggeration.\nNEELIX: Go ahead then. Call your shot.\nTUVOK: Logic would dictate that if I strike the cue ball properly, it\nwill deflect first off the rear bumper, then the side, striking the\neleven ball and causing it to roll directly into the corner pocket.\nPARIS: This I have to see.\n(The cue ball hits the rear bumper and drops into the pocket.) \nTUVOK: Perhaps the ship's stabilisers are not operating at peak\nefficiency.\nGAUNT GARY: Yeah, and maybe Tom Terrific over here forgot to tell you\nthat Sandrine's table rolls a little to the east.\nNEELIX: You should have called a safety.\nJANEWAY [OC]: Janeway to Mister Neelix. Please report to the bridge. \n [Bridge]\n\n NEELIX:\nYou wanted to see me, Captain.\nJANEWAY: Yes, Neelix. We've received a subspace message from an\napproaching vessel. They're asking for you.\nNEELIX: Me?\nKIM: The alien ship is entering visual range, Captain.\nJANEWAY: Slow to impulse. On screen. Do you recognise it?\nNEELIX: That's a Haarkonian shuttle.\nCHAKOTAY: Haarkonian?", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 11, "LOC"], [249, 254, "PER"], [375, 386, "PER"], [494, 500, "PER"], [625, 638, "PER"], [829, 842, "PER"], [1337, 1349, "PER"], [1384, 1394, "LOC"], [1484, 1491, "PER"], [1495, 1508, "PER"], [1531, 1537, "LOC"], [1542, 1548, "LOC"], [1582, 1589, "PER"], [1605, 1611, "PER"], [1841, 1851, "SPEC"], [1871, 1881, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 716, "text": "[Sisko's\nquarters]\n\n(Jake is loading up a suitcase.) \nSISKO: Don't you think you might be overpacking? \nJAKE: It'll close. \nSISKO: You don't have to take everything at once. It's not like you're\nmoving to Bajor. One G twelve is practically right next door. \nJAKE: I know, but I'm not moving to one G twelve. I found some great\nquarters over in section M. \nSISKO: That's all the way on the other side of the habitat ring. \nJAKE: Dad, don't get all sentimental on me. \nSISKO: Wait until your son moves out on you. \nJAKE: I don't have a son. \nSISKO: Ha, ha. Go ahead, Jake, make jokes. One day you'll be standing\nwhere I am, and believe me, you won't like it any more than I do. \nJAKE: Yeah, maybe, but right now I'm standing here and I can't wait to\nspend my first night in my own place. \n(Slams the case shut.) \nJAKE: See? I told you it'd close. \nSISKO: Now wait, wait, let me get this straight. I can visit any time I\nwant, but I have to call first. You won't be available for breakfast or\nlunch, but I can count on one dinner a week. \nJAKE: Yeah, well some weeks maybe even two. \nSISKO: Ah. I have raised a very generous son. You and Nog moving in\ntogether. I can remember when I didn't even want you talking to him. \nJAKE: Yeah, well, things change. \nSISKO: They sure do.\n\n [Rom's quarters]\n\n(Rom is arranging the room just so when the\ndoorbell rings.) \nROM: Come in. \n(Quark enters with two trays of bottles.) \nROM: Oh. It's you? \nQUARK: Who'd you think it was? \nROM: Nog. \nQUARK: How could it be Nog? His ship hasn't even docked yet. \nROM: I guess I wasn't thinking. \nQUARK: What else is new?", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 17, "LOC"], [21, 25, "PER"], [205, 210, "LOC"], [212, 224, "LOC"], [294, 306, "LOC"], [344, 353, "LOC"], [407, 419, "LOC"], [1135, 1138, "PER"], [1277, 1291, "LOC"], [1295, 1298, "PER"], [1372, 1377, "PER"], [1471, 1474, "PER"], [1500, 1503, "PER"]]}
{"id": 717, "text": "Captain's log, stardate 51145.3. The Defiant has been operating out of\nStarbase three seven five, conducting forays into Dominion controlled\nspace. While the missions have taken a toll on my people, they remain\ndetermined to do whatever it takes to win this war, as do I. \n [Mess hall]\n\n(Nog is running an impromptu bar) \nNOG: Here you are. \nSISKO: Where did you get your hands on Saurian Brandy? \nBASHIR: In the middle of a war, no less. \nNOG: It's a busy Starbase. I may be a Cadet, but I'm still a Ferengi. \nDAX: Lucky for us. \n(O'Brien enters with a metre long canister.) \nO'BRIEN: Excuse me, Captain. The power cell from the phaser array. We\nused it up on the last mission. \n(Sisko takes the canister.) \nSISKO: Take a good look at this, people. It says something about this\nship. It says that we will fight and we will keep on fighting until we\ncan't fight anymore. \nALL: Yes, sir! \nSISKO: You don't just throw something like this away. \nALL: No, sir! \n(Sisko places it against the bulkhead, on some pipework, with six other\ncanisters. Cheers and applause.) \nNOG: Admiral on deck. \nROSS: As you were. Ben. \nSISKO: Admiral. \nROSS: Let's take a walk.\n\n [Defiant corridor]\n\nROSS: What was going on in there? \nSISKO: Just a little ritual we fell into. Kind of helps the crew\nunwind. \nROSS: Well, they deserve it. They did a hell of a job. \nSISKO: Thank you, sir. But you didn't come here to tell me that, did\nyou? \nROSS: No, I didn't. Ever since this war began, the Dominion's been able\nto outmanoeuvre us at every turn. No matter where we send our ships,", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[33, 44, "SPEC"], [71, 96, "LOC"], [121, 129, "GPE"], [275, 284, "LOC"], [288, 291, "PER"], [457, 465, "LOC"], [501, 508, "SPEC"], [532, 539, "PER"], [597, 604, "PER"], [1106, 1109, "PER"], [1119, 1126, "PER"], [1157, 1173, "LOC"], [1467, 1475, "GPE"]]}
{"id": 718, "text": "[Wardroom]\n\nSISKO: The Dominion has solidified its hold on the\nKalandra Sector. They're trying to establish a supply line running\nthrough Betazoid space into the Argolis\nCluster. \nWORF: If they succeed, they will be able to launch an attack against\nVulcan. \nSISKO: Starfleet's going to try to cut them off near the Tibor Nebula.\nThe Seventh Fleet will be engaging the enemy in the morning. \nDAX: The Seventh Fleet is still at half-strength. They took heavy\nlosses at Sybaron. \nSISKO: Well let's just hope they can get the job done. On a happier\nnote, I do have a bit of good news. \nBASHIR: That makes a welcome change. \nSISKO: The Romulans have forced the Dominion to retreat from the\nBenzite system. \nODO: That is good news. The question is, will the Romulans be willing\nto leave Benzar after the war is over? Once they capture territory,\nthey very rarely give it up. \nSISKO: Right now, we need to concentrate on beating the Dominion. We'll\nworry about the Romulans later. As some of you already know, Major\nKira, Jake and I will be leaving for Bajor at twenty two hundred. \nDAX: There's a war on. This is no time for a vacation. \nKIRA: The archaeologists excavating B'hala have found something they\nwant the Emissary to see. \nSISKO: We'll be returning tomorrow night. That's all, people. \n(Everyone leaves except Kira and Odo.) \nKIRA: Will the Romulans leave Benzar? You love to bring up the\nworst-case scenario in these meetings, don't you? \nODO: Somebody has to. Besides, everyone expects me to be dour and\nsuspicious. I don't want to disappoint them.\nKIRA: If they only knew the real you. \nODO: That is the real me. At least as far as everyone else is\nconcerned.\n\n[Tunnel]\n\nKORAL: (a monk) I can't tell you how pleased we are\nby your visit, Emissary. \nSISKO: Glad to be here, Ranjen.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 9, "LOC"], [23, 31, "GPE"], [63, 78, "LOC"], [138, 146, "SPEC"], [162, 177, "LOC"], [249, 255, "LOC"], [265, 274, "ORG"], [315, 327, "LOC"], [329, 346, "ORG"], [396, 413, "ORG"], [467, 474, "LOC"], [656, 664, "GPE"], [685, 699, "LOC"], [631, 639, "SPEC"], [752, 760, "SPEC"], [781, 787, "LOC"], [926, 934, "LOC"], [958, 966, "SPEC"], [1003, 1013, "PER"], [1015, 1019, "PER"], [1046, 1051, "LOC"], [1168, 1174, "LOC"], [1210, 1218, "PER"], [1315, 1319, "PER"], [1324, 1327, "PER"], [1346, 1354, "SPEC"], [1361, 1367, "LOC"], [1670, 1676, "LOC"], [1746, 1754, "PER"], [1781, 1787, "PER"]]}
{"id": 719, "text": "[Runabout\nRio Grande]\n\nKIRA: I've never seen anything like that. \nBASHIR: Hmm? \nKIRA: I've never seen anything like that. \nBASHIR: The woman? \nKIRA: She was dead. The tricorder clearly showed \nBASHIR: Ah yes, well, tricorders. Very accurate with live people, not\nso accurate with dead ones. We learn that first year medical school. \nKIRA: Well, I was very impressed, Doctor. \nBASHIR: And well you should have been. I impressed myself on this one\nactually. I can't imagine what other doctor would even consider\nexamining the scapular nodes for parasitic infection. I just seem to\nhave a talent, I suppose. A vision that sees past the obvious, around\nthe mundane, right to the target. Fate has granted me a gift, Major. A\ngift to be a healer. \nKIRA: I feel privileged to be in your presence. \nBASHIR: Glad to have you along. \nKIRA: Did anyone ever tell you that you're \nCOMPUTER: Priority one broad band distress signal. \nKAJADA [OC]: Kobliad transport Reyab to any ship. Our central power\nlinkage exploded. We're losing life support. Please respond. \nBASHIR: Just picking it up on long range sensors. Bearing three four\nseven mark zero eight. \nKIRA: I'm reading massive energy leakage. Its aft structural integrity\nfield is failing. This is the Federation Ship Rio Grande. We're on our\nway.\n\n[Kobliad transport]\n\n(Kira and Bashir beam into a smoky corridor.) \nBASHIR: O-2 pressure dropping rapidly. Toxic gas levels are rising.\nWe've got no more than ten minutes breathing time left in here. \nKIRA: Automatic fire suppression must be offline. I'll check the\ncentral power linkage. \n(Bashir sees to a woman lying on the floor.) \nBASHIR: Relax. I'm a doctor. \nKAJADA: What happened? \nBASHIR: You lost consciousness. Now listen, is there anyone else aboard\nyour ship? We've got to evacuate it.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 20, "LOC"], [367, 373, "PER"], [1244, 1270, "SHIP"], [933, 956, "SHIP"], [1292, 1309, "SHIP"], [1313, 1317, "PER"], [1322, 1328, "PER"]]}
{"id": 720, "text": "Station\nLog, stardate 46925.1. We have been honoured with a visit by a\ndelegation of Federation ambassadors on a fact-finding mission to the\nwormhole. Fortunately I have just the officer to take them off my\nhands.\n\n [Quark's] \nBASHIR: I only wish there was something I could do,\nAmbassador. \nTAXCO: (alien red-head) Madam Ambassador. \nBASHIR: Madam Ambassador. But all the guest quarters on the station are\nroughly the same size. \nTAXCO: Then move me to the crew level. \nBASHIR: All the quarters on the crew level are currently occupied. \nTAXCO: Then someone can move. You, for example. \nVADOSIA: (Bolian) She did the same thing during the voyage here. She's\nnever satisfied. \nTAXCO: At least I didn't bother the Captain every hour with some new\nsuggestion on how to run his ship. \nVADOSIA: He welcomed my suggestions, as I'm sure your Commander Sisko\nwill welcome them. If we ever get to spend any time with him. \nBASHIR: Commander Sisko is extremely busy. \nVADOSIA: With what? \nBASHIR: With the recalibration sweep. \nLOJAL: (Vulcan) What are you recalibrating? \nBASHIR: Everything. It's a sweeping recalibration of all systems. \nLOJAL: I cannot speak for the others, but I would be fascinated to\nobserve this recalibration, Doctor. \nBASHIR: You would? After your long trip, I thought you might enjoy\nstopping by a holosuite? \nTAXCO: Are you actually suggesting we indulge in one of those\ndisgusting Ferengi sex programmes? \nBASHIR: No. I, the holosuites are capable of many different \nVADOSIA: Of course that was what he was suggesting. The Arbazan are so\nsexually repressed. \nTAXCO: Why, this is outrageous. \nBASHIR: Perhaps we should all just get some rest. \nLOJAL: I did not come all this way to rest, Doctor. I would like to see\nyour facility. \nTAXCO: A first-year officer assigned as our liaison. Starfleet command\nwill hear of this.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[217, 224, "LOC"], [141, 149, "LOC"], [279, 289, "PER"], [343, 359, "PER"], [598, 604, "SPEC"], [713, 720, "PER"], [836, 851, "PER"], [923, 938, "PER"], [1027, 1033, "SPEC"], [1401, 1408, "SPEC"], [1543, 1550, "SPEC"], [1707, 1713, "PER"], [1804, 1821, "ORG"]]}
{"id": 721, "text": "Last\ntime on Star Trek Deep Space Nine \n SISKO: If you could do any science project you\nwanted to, anything at all? \nJAKE: Visit the Gamma Quadrant? \n(They meet Eris, who knocks Sisko down with an energy ball before the\nJem'Hadar take Sisko and Quark prisoner.) \nQUARK: We've never heard of the Jem'Hadar. \nERIS: Then you've been fortunate. Negotiations with the Dominion can be\na dangerous thing. \nTALAK'TALAN: The Dominion will no longer stand by and allow ships from\nyour side to violate our territory. \nKEOGH: Starfleet's orders are simple. Traffic through the wormhole will\nbe suspended until the Odyssey can investigate the Jem'Hadar's threat. \nDAX: What about Benjamin and the others? \nKEOGH: Don't worry, Lieutenant. Commander Sisko's return is a top\npriority. \nDAX: If you're going to try to rescue them, then we're coming with you.\n\n(Eris takes down the security field. Sisko kills a Jem'Hadar.) \nKIRA: Here they come. \nBASHIR: Major, one of the Jem'Hadar ships is making a direct run at the\nOdyssey. \n(KaBOOM) \nSISKO: The Jem'Hadar wanted us to escape, didn't they? \nERIS: You have no idea what's begun here. \n(Eris taps her cuff and beams out) \nKIRA: She'll be back. The question is who she'll bring with her? \nSISKO: If the Dominion comes through the wormhole the first battle will\nbe fought here, and I intend to be ready for them. \n And now, the continuation.\n\n [Ops]\n\nKIRA: We're in trouble, people. We've run seven\nsimulations, and they all come out the same. The Jem'Hadar overwhelm\nour defences and board the station within two hours. \nBASHIR: Two hours doesn't even give us time to get reinforcements from\nBajor. \nDAX: There must be something we overlooked.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[133, 147, "LOC"], [161, 165, "PER"], [178, 183, "PER"], [220, 229, "SPEC"], [295, 304, "SPEC"], [235, 240, "PER"], [245, 250, "PER"], [363, 371, "GPE"], [416, 424, "GPE"], [514, 523, "ORG"], [565, 573, "LOC"], [602, 609, "SPEC"], [630, 639, "SPEC"], [667, 675, "PER"], [713, 723, "PER"], [725, 740, "PER"], [844, 848, "PER"], [880, 885, "PER"], [894, 903, "SPEC"], [1002, 1009, "SPEC"], [1033, 1042, "SPEC"], [1122, 1126, "PER"], [1237, 1245, "GPE"], [1378, 1381, "LOC"], [1481, 1490, "SPEC"], [1626, 1631, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 722, "text": "[Infirmary]\n\n(Kira is sitting on a bed getting her jabs.) \nKIRA: Is all this really necessary? \nBASHIR: The Klingon invasion has all but destroyed the Cardassian\nhealth system. They're suffering outbreaks of all kinds of diseases and\nin epidemic proportions. Besides, you've only got twelve more\ninoculations to go. \nKIRA: Twelve? \nBASHIR: Sorry, but if you want to go to the conference. \nKIRA: I don't want to go. I'm no diplomat. Going to some obscure\nCardassian outpost to share Bajoran intelligence about the Klingons\nisn't exactly something I'm good at. I don't know why I even agreed to\ngo in the first place. \nBASHIR: You agreed to go because it was a personal request from the\nFirst Minister of Bajor. \nKIRA: Oh, it was a personal request all right. Shakaar took me to my\nfavourite restaurant in Jalanda City, poured me glass after glass of\nspring wine, then took me to his home, and gave me a massage with\nKolaish spice oil. \nBASHIR: Well, nice to know he's keeping in touch with his constituents.\n\nKIRA: It wasn't fair. I mean, I would have said yes to anything at that\npoint. \n(Kira gasps and lies down on the bed.)\nBASHIR: What is it? \nKIRA: I'm seeing spots. \nBASHIR: Big green, swirling ones? \nKIRA: The size of Alvinian melons. \nBASHIR: And is the room beginning to spin? \nKIRA: Yes. \nBASHIR: Good. It means the vaccine's beginning to work. Everything'll\nsettle down in a moment. \nWORF: Major, may I speak with you? \nKIRA: I'm not going anywhere. \nBASHIR: This one might make you a little queasy. If you have something\nto say to the major, you'd better make it fast. \nWORF: The Federation has some concerns about your upcoming meeting with\nthe Cardassians. \nKIRA: So do I.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 10, "LOC"], [14, 18, "PER"], [108, 115, "SPEC"], [151, 161, "SPEC"], [454, 464, "SPEC"], [482, 489, "SPEC"], [513, 521, "SPEC"], [758, 765, "PER"], [804, 816, "LOC"], [685, 708, "PER"], [1089, 1093, "PER"], [1593, 1603, "GPE"], [1659, 1670, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 723, "text": "First\nOfficer's log, stardate 48521.5. Odo and I are returning to Deep Space\nNine after reviewing security procedures at Prophet's Landing, the\nBajoran Colony closest to the Cardassian Border.\n\n [Runabout Mekong]\n\nKIRA: Those orbital sensor platforms should give\nthe colonists plenty of advanced warning in case the Cardassians ever\ndecide to violate the new treaty. \nODO: Hopefully. \nKIRA: How did your meeting with Security Chief Bemar go? \nODO: Fine. \nKIRA: Was he properly impressed by the depth of your expertise? \nODO: Huh. \nKIRA: Odo, is something bothering you? \nODO: What makes you say that? \nKIRA: Well for one thing, you haven't said five words to me since we\nleft Prophet's Landing. \nODO: Huh. \nKIRA: Look, if I've done something to offend you, I wish you'd tell me\nwhat it is. \nODO: It's not important. \nKIRA: Whatever you say. \nODO: It's certainly not worth making an issue about. \nKIRA: Well, glad to hear it. \nODO: It's just (pause) When Governor Avesta invited us to dinner at his\nhouse \nKIRA: Go on. \nODO: You said no. \nKIRA: And? \nODO: You never bothered to ask me if I wanted to go. \nKIRA: You wanted to go to the governor's house for dinner? \nODO: Not particularly. \nKIRA: Well then, what's the problem? \nODO: The problem is you never asked what I wanted. \nKIRA: Odo, you don't eat. Besides, you hate socialising with people you\ndon't know. \nODO: Well that's beside the point. I would have liked to have been\nconsulted, that's all. \nKIRA: You're right. Next time we are invited out for dinner, I'll make", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[39, 42, "PER"], [66, 81, "LOC"], [121, 138, "LOC"], [174, 191, "LOC"], [196, 211, "SHIP"], [316, 327, "SPEC"], [417, 437, "PER"], [537, 540, "PER"], [676, 693, "LOC"], [954, 969, "PER"], [1284, 1287, "PER"]]}
{"id": 724, "text": "[Transporter\nroom] \nBERKELEY: Ready to beam down. Energise. Energise.\nKIRK: Having trouble, gentlemen?\nBERKELEY: I just don't understand the problem, sir.\nKIRK: You're beaming cargo down to a penal colony, Mister Berkeley.\nBERKELEY: Their security force field, sir.\nKIRK: U.S.S. Enterprise to Tantalus colony.\nWOMAN [OC]: Rehab colony. Come in.\nKIRK: Request opening in your force field for beaming down of cargo.\nWOMAN [OC]: Enterprise, affirmative. Our security cover is now open.\nKIRK: Energise. Any incoming cargo?\nBERKELEY: Just one item, sir. Some research material bound for the\nCentral Bureau of Penology at Stockholm.\nWOMAN [OC]: Tantalus cargo ready to beam up.\nKIRK: Oh, Mister Berkeley, you might refamiliarise yourself with the\nmanual on penal colony procedures.\nBERKELEY: Immediately, sir.\nKIRK: I think you can take the time to lock this up first.\nBERKELEY: I'll get a vault assignment. (leaves. The box opens, a man\nclimbs out and attacks the technician)\n\nCaptain's log, stardate 2715.1. Exchanged cargo\nwith penal colony on Tantalus V. I've departed without going ashore. \n[Bridge]\n\nKIRK: I would like to have met Doctor Adams. Have\nyou ever been to a penal colony since they started following his\ntheories?\nMCCOY: A cage is a cage, Jim.\nKIRK: You're behind the times, Bones. They're more like resort colonies\nnow.\nUHURA: Message, Captain. Switching to speaker.\nWOMAN [OC]: Tantalus colony to Enterprise. We are unable to locate one\nof our inmates. This is a potentially violent case. Possibly hidden in\nthe box we beamed up to you. Repeat, unable to locate one of our\ninmates. This is a potentially violent case.\nKIRK: Enterprise acknowledging. Stand by. Security alert three.\nUHURA: Security alert, condition three. All sections go to alert", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 17, "LOC"], [206, 221, "PER"], [293, 308, "LOC"], [322, 334, "LOC"], [426, 436, "SHIP"], [272, 289, "SHIP"], [586, 625, "ORG"], [639, 647, "LOC"], [682, 697, "PER"], [1041, 1051, "LOC"], [1091, 1097, "LOC"], [1131, 1143, "PER"], [1348, 1355, "PER"], [1286, 1291, "PER"], [1391, 1406, "LOC"], [1410, 1420, "SHIP"], [1637, 1647, "SHIP"]]}
{"id": 725, "text": "[Bridge]\n\n SULU: Approaching planet Omega Four, sir. Object\nahead. Another vessel in planet orbit, Captain. \nKIRK: Lieutenant, sound alert. \nUHURA: Aye, sir. All decks report ready, sir. \nKIRK: Long range sensor scan, Mister Sulu. \nSULU: It's the USS Exeter, sir. \nKIRK: Try to contact her, Lieutenant. \nUHURA: Aye, sir. \nKIRK: The Exeter. she was patrolling in this area six months ago. I\nhadn't heard of any trouble. \nUHURA: Receiving no response to our signal, sir. \nSULU: The sensors indicate no damage to the vessel, Captain. \nKIRK: I see. Magnification factor three, Mister Sulu. \n(The viewscreen shows a sister ship to the Enterprise orbiting the\npurple planet.) \nKIRK: Hold our position out here, Mister Sulu. Lieutenant, have Mister\nSpock, Doctor McCoy, and Lieutenant Galloway report to the transporter\nroom. We'll board and investigate.\n\n[Transporter room]\n\nSPOCK: We're locked onto the Exeter's engineering\nsection, Captain. \nKIRK: Phasers on heavy stun. Energise.\n\n[Exeter Engineering]\n\n(It's dark and quiet.) \nSPOCK: Captain. \n(There's a red jacket draped across a console, with white crystals\nscattered in and around it.) \nKIRK: Just their uniforms left. \nSPOCK: As if they were in them when \nKIRK: Exactly. When what? \n(McCoy scans the white crystals.) \nKIRK: This is Captain Kirk of the USS Enterprise. Is anyone on board?\nIf there is, and you can hear me, please respond by intercom to the\nengineering section. Is there anyone on board? \nSPOCK [OC]: Spock here, Captain.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[36, 46, "LOC"], [99, 106, "PER"], [1, 7, "LOC"], [115, 125, "PER"], [218, 229, "PER"], [247, 257, "SHIP"], [328, 338, "SHIP"], [573, 584, "PER"], [630, 640, "SHIP"], [705, 716, "PER"], [735, 747, "PER"], [749, 761, "PER"], [767, 786, "PER"], [850, 866, "LOC"], [801, 817, "LOC"], [894, 926, "LOC"], [979, 997, "LOC"], [1031, 1038, "PER"], [1236, 1241, "PER"], [1284, 1296, "PER"], [1304, 1318, "SHIP"], [1408, 1427, "LOC"], [1480, 1487, "PER"], [1468, 1473, "PER"], [522, 529, "PER"], [291, 301, "PER"], [718, 728, "PER"], [928, 935, "PER"]]}
{"id": 726, "text": "Captain's log, stardate 5591.2. The crew of the Enterprise is ready for\nsome well-deserved rest and recreation. Therefore we have set course\nfor the so-called 'shore leave planet', located in the Omicron Delta\nregion. The uninhabited planet was constructed long ago by a highly\nadvanced alien race. Its sole purpose is to provide fun and amusement\nfor space travelling passers-by. \n [Planet surface] \n MCCOY: Yes, just as beautiful as I remembered it.\nNothing's changed. \nSULU: This looks like the same spot we beamed down on on  our first visit. Remember, Doctor,\nwhen we saw the White Rabbit? \nMCCOY: Yes, and all because I said this place made me feel like Alice\nin Wonderland. \nRABBIT: One side! One side! I'm late! I'm late! Oh, my fuzzy ears and\nwhiskers, I'm late! \n(And the white rabbit in waistcoat and jacket bounds across the meadow,\nfollowed by) \nALICE: I beg your pardon, but did you see a white rabbit? \nUHURA: He went that way, Alice. \nALICE: Thank you so very much. \nSULU: Like you said, Doctor, nothing's changed. \nUHURA: It's hard to believe they're not real. \nMCCOY: Well just remember they're highly sophisticated robots created\nby the planet computer to make your dreams come true. \nUHURA: So think only happy thoughts. \nMCCOY: My prescription exactly. \n(So, Uhura finds a mirror-like lake to sit by, gazing at her reflection\nand humming to herself, while Sulu walks in the woods, and McCoy gazes\nat a colonial house with formal gardens) \nMCCOY: Lovely. They just don't make them like that anymore. \nQUEEN: Off with his head. Off with his head! \nMCCOY: Hey, what's going on here. \n(One of the Jack playing cards throws his lance) \nQUEEN: Stop him! \n(McCoy runs) \nMCCOY: Enterprise! Emergency! Beam up! \n [Transporter room] \n MCCOY [OC]: Beam up! \n(Scott works the controls)", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[48, 58, "SHIP"], [196, 216, "LOC"], [384, 398, "LOC"], [660, 679, "PER"], [557, 563, "PER"], [581, 593, "PER"], [943, 948, "PER"], [1004, 1010, "PER"], [1280, 1285, "PER"], [1377, 1381, "PER"], [1406, 1411, "PER"], [1671, 1676, "PER"], [1726, 1742, "LOC"], [1769, 1774, "PER"]]}
{"id": 727, "text": "Captain's log, stardate 5843.7. The Enterprise is in the grip of a\nraging epidemic. Three crewmen have died and twenty three others have\nbeen struck down by Rigelian fever. In order to combat the illness,\nDoctor McCoy needs large quantities of ryetalyn,\nwhich is the only known antidote for the fever. Our sensors have picked\nup sufficient quantities of pure ryetalyn on a small planet in the\nOmega system. We are beaming down to secure this urgently needed\nmaterial.\n\n[Planet surface]\n\n(Compared to the lurid red, purple and vivid blue\nof the planet from space, the ground is pretty normal) \nKIRK: Report. \nMCCOY: Jim, there's a large deposit bearing two seven three, four\nkilometres away. I've got four hours to process that stuff, otherwise\nthe epidemic will be irreversible. Everybody on board the Enterprise\nwill \nSPOCK: Strange. Readings indicate a life form in the vicinity,\napparently human. Yet ship's sensors indicated this planet was\nuninhabited. \nKIRK: Let's get that ryetalyn. \n(A strange device comes travelling through the air towards them. A bit\nlike Nomad, but much smaller and with more round bits. It fires an\nenergy beam at the landing party's feet. They try to fire their\nphasers.) \nKIRK: Inoperative. \n(The device fires again, and closes in.) \nFLINT: Do not kill. \n(The device backs away and a silver-haired man in sort of doublet and\nhose approaches) \nKIRK: I'm Captain James Kirk \nFLINT: I know who you are. I have monitored your ship since it entered\nthis system. \nKIRK: Then if you know who we are, you know why we're here, Mister? \nFLINT: Flint. You will leave my planet. \nSPOCK: Did you say your planet, sir? \nFLINT: My retreat from the unpleasantness of life on Earth, and the\ncompany of people.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[36, 46, "SHIP"], [205, 217, "PER"], [393, 405, "LOC"], [470, 484, "LOC"], [802, 812, "SHIP"], [1385, 1403, "PER"], [1550, 1556, "PER"], [1566, 1571, "PER"], [1691, 1696, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 728, "text": "Captain's Log: Stardate 4372.5. On a top-secret diplomatic mission, the\nEnterprise has entered the Tellun star system.\nMaintaining communications blackout, we have taken aboard Petri,\nAmbassador from Troyius, the outer planet, and are now approaching the\ninner planet Elas.\n\n[Turbolift]\n\nKIRK: Some desk-bound Starfleet bureaucrat cut\nthese cloak-and-dagger orders. \nSCOTT: Aye, but why the secrecy? This star system's under Federation\ncontrol. \nSPOCK: It's in a border area, Mister Scott. The Klingons also claim\njurisdiction. \nSCOTT: From what I've seen, it's not worth fighting about. Why are we\nhere, Captain? \nKIRK: My orders are to co-operate with Ambassador Petri in all matters\npertaining to his mission here. \nUHURA [OC]: Bridge to Captain Kirk. \nKIRK: Scotty. (Scott presses the intercom button) Kirk here. What is\nit? \nUHURA [OC]: Captain, I have a signal from the Elasians. They're ready\nto beam aboard, and they demand an explanation for the delay. \nKIRK: Demand? What delay? All right. Beam them aboard. \nSPOCK: Sounds typical of the Elasians. The scientists who made the\ninitial investigation reported the men were vicious and arrogant. \nMCCOY: That's just the negative part, Mister Spock. I've been over\nthose records. Now the women, they're supposed to be something very\nspecial. They're supposed to have a kind of subtle, mystical power that\ndrives men wild. \n[Corridor]\n\n(The Ambassador is a skinny humanoid with orange\nhair and grass green skin.) \nKIRK: Ambassador Petri, would you drop all this nonsense and tell me\nwhat this is about? \nPETRI: That must wait until the Dohlman is aboard. \nKIRK: Dohlman? What the devil is a Dohlman? \n[Transporter room]", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[72, 82, "SHIP"], [99, 117, "LOC"], [177, 182, "PER"], [200, 207, "LOC"], [268, 272, "LOC"], [276, 285, "LOC"], [310, 319, "ORG"], [425, 435, "GPE"], [476, 488, "PER"], [494, 502, "SPEC"], [654, 670, "PER"], [731, 737, "LOC"], [741, 753, "PER"], [762, 768, "PER"], [771, 776, "PER"], [806, 810, "PER"], [842, 849, "PER"], [876, 884, "SPEC"], [605, 612, "PER"], [1048, 1056, "SPEC"], [1191, 1203, "PER"], [1379, 1387, "LOC"], [1391, 1405, "PER"], [1474, 1490, "PER"], [1590, 1597, "PER"]]}
{"id": 729, "text": "Captain's log, stardate 44932.3 The Enterprise is preparing to enter\nthe Mar Oscura, an unexplored dark matter nebula. Commander Data is\nmodifying several new photon torpedoes for an experiment designed to\nelicit more information about this unusual phenomenon.\n\n[Torpedo bay]\n\nDATA: The initial dispersal pattern should not be\nmore than seven kilometres in diameter. Jenna? \nJENNA: Oh, er, six point eight kilometres. \nDATA: That should suffice. Is there something occupying your thoughts,\nJenna? You seem somewhat subdued today. \nJENNA: I bumped into Jeff again in the turbolift this morning. He asked\nme to dinner. \nDATA: What was your response? \nJENNA: I told him I'd think about it. \nDATA: As you requested, I will now remind you of the reasons you\ndecided to end your relationship with Jeff. \nJENNA: I guess I asked for this. Go ahead. \nDATA: You objected to the fact that he seemed unwilling to set aside\nsufficient time for you. You said he was unresponsive, that he never\ndid the little things. You disliked the sound he made when he ate his\nsoup. \nJENNA: Okay, okay. I remember. \nDATA: This is the third time I have refreshed your memory. Do you wish\nto rescind our agreement? \nJENNA: No. No, it's for my own good. It's just so easy to forget. Hand\nme the sequencer. \nDATA: Throughout history, many lovers have suffered the same\ndifficulty. Anne Boleyn was quite distressed that Henry the Eighth\npreferred the company of his huntsmen over that of his wife. \nJENNA: Since when did you develop an interest in romantic historical\nfigures? \nDATA: Six weeks ago, when you and Jeff dissolved your relationship, I\nsaw an excellent opportunity to study that aspect of human intimacy. As\nyour friend, it is my responsibility to be supportive in times of need.\n\nJENNA: That's very sweet, Data. \nDATA: Data to Bridge. We are ready \n[Bridge]", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[32, 46, "SHIP"], [73, 83, "LOC"], [119, 133, "PER"], [263, 274, "LOC"], [367, 372, "PER"], [490, 495, "PER"], [552, 556, "PER"], [791, 795, "PER"], [1350, 1361, "PER"], [1388, 1404, "PER"], [1580, 1584, "PER"], [1787, 1791, "PER"], [1800, 1804, "PER"], [1808, 1814, "LOC"], [1831, 1837, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 730, "text": "Captain's log, Stardate 43539.1. We have moved into orbit around Bre'el\nFour. With the assistance of the planet's emergency control centre,\nwe're investigating a potentially catastrophic threat to the population\nfrom a descending asteroidal moon. \n[Bridge]\n\nDATA: The satellite's trajectory is continuing to\ndeteriorate, Captain. This orbit will put it within five hundred\nkilometres of the planet surface. \nGARIN [on viewscreen]: We're predicting the atmospheric drag will bring\nit down on the next orbit. \nSCIENTIST [on viewscreen]: Have you been able to find any explanation\nfor this? \nDATA: No, Doctor. It is a most unusual phenomenon. \nPICARD: Won't the moon disintegrate prior to impact? \nSCIENTIST [on viewscreen]: No, it has a ferrous crystalline structure\nand it will be able to withstand tidal forces, Captain \nRIKER: Could we blow it into pieces? \nDATA: The total mass of the moon would remain the same, Commander, and\nthe impact of thousands of fragments would spread destruction over an\neven wider area. \nPICARD: How long before impact? \nDATA: Twenty nine hours, sir. Projecting it somewhere on the western\ncontinent. That\nwould destroy an area eight hundred kilometres in radius. \nSCIENTIST [on viewscreen]: That damage would be insignificant, Captain,\ncompared to the seismic repercussions massive landquakes, and tsunami. \nGARIN [on viewscreen]: The force would raise a cloud of dust around the\nplanet, leading to a significant temperature reduction. We could be\nlooking at our own ice age. \nPICARD: Mister La Forge, is there any way that the Enterprise could\ncoax that satellite \n[Engineering]\n\nPICARD [OC]: Back where it belongs? \nLAFORGE: We'd need to apply a delta vee of about four kilometres per\nsecond. Even with warp power to the tractor beam, it would mean\nexceeding recommended impulse engine output by at least forty-seven\npercent. It'd be like \n[Bridge]", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[65, 76, "LOC"], [321, 328, "PER"], [599, 605, "PER"], [812, 819, "PER"], [249, 255, "LOC"], [915, 924, "PER"], [1258, 1265, "PER"], [1516, 1531, "PER"], [1559, 1569, "SHIP"], [1598, 1609, "LOC"], [1874, 1880, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 731, "text": "Captain's log, Stardate 43872.2. In order to neutralise a sudden\ncontamination of the water supply at the Federation colony on Beta Agni\nTwo, we are procuring one hundred and eight kilos of hytritium from the\nZibalian trader, Kivas Fajo. Because pure hytritium is too unstable for\nour transporters, Lieutenant Commander Data has been shuttling the\nmaterial to the Enterprise.\n\n[Jovis Cargo bay]\n\nDATA: Data to Enterprise. \nPICARD [OC]: Go ahead, Mister Data. \nDATA: This will be the last trip, sir. \n[Bridge]\n\nDATA [OC]: The remaining cases of hytritium are now\nbeing loaded. \nPICARD: Acknowledged. Mister Worf, advise Beta Agni Two that our\ndeparture is imminent. \nWORF: Aye, Captain. \nRIKER: At warp six, we should be there in just over sixteen hours.\n\n[Jovis Cargo bay]\n\n(The rear hatch on shuttlepod Pike closes and Data\ngets into the pilot's seat) \nDATA: Loading is complete. I am proceeding with departure. Enterprise\nshuttlebay two, prepare for docking, level one\nprecautions for incoming material remain in effect. \nVARRIA: If you'll just acknowledge this last load, Commander> \n(Data puts his thumb on the PADD and is enveloped in electricity. He is\nknocked out cold. Varria takes back the PADD then she scans him) \nVARRIA: Twenty six point eight kilos of tripolymer composites. Eleven\npoint eight kilos of molybdenum-cobalt alloy. One point three kilos\nBioplast sheeting. \n[Bridge]\n\nLAFORGE: Shuttle twelve containment field reads\nnominal. Now leaving the Jovis. \nPICARD: On viewer. \nLAFORGE: Containment field stable. Gravitational fluctuations within", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[378, 393, "LOC"], [410, 420, "SHIP"], [402, 406, "PER"], [299, 324, "PER"], [106, 140, "LOC"], [226, 236, "PER"], [209, 217, "SPEC"], [364, 374, "SPEC"], [446, 457, "PER"], [501, 507, "LOC"], [599, 610, "PER"], [619, 632, "LOC"], [677, 684, "PER"], [756, 771, "LOC"], [793, 808, "SHIP"], [820, 824, "PER"], [913, 938, "LOC"], [1075, 1084, "PER"], [1088, 1092, "PER"], [1177, 1183, "PER"], [1384, 1390, "LOC"], [1466, 1471, "SHIP"]]}
{"id": 732, "text": "[Bridge]\n\nPICARD: Good evening, Mister Data. \nDATA: Actually, good morning, sir. Ship status is \nPICARD: No need to report. I'm just here to do some work on my own. \nDATA: Aye, sir. \nPICARD: I'd like to talk to Doctor Mowray at his archaeological site on\nLandris Two. Could you put it through to my Ready room? \nDATA: I'm sorry, sir, but Stellar Cartography has requested a\ncommunications blackout while they run an experiment. \nPICARD: How long will it be? \nDATA: Another three hours twenty two minutes, sir. I can override it if\nnecessary. \nPICARD: No, it's not important. \nDATA: Aye, sir.\n\n[Ready room]\n\nPICARD: Computer, display the latest excavation\nschematics on Landris Two. \nCOMPUTER: Library computer is temporarily offline. \nPICARD: Explain. \nCOMPUTER: Library systems have been allocated to Stellar Cartography. \nPICARD: Tea, Earl Grey. Hot. \nCOMPUTER: Replicator systems are offline at the request of \nPICARD + COMPUTER: Stellar Cartography. \nPICARD: What could they possibly be doing down there? \n\n[Stellar cartography]\n\n(the room is dark as Picard enters) \nNELLA: In or out, just close that door. And don't move. It'll take a\nsecond for our eyes to re-adjust. Okay, levate to three point two,\nMarquez. \nMARQUEZ: Now at three point two, Commander. \nNELLA: Good. Good we can do this. No, no, no, we're losing vertical\nalignment. Compensate. Compensate! \nMARQUEZ: Compensating. \nNELLA: Gently. Gently, Marquez, don't bump it. No. No wait. Hit the.\nOh, forget it. Forget it. Lights. Whoever you are, you just ruined four\nhours of work. \nPICARD: You might have taken the simple precaution of locking the door.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[32, 43, "PER"], [1, 7, "LOC"], [211, 224, "PER"], [255, 266, "LOC"], [338, 357, "ORG"], [594, 604, "LOC"], [299, 309, "LOC"], [669, 680, "LOC"], [802, 821, "ORG"], [933, 952, "ORG"], [1012, 1031, "LOC"], [1250, 1259, "PER"]]}
{"id": 733, "text": "Captain's log, stardate 45614.6. We have been contacted by an\nandrogynous race called the J'naii to investigate the mysterious\ndisappearance of one of their shuttlecraft.\n\n[Bridge]\n\n(the J'naii are wearing loose-fitting one-piece\nsuits and all have short hair) \nDATA: Captain, we are approaching the designated coordinates. \nPICARD: On screen. Long range scan, Mister Data. \nDATA: Sensors find no evidence of the shuttle anywhere within the star\nsystem. \nSOREN: It couldn't have travelled outside the system. \nRIKER: Mister Data, reconfigure high resolution sweep, radius one\nmillion kilometres. Check for any debris. \nDATA: Scan shows no debris within that radius. \nKRITE: I don't understand it. A shuttle doesn't simply vanish. \nSOREN: There has to be an explanation. \nDATA: Captain, I am detecting an unusual reading. It appears to be a\nneutrino emission with no visible source. \nPICARD: Explanation? \nDATA: I have none, sir. I recommend we launch a probe. \nPICARD: Make it so. \nWORF: Probe is launched. \nDATA: Sensors show no evidence of any unusual phenomenon. \n(then the probe vanishes) \nDATA: The probe is no longer transmitting. \nSOREN: What happened? Where did it go?\n\nCaptain's log, supplemental. The sudden\ndisappearance of our probe suggests that we may have found the first\ninstance of what is called null space, an anomaly which until now had\nbeen only theoretical. Commander Riker has been working around the\nclock with a team of J'naii specialists to formalise this hypothesis.\n\n[Civic chamber]\n\nSOREN: During the creation of a star system, when\nclouds of interstellar dust and gas coalesce, turbulent regions of\nmagnetic and gravitational fields may develop. If certain conditions", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[90, 96, "SPEC"], [173, 179, "LOC"], [187, 193, "SPEC"], [268, 275, "PER"], [361, 372, "PER"], [517, 528, "PER"], [777, 784, "PER"], [1380, 1395, "PER"], [1445, 1451, "SPEC"], [1496, 1509, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 734, "text": "[Graveyard]\n\n(What looks like a traditional British church and churchyard, with people wearing plaid sashes over their tweeds, and a bell\ntolling) \nCRUSHER: Most people on this colony will remember my grandmother as a\nhealer, but her abilities went beyond that. She didn't just relieve\npain and fight illness. She knew that wellbeing is more than a healthy\nbody. Her remedies often included words of advice as well as medicinal\nteas, and often they were just as bitter tasting. I will miss Felisa\nHoward very much. Her healing, her advice, and most of all, the\ninspiration she has provided me throughout the years. Rest in peace,\nNana. \nMATURIN: (not human) And so now we commit her body to the ground, earth\nto earth, ashes to ashes, dust to dust, in sure and certain hope that\nher memory will be kept alive within us all. \nALL: Amen. \n(most people through soil onto the coffin, but one man throws a\ncamellia. A little later, after the titles) \nTROI: That was a beautiful. \nCRUSHER: Oh, thank you. Deanna, did you notice a strange man at the\nservice? He was in his mid-thirties with longish hair? \nTROI: No. \nCRUSHER: He threw a flower on Nana's grave. A camellia. It was her\nfavourite flower. She used to keep them all over the house. \nTROI: Maybe he was a friend or one of her patients. \nCRUSHER: It was a very personal gesture, and he gave me a remarkable\nlook. Well, I guess I should be going back to the house. There are some\nthings I need to do. It's only a few minutes from here. Would you mind\ncoming along? \nTROI: I'd love to. \nCRUSHER: Thanks. \nMATURIN: How long do you plan on staying? \nPICARD: A few more hours. Why? \nMATURIN: Well, as you know, Caldos is one of the first terraforming\nprojects of the Federation. Our weather controls and fusion systems are\nnearly a century old. I wouldn't mind having a starship Engineer take a\nlook at them. Perhaps give us a few upgrades. Maybe in exchange for a\ntour of the colony and a home-cooked meal? \nPICARD: Well, we are due at Starbase six two one tomorrow morning, but\nwe could delay for a few days. Yes, I'm sure we could find the time. \nMATURIN: Excellent. \nPICARD: I would enjoy that tour. Caldos Colony is a most impressive", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 10, "LOC"], [490, 503, "PER"], [630, 634, "PER"], [1140, 1144, "PER"], [999, 1005, "PER"], [1659, 1665, "LOC"], [1715, 1725, "GPE"], [1985, 2005, "LOC"], [2152, 2165, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 735, "text": "Captain's log, stardate 41636.9. As feared, our examination of the\nseven year overdue Federation freighter, Odin, disabled by an asteroid\ncollision, revealed no survivors. However, three escape pods were\nmissing, suggesting the possibility of survivors.\n\n[Bridge]\n\nLAFORGE: Ready to begin orbit of Angel One,\nCaptain. \nPICARD: Make it so, Mister La Forge. What kind of place is this, Data? \nDATA: Angel One is a class M planet, sir, supporting carbon based flora\nand fauna, sparsely populated with intelligent life forms. It is\nsimilar in technological development to mid-twentieth century Earth. \nLAFORGE: Kind of like being marooned at home. \nRIKER: Assuming any of the survivors made it this far. Admittedly, it\n'is the closest planet to the\nOdin, but to travel distance we did in two days at warp one would have\ntaken the Odin escape pod five months. \nDATA: Five months, fourteen days, eleven hours, two minutes \nRIKER: Thank you, Data. \nDATA: And fifty seven seconds. \nTASHA: Captain, we're receiving an audio signal from Angel One. \nPICARD: Starfleet are adamant that we maintain excellent diplomatic\nrelations with this planet. Mister Data, is there any other pertinent\ninformation before we reply? \nDATA: Angel One has evolved into a constitutional oligarchy. It is\ngoverned by a parliamentary body consisting of six elected Mistresses,\nand headed by a female they refer to as The Elected One.\nTROI: It sounds like my own planet. \nWORF: Klingons appreciate strong women. \nPICARD: How current is this information, Mister Data? \nDATA: A Federation vessel last visited this planet sixty two years ago,\nCaptain. \nPICARD: Counsellor, as this is a female dominated society, you might\nwish to make the initial contact. \nTROI: Thank you, sir. \nPICARD: Open hailing frequencies. \nTASHA: Hailing frequencies open, sir. \nTROI: This is Counsellor Deanna Troi from the USS Enterprise. \nBEATA: [OC]: I am Beata, The Elected One. How may we assist you,\nCounsellor?", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[108, 112, "SHIP"], [256, 262, "LOC"], [298, 307, "LOC"], [309, 316, "PER"], [339, 354, "PER"], [384, 388, "PER"], [397, 406, "LOC"], [745, 749, "SHIP"], [826, 830, "SHIP"], [935, 939, "PER"], [981, 988, "PER"], [1027, 1036, "LOC"], [1047, 1056, "ORG"], [1135, 1146, "PER"], [1213, 1222, "GPE"], [1445, 1453, "SPEC"], [1521, 1532, "PER"], [1607, 1614, "PER"], [1625, 1635, "PER"], [1832, 1854, "PER"], [1864, 1878, "SHIP"], [1946, 1956, "PER"], [1899, 1921, "PER"]]}
{"id": 736, "text": "[Medical\nFacility]\n\n(an emergency is being rushed in on a trolley) \nNURSE: Watch the door. Careful, he may have suffered cranial damage. \nTAVA: Move him onto the diagnostic pad. \nNURSE: Right. \nTAVA: Slowly. \nNURSE: Right, here we go. \n(the patient is lifted onto a bed) \nTAVA: Slowly. That's good. \nNURSE: All right. Careful. \n(the patient is hooked up to monitors) \nNILREM: Readings? \nNURSE: They're fluctuating, sir. \nNILREM: He took a severe blow. Possible trauma to the telencephalon. \nTAVA: Start fifteen octares of quadroline. We'll need a complete\ndel-scan series. \nNILREM: I can't find his cardial organ. \nTAVA: What do you mean? I'm reading a steady circulation. \nNILREM: There it is. Up here. \nTAVA: In his digestive tract? \nNILREM: Ever seen anything like this? \n(Tava, a female doctor, palpates the chest) \nTAVA: He's missing three costal struts on one side and four on the\nother. \nNILREM: You think that's something? Look at this \n(holds up a foot) \nNILREM: He has digits on his terminus. \n(Tava removes the mittens to reveal the patient has fingers, unlike his\nalien doctors) \nTAVA: What are you? \n(he is Riker, made to look like one of them)\n\n[Riker's hospital room]\n\n(later, Riker is a bed, being seen by the Senior\nRegistrar or equivalent) \nRIKER: What happened? \nBEREL: You're in the crisis room at the Sikla Medical Facility. You've\nhad a severe injury, but you're going to be all right.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 17, "LOC"], [776, 780, "PER"], [1120, 1125, "PER"], [1160, 1181, "LOC"], [1192, 1197, "PER"], [1226, 1242, "PER"], [1322, 1344, "LOC"]]}
