{"id": 620, "text": "STAR TREK\n THE NEXT GENERATION\n THE BRIGADE OF THE DOOMED\n PART II\n PROLOGUE\n The bridge crew watched, transfixed, as the shock wave from the\n imploding vessel raced towards them.  It knocked the other vessels out of\n commission, and they weren’t as severely damaged as the Enterprise.  They would\n survive it; Enterprise wouldn’t.\n “It is a good day to die,” Worf said as the shock wave was within moments\n of destroying the Enterprise.\n Captain Williams on the Ariel watched in horror as the shock wave took\n out the Enterprise.  It was so clean… there wasn’t even any time to think about it.\n “There are… no debris…” Black said with puzzlement.  Then, she nodded.\n “The shock wave had residual tryolic waves, no doubt from the power core of the\n Garthusian sphere.  That explains the lack of an implosion or any debris.”\n Williams got out of the command chair and looked at Commander\n McGrady.  “Memorial service at nineteen hundred,” he said.  “I’ll be in the ready\n room.”\n CHAPTER ONE\n Captain Kalome of the Imperial Star Destroyer Gunterge didn’t believe his\n eyes.  The alien vessel was nothing like he had ever seen before.  It had a large\n forward section shaped like a saucer, a large section in the aft section with two\n long protusions that appeared to connect to some kind of propulsion system.  It\n was also loaded with numerous other things he’d never even dreamed of.  Kalome\n turned to his first officer, Commander Jafar.  “We will send over troops to\n investigate that vessel immediately.  It will belong to the Empire!”\n “As well as increase your standing,” Jafar replied.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[82, 88, "ORG"], [274, 284, "SHIP"], [311, 321, "SHIP"], [360, 364, "PER"], [426, 436, "SHIP"], [439, 455, "PER"], [463, 468, "SHIP"], [519, 529, "SHIP"], [620, 625, "PER"], [825, 833, "PER"], [877, 895, "PER"], [992, 1006, "PER"], [1014, 1046, "SHIP"], [1386, 1392, "PER"], [1423, 1438, "PER"], [1531, 1537, "GPE"], [1578, 1583, "PER"]]}
{"id": 621, "text": "Kalome eyed the first officer warningly.  “What?”\n “Nothing, sir.”\n “Good.  Now send over the troops!”\n Captain Jean-Luc Picard of the Federation Starship Enterprise awakened.\n He looked around him.  Everything was dark.  He had a hard time breathing.  He\n must have been in Hell.  It figured.\n He heard a noise to his right.  Picard looked in that direction sharply.  He\n could make out a form struggling to get up.  “Ughh.”  It sounded like Commander\n Riker.\n “Will?” Picard said.\n “Captain?” Riker answered.\n Picard felt around the back of him.  He felt a chair, with the same creaks\n and crevices of… the command chair on the Enterprise.  He must not have been in\n Hell after all.  Somehow, the Enterprise had survived the shock wave.  “Number\n One, we must restore at least partial power.”     “What I don’t understand is,”\n Riker said, standing up, “why Starfleet didn’t immediately come in and scan for\n survivors.  It looks like they just left us here to rot.”\n Picard scowled at that thought.  “I don’t think so.  Perhaps that shock wave\n knocked out the rest of the fleet, too.”\n Riker scrambled for the Jeffries tube access in the aft section of the\n bridge.  “Well, by staying here we’re not going to accomplish anything.  We have\n to get to Engineering.”\n “Hold on,” Picard cautioned.  “We need to check on the conditions of the\n rest of the bridge crew.”\n Riker came back to where Picard was standing.  “All right.”  He then\n suddenly looked like he saw a ghost.  “Deanna.  I can’t believe I forgot about her.”\n He rushed to where Troi’s chair was, and scanned the area with his eyes the best\n he could.  “Imzadi?”  Riker heard a low groan about one meter away.  He could\n make out Troi’s crumpled form.  He rushed to her side.  “Deanna!?  Deanna!?\n Are you all right?”", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[0, 6, "PER"], [104, 127, "PER"], [135, 145, "GPE"], [155, 165, "SHIP"], [327, 333, "PER"], [275, 279, "LOC"], [443, 459, "PER"], [470, 476, "PER"], [463, 467, "PER"], [485, 492, "PER"], [495, 500, "PER"], [512, 518, "PER"], [630, 640, "SHIP"], [669, 673, "LOC"], [699, 709, "SHIP"], [741, 752, "PER"], [830, 835, "PER"], [860, 869, "ORG"], [970, 976, "PER"], [1090, 1095, "PER"], [1254, 1265, "LOC"], [1280, 1286, "PER"], [1370, 1375, "PER"], [1395, 1401, "PER"], [1479, 1485, "PER"], [1545, 1551, "PER"], [1620, 1626, "PER"], [1630, 1635, "PER"], [1696, 1702, "PER"], [1744, 1750, "PER"], [1754, 1760, "PER"]]}
{"id": 622, "text": "She gave a low moan and awakened.  She looked around.  Will was\n kneeling beside her.  “Oh Bill…” she muttered in pain.\n “We must get her to sickbay,” Picard said.  “I want to check you out too,\n Commander.”\n “I can wait,” Riker replied.  “We must help Deanna.”\n Troi looked at Picard.  “I think I can stand…” she said.  She put her hand\n up against the wall, and pushed herself up into a standing position.  Troi had a\n pained expression on her face.  “I… think I can make it to sickbay.”\n Picard heard someone getting up in the bridge’s aft section.  He saw\n Worf’s large figure over the blackened tactical console.  “So we have not died and\n crossed the River of Blood…”\n “I’m afraid not, Mr. Worf,” Picard said.  “Commander Riker and I will get\n the counselor to sickbay.  Lieutenant, you have the bridge.”     Worf looked\n around the bridge.  “I will make the most of it, sir.”      Picard nodded and\n gestured at the aft Jeffries tube access.  “All right, let’s go…”\n Lieutenant Commander Geordi La Forge struggled to his feet and looked\n around.  The rest of the engineering personnel were either still unconscious or\n struggling to their feet as Geordi was.\n “This is a rather poor condition,” came a rushed, nervous voice from\n behind Geordi.  He nearly had a heart attack.  “Did I scare you, sir?” Barclay\n asked, noticing how Geordi’s shoulders jerked upward.\n “Don’t you ever do that to me again!” Geordi snapped.  “I’m sorry,\n sir,” Barclay said.  He made a point of looking around Engineering and noticing\n the matter-antimatter reactor not pulsing.  “We need to restore power as soon as\n possible.”\n Geordi flashed Barclay an angry look.  “I know that, Lieutenant!  Now, we\n have to get EPS power flowing through Engineering, and that way we can see\n how much damage we’re dealing with here.”\n “I suggest we check the fusion reactors, sir,” Barclay said.  “They have\n been taxed lately.”", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[55, 59, "PER"], [91, 95, "PER"], [141, 148, "LOC"], [151, 157, "PER"], [196, 205, "PER"], [223, 228, "PER"], [253, 259, "PER"], [263, 267, "PER"], [278, 284, "PER"], [409, 413, "PER"], [480, 487, "LOC"], [491, 497, "PER"], [530, 538, "LOC"], [561, 567, "PER"], [657, 671, "LOC"], [692, 700, "PER"], [703, 709, "PER"], [718, 733, "PER"], [777, 787, "PER"], [815, 819, "PER"], [888, 894, "PER"], [974, 1010, "PER"], [1154, 1160, "PER"], [1070, 1081, "ORG"], [1244, 1250, "PER"], [1308, 1315, "PER"], [1337, 1345, "PER"], [1410, 1416, "PER"], [1446, 1453, "PER"], [1495, 1506, "LOC"], [1615, 1621, "PER"], [1630, 1637, "PER"], [1668, 1678, "PER"], [1728, 1739, "LOC"], [1856, 1863, "PER"]]}
{"id": 623, "text": "THE BRIGADE OF THE DOOMED\n PART III\n CHAPTER ONE\n Captain’s log, stardate 44333.3.  The Enterprise has been\n fully repaired at Starbase 121, and we now have replacement crew\n members for those who were killed battling the Garthusians or the\n Galactic Empire.  Also, Ensign Wesley Crusher is back in full\n health and is resuming his duties at the conn.\n Meanwhile, since the Battle of Feronium, there has been no\n Garthusian activity within Federation space.  Attempts at\n communication with Vraris have failed.  The Romulan Star Empire\n has also been quiet since Feronium.\n There is a mystery about the Romulans… why did they betray\n us at the Battle of Feronium?  As of yet, we have no solid\n answers.  It has been suggested that the Romulans and the\n Garthusians are allies, but that is difficult to prove.  The\n Klingons are subscribing to this theory, believing that the\n “dishonorable cowards” decided to join the stronger side than risk\n a fight to the death.  Anyway, communication attempts with Romulus\n have also met with failure.\n The Enterprise has been given the task of determing the\n relationship between the Garthusians and the Romulans.  It will\n not be easy.  Right now, the Enterprise is on a course for the\n Romulan Neutral Zone so we can begin our investigation.  Starfleet\n is also strengthening defences along the Federation-Garthusian\n border.\n Lieutenant Commander Data raised an eyebrow, emulating\n surprise.  “A distress call?”", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[88, 98, "SHIP"], [127, 139, "LOC"], [222, 233, "SPEC"], [242, 257, "GPE"], [266, 287, "PER"], [413, 423, "SPEC"], [440, 456, "LOC"], [491, 497, "LOC"], [516, 535, "GPE"], [603, 611, "SPEC"], [735, 743, "SPEC"], [753, 764, "SPEC"], [815, 823, "SPEC"], [1003, 1010, "GPE"], [1045, 1055, "SHIP"], [1123, 1134, "SPEC"], [1143, 1151, "SPEC"], [1192, 1202, "SHIP"], [1227, 1247, "LOC"], [1284, 1293, "ORG"], [1336, 1365, "LOC"], [1368, 1393, "PER"]]}
{"id": 624, "text": "“Yes, sir,” Woorf said.  “From within the Romulan Neutral\n Zone.”\n “Put the vessel on the communications system, Lieutenant,”\n Data ordered.\n The speakers crackled to life.  “This is Captain John\n Hommand of the freighter-”  Static sounded loudly, then silence.\n “Can you determine the status of the distressed?” asked\n Data.\n “Affirmative, sir.”  Worf scanned his tactical console.\n “The freighter is the Kobayashi Maru, Gabriel-class.  It’s shields\n are down, it’s warp core is threatening to breach, their life-\n support is down, and they have five hull breaches.”\n “Estimated survival time, Mr. Worf?”\n “Twelve minutes, Captain.”\n “Distance?”\n “Ten million kilometers.”\n Data considered the situation.  The Kobayashi Maru was\n severely crippled, and was within the Romulan Neutral Zone.  It\n was out of transporter range, so the Enterprise would have to go\n into the Neutral Zone to beam out the survivors.  However,\n entering the Neutral Zone would be a gross violation of the Treaty\n of Algernon.  It could lead to war with the Romulan Empire.  It\n would take only a minute at most to evacuate the freighter,\n though.\n “What are your orders, sir?” Commander Riker, who was\n sitting on Data’s right, asked.\n Data came up with a course of action.  “Operations,” he\n said, “launch a probe.  See if we can get a visual on the\n Kobayashi Maru.”\n “Aye, sir,” Ensign Viers said.  She touched a few buttons.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[12, 17, "PER"], [42, 63, "LOC"], [113, 123, "PER"], [127, 131, "PER"], [183, 204, "PER"], [320, 324, "PER"], [348, 352, "PER"], [406, 420, "SHIP"], [595, 603, "PER"], [624, 631, "PER"], [675, 679, "PER"], [711, 725, "SHIP"], [769, 789, "LOC"], [833, 843, "SHIP"], [871, 883, "LOC"], [935, 947, "LOC"], [1034, 1048, "GPE"], [1154, 1169, "PER"], [1191, 1197, "PER"], [1213, 1217, "PER"], [1329, 1343, "SHIP"], [1359, 1371, "PER"]]}
{"id": 625, "text": "“Probe launched.  It will take it two minutes to get within visual\n range.”\n “Acknowledged, Ensign.”  Data turned to Riker, who had a\n questioning look on his face.  “We must verify what our sensor\n readings have told us.  I suspect that it may be a ruse by the\n Romulans, in order to draw us into the Neutral Zone.  That will\n give them an excuse to take the Enterprise.”\n Riker nodded an turned away from Data.\n “Captain,” Viers said, “I have a visual.”\n “On screen,” Data said.\n The freighter Kobayashi Maru did in fact appear on the main\n viewer at the front of the bridge.  It was a real ship; it wasn’t\n a fake.  Debris floated around the Kobayashi Maru, and five hull\n breaches could be seen.\n “Life-signs?” Data asked.\n “Fourteen,” Viers replied.  “Most of them are faint.”\n It could still be a deception, Data thought.  “Species?”\n “Five humans, four Vulcans, two Andorians, and three\n Bajorans.”\n No Romulans, Data thought, getting out of the command chair.\n He approached the fore section of the bridge.  The distress call\n did appear to be genuine.  “We must enter the Neutral Zone and\n rescue the survivors of the accident.”\n “Captain-” Riker said.\n “I am aware of the implications, Mr. Riker,” Data said,\n facing him.  “I also have no intention of provoking the Romulans.\n We will initiate a touch-and-go transport.”\n “Touch-and-go, sir?” Viers asked.\n “We will approach the freighter at a warp velocity, drop out\n of warp for the duration of the transporting process, then warp", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[92, 98, "PER"], [102, 106, "PER"], [117, 122, "PER"], [263, 271, "SPEC"], [302, 314, "LOC"], [360, 370, "SHIP"], [407, 411, "PER"], [415, 422, "PER"], [425, 430, "PER"], [470, 474, "PER"], [496, 510, "SHIP"], [645, 659, "SHIP"], [715, 719, "PER"], [740, 745, "PER"], [814, 818, "PER"], [847, 853, "SPEC"], [860, 867, "SPEC"], [873, 882, "SPEC"], [895, 903, "SPEC"], [910, 918, "SPEC"], [920, 924, "PER"], [1081, 1093, "LOC"], [1007, 1013, "LOC"], [1140, 1147, "PER"], [1150, 1155, "PER"], [1196, 1205, "PER"], [1208, 1212, "PER"], [1276, 1284, "SPEC"], [1353, 1358, "PER"]]}
{"id": 626, "text": "Q-Logy\n By Jeff Stoneking\n CHAPTER ONE\n So this was what it was like to be dead?  Consciousness dissipating as the void all around stretches endlessly and no escape is in sight, and an unsettling feeling that there may be no God after all?  Or perhaps there was a God, a single Creator who had deemed that the entity was destined to spend the rest of eternity separated from Him.  Maybe this was a transitional phase in reincarnation, or perhaps the mythical place commonly referred to as purgatory by corporeal life forms.  Being dead for the first time, and seeing that none other of his species had experienced death, the entity didn’t really know what to expect, though various books, religious and secular, had postulated theories throughout the millennia.  For all he knew, the entity would just as well end up in Heaven or Hell, Sto’vo’kor or Gre’thor, or in the Divine Treasury or the Vault of Eternal Destitution, or simply no where at all.  After all, being part of a species that never died, would any of those places welcome him willingly?  He once was a God, so what God would want him to spend eternity with Him?\n “I think,” the entity thought, recalling that was the tell tale sign of being simply a being.  However, the thought took no substance, and seemed to touch nothing in time.  The entity was pulled out of all that was called home, all that was called familiar.  The entity thought, but only unto itself.  “I think yet I think not; I think not and I am dead.”\n With this thought, there was no substance, no root of any kind or reality.  The entity reached out beyond itself into the deep reaches of the cosmos.  If there was an afterlife, the entity was determined to find it.  Unfortunately, nothing answered back.  For the entity’s entire life, there had been a multitudinous array of voices in his head.  The entity had been part of a great societal experiment, never being alone, never being without reach of the arms of comrades or beyond the grasp of their words.  Now the entity was all alone, thinking what might have been the last thought.  Why was the entity being punished so horribly?  Was the execution?  Excommunication?  The entity forgot the details that lead up to this horrific solitude.  There was the vibrancy of life, the wonderment of it all, then nothing.  Emptiness, space, and silence. Would these be the companions of the entity though the rest of eternity?  The entity always wanted to live forever, and kept on telling others that it would live forever, but now the thought of a true eternity terrified the entity.  The entity cried, and it cried out to whoever might listen, but would anybody hear?\n Guinan, off duty and soaking in the beauty of the arboretum, noticed something slightly awry.  She gazed over at Keiko O’Brien, who was fixing her attention on planting seeds she received from Forchin.  Keiko had complained about the lack of fresh fruits and vegetables aboard the Enterprise, stating that replicator technology had a far way to go.  As she was planting yet another seed, her eyes lost their lock on her work and she looked up at Guinan.  There was something awry.\n “Guinan,” Keiko started, “what brings you up here?\n Guinan had entered the arboretum after Keiko and, apparently, Guinan had not noticed Keiko, as her concentration seemed to be broken slightly with Keiko’s question.  “It’s peaceful up here,” Guinan replied with a smile.  “It’s one of those few places one can go on the ship and forget that you are in space.  It’s a nice retreat.”\n “I suppose so,” smiled Keiko.  “You must be reminded all the time you are in space working in Ten-Forward.  Of course, there always is the holodeck.”\n “Oh, I don’t go into the holodeck much unless Jean Luc or somebody else might invite me along for an adventure.  I prefer to relax in more realistic settings,” Guinan replied.\n There was something awry.  Keiko could sense unease in Guinan, as if she was making small talk but there was something charging through her mind at that moment that caused her to be detached from the present.  She felt Guinan had not simply come to the arboretum to be away from the feeling of being on a star ship, but something was preoccupying her, and even though Guinan replied to all of Keiko’s comments, Keiko still felt as if Guinan was not even talking to anybody in particular, really.  Guinan could not even keep in eye contact with Keiko and were in constant gaze out the windows.  Keiko turned her head up and looked out the window.  It was simply a star field, an odd choice for somebody to focus on when they just claimed they wanted to get away from the feeling of being in space.  “What is it?” Keiko asked, hoping to get responses out of Guinan that were perhaps more truthful.\n “I don’t know.  We’re on route to Wadi Besor,” Guinan replied, “but I feel as if we shouldn’t go.  I felt something earlier, a disturbance of some sort.  I can’t describe it entirely, nor even understand it myself.”\n Keiko nodded.  She could not describe in concrete language either, but she sensed something was unusual, as if things were not the same anymore.  “Something is happening but I don’t know what.  From what I’ve seen, everything appears to be status quo.”\n “Yes,” Guinan nodded.  “Status quo.  That’s what they want us to think, anyway.”\n Keiko did not know what to say to that, or how to even how to think she should take it.  At that moment, Miles O’Brien came over Keiko’s com badge, “Keiko, I can’t get off of duty right now to get Molly from the day care.  Do you think you could get her now?”\n “Sure thing, Miles,” Keiko replied, relieved that she had a chance to get away from Guinan.  “Sorry, Guinan, but I have to go,” Keiko said awkwardly as she excused herself.\n Guinan just nodded as if she was unattached from the moment.  As Keiko took her leave of the arboretum, Guinan simply continued to watch out the window as if looking for something, or perhaps expecting something.\n It was not first in the arboretum that Guinan felt this way, however.  It first occurred to her moments after she left Ten Forward, as she walked down the halls of the Enterprise.  Every curve of the corridors, the nuance of each computer console, down to the locations of the Jefferies Tubes caused an odd sensation to course through Guinan’s being.  Yet, all was the same as it has always been.\n “Computer,” Guinan said with hesitation in the arboretum, not sure what to expect, “what ship is this?”\n “This is the USS Enterprise,” the computer spoke back, “registry number NCC-1701-D.”\n That is exactly what Guinan thought she would hear, yet she almost expected to hear something else.  “That,” she said softly and slowly through her lips, “is not right.”  She paused with unease, worry, and confusion forming in her brow and then said, “Computer, locate Captain Picard.”\n “Captain Picard is deceased,” the computer responded as if giving a weather report.  “Date of death: stardate 44741.9.”\n Guinan leaned up against the nearest wall and the words of the computer had barely penetrated her mind and her thoughts.  Something more ominous seemed to emanate from somewhere outside the ship, something she felt and heard all around her, inside her.  It was coming closer, though she could not yet see it.  Out there, beyond the blackness of space, something was coming and it felt terrible.\n “Miles!” Keiko called out down the corridor.  He was walking out of the transporter room, apparently just getting off duty.  Keiko had Molly in her arms as she quickened her pace to meet up with her husband.  “I was just with Guinan in the arboretum.  She is acting awfully strange.”\n Miles chuckled, “As if that’s a surprise?”\n “Seriously, Miles!” Keiko continued.  “I know she can be rather eccentric, but she really has me concerned.  She really seemed to be concerned about our recent mission to Wadi Besor andÉ”\n “Wait a minute?” Miles interrupted.  “How does she know about that?”", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[11, 25, "PER"], [278, 285, "PER"], [489, 498, "LOC"], [820, 826, "LOC"], [830, 834, "LOC"], [836, 846, "LOC"], [850, 858, "LOC"], [870, 885, "LOC"], [893, 921, "LOC"], [2653, 2659, "PER"], [2766, 2779, "PER"], [2703, 2712, "LOC"], [2846, 2853, "PER"], [2856, 2861, "PER"], [2934, 2944, "SHIP"], [3099, 3105, "PER"], [3136, 3142, "PER"], [3145, 3150, "PER"], [3187, 3193, "PER"], [3210, 3219, "LOC"], [3226, 3231, "PER"], [3249, 3255, "PER"], [3272, 3277, "PER"], [3334, 3341, "PER"], [3378, 3384, "PER"], [3542, 3547, "PER"], [3613, 3624, "LOC"], [3658, 3666, "LOC"], [3695, 3703, "LOC"], [3716, 3724, "PER"], [3830, 3836, "PER"], [3874, 3879, "PER"], [3902, 3908, "PER"], [4066, 4072, "PER"], [4100, 4109, "LOC"], [4215, 4221, "PER"], [4240, 4247, "PER"], [4258, 4263, "PER"], [4281, 4287, "PER"], [4344, 4350, "PER"], [4391, 4396, "PER"], [4441, 4446, "PER"], [4659, 4664, "PER"], [4703, 4709, "PER"], [4778, 4788, "LOC"], [4791, 4797, "PER"], [4961, 4966, "PER"], [5222, 5228, "PER"], [5297, 5302, "PER"], [5402, 5415, "PER"], [5426, 5433, "PER"], [5446, 5451, "PER"], [5494, 5499, "PER"], [5571, 5576, "PER"], [5579, 5584, "PER"], [5642, 5648, "PER"], [5659, 5665, "PER"], [5686, 5691, "PER"], [5732, 5738, "PER"], [5797, 5802, "PER"], [5825, 5834, "LOC"], [5836, 5842, "PER"], [5970, 5979, "LOC"], [5985, 5991, "PER"], [6065, 6076, "LOC"], [6114, 6124, "SHIP"], [6281, 6289, "PER"], [6356, 6362, "PER"], [6466, 6476, "SHIP"], [6556, 6562, "PER"], [6804, 6818, "PER"], [6823, 6837, "PER"], [6943, 6949, "PER"], [7340, 7345, "PER"], [7348, 7353, "PER"], [7464, 7469, "PER"], [7474, 7479, "PER"], [7565, 7571, "PER"], [7579, 7588, "LOC"], [7624, 7629, "PER"], [7680, 7685, "PER"], [7688, 7693, "PER"], [7839, 7849, "LOC"], [7874, 7879, "PER"]]}
{"id": 627, "text": "“I don’t know,” Keiko replied.  “I didn’t think I should even ask.  What’s the big deal?”\n “Well, our destinations aren’t usually broadcast over the ship,” Miles replied, “and this destination has been kept quiet among the senior crew.”\n “Why?  What’s on Wadi Besor?”\n “It’s the home world of the Taecate,” Miles answered.  “I don’t know exactly why we are going there, but I do know that Captain Tutizi was stationed there on the Federation outpost there, and that he and the Captain were good friends.”\n “Captain Tutizi?” echoed Keiko.  “Wasn’t he murdered?”\n “Exactly,” Miles affirmed, “and as far as I know, his killer is still at large, which is why our trip to Wadi Besor isn’t being made public for the time being, in the event the murderer is on board the ship.  The security team is still investigating the potential that the killer may be on board.”\n “Oh, that’s absurd,” Keiko said.  “The Enterprise was nowhere near Wadi Besor at the time of Tutizi’s death.”\n “They are just keeping the possibility open, Keiko,” Miles said.\n “I don’t care,” insisted Keiko.  “It makes no sense to mark the Enterprise crew as a ship of suspects.  What about all the other ships in Starfleet?”\n “To tell the truth, Keiko, I am not entirely sure of all the ins and outs of this investigation.  What little I do know came from the official channels, which I can assure you.  Nobody is being charged as a suspect yet.  Nevertheless, that’s all beside the point.  I still cannot understand how Guinan knows we are going there.  UnlessÉ”\n “Miles, don’t trail off like that.  You know I hate when you do that.”\n “Well, it’s just that I helped out in stellar spectroscopy earlier today.  Commander Data and I were investigating an anomaly recently located near Wadi Besor.”\n “What kind of anomaly?” Keiko asked.\n “I don’t know,” Miles said.  “But I did see something like it before on one of our missions, I am almost certain of that.”\n “And what are you doing helping Data?  You’re not a science officer,” Keiko wondered.\n “It’s just stellar spectroscopy,” Miles replied.  “It’s pretty elementary stuff, really, and besides, I think it could help me in that promotion I am gunning for at Deep Space Nine.  It never hurts to broaden your horizons, so they say.  As a matter of fact, I am scheduled to go on duty in stellar spectroscopy in an hour.”\n “But you just got off of duty!” Keiko countered.\n “I might have to pull a few double shifts in the next few weeks,” O’Brien mentioned.  “Sorry, but this training for my promotion at Deep Space Nine is killing me too.  I am sure once we get to Deep Space Nine, we will have much more time to ourselves.”\n CHAPTER TWO\n The entity searched through the expanse of nothingness.  Searching for something, perhaps another dead soul wandering though this…this limbo?  The entity did not know what it was.  The blackness stretched seemingly from east to west, with no end in sight.  No throne, no God, no Prophets or wormhole aliens, no vaults or hordes of honored Klingons within any imaginable grasp within this void, not even an angel or a lesser deity made by humanoid hands.  No light, no door, no escape; the entity just drifted through nothing, and with each passing moment grew more weary and more depressed.  Where were the parties?  The fanfare music?  The singing choirs of seraphim?  The hordes of welcoming and willing virgins?  The entity began to question exactly where the eternal resting place would be.\n Unexpectedly, almost frightening the entity, something came up behind it.  The entity refocused his attention and could have smiled if it had a mouth:  It was another disembodied entity, and the entity recognized the second entity.  At last, a friend?\n “Come,” the Captain said, hearing his door chime but not looking up.\n The door slid and a silent presence flowed into the Captain’s ready room that made the Captain uneasy.  He looked up and saw Guinan standing there, as if she were trying to find the words to say.  “Guinan,” he began softly, “what can I do for you?”\n “How did Captain Picard die?” Guinan asked carefully, fearing she was going mad.\n “Guinan,” Captain Riker said with slight hesitation, “Captain Picard was assassinated seven years ago at an archaeological conference.”\n Guinan knew this but she also knew that it was horribly wrong.            In her mind, she was trying to place the pieces of the puzzle together, trying to reconcile what she felt was wrong with what she had known to be reality for all her life. She remembered how Commander Riker received the command of the Enterprise, which took place shortly after Captain Picard’s death.  She could clearly recall each step Riker took the Enterprise along the way:  She remembered how Riker confronted Soran, how Riker found himself in the Nexus and opted to go back far enough in time to save the Enterprise-D from destruction.  These were all things that she could remember as it was reality, but it was reality construed.  However, there was something deep inside her telling her that she had just talked to Captain Picard that morning, though her conscious mind had no recollection of the event.  “What?” she asked, almost as if she was merely arguing with her mind and not even talking to Captain Riker.\n “He was giving the keynote address and an assassin had bypassed security and made his way in with the team that had gathered for the conference.  The alien killed Captain Picard.”\n Guinan steadied herself and looked Riker straight in the eye.  “Captain Riker,” she said, the words sounding unnatural as they came out, “this isn’t right.”  She paused.  “The bridge, the people,” she said as she shook her head and looked around.  She paused a moment and added, “The ship.  What kind of ship is this?  What is its purpose?”\n “The Enterprise is a science vessel,” Riker replied.  “It has been ever since the peace treaty was made with the Vulcans and the Romulans.  Ambassador Spock had brought unification to the two worlds and the Klingons have focused their forces against the Cardassians.”\n “I know that,” Guinan conceded.  “Yet, I know that this is all wrong. This is a ship of exploration, yes, but it also a ship of peace and of defense.  It has greater potential than being a science vessel.”", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[16, 21, "PER"], [156, 161, "PER"], [255, 265, "LOC"], [297, 304, "SPEC"], [389, 403, "PER"], [431, 441, "GPE"], [477, 484, "PER"], [507, 520, "PER"], [531, 536, "PER"], [573, 578, "PER"], [667, 677, "LOC"], [775, 788, "ORG"], [882, 887, "PER"], [900, 910, "SHIP"], [928, 938, "LOC"], [954, 962, "PER"], [1017, 1022, "PER"], [1025, 1030, "PER"], [1063, 1068, "PER"], [1102, 1112, "SHIP"], [1176, 1185, "ORG"], [1209, 1214, "PER"], [1484, 1490, "PER"], [1529, 1534, "PER"], [1675, 1689, "PER"], [1748, 1758, "LOC"], [1786, 1791, "PER"], [1816, 1821, "PER"], [1956, 1960, "PER"], [1994, 1999, "PER"], [2045, 2050, "PER"], [2176, 2191, "LOC"], [2369, 2374, "PER"], [2453, 2460, "PER"], [2519, 2534, "LOC"], [2580, 2595, "LOC"], [2993, 3001, "SPEC"], [3715, 3722, "PER"], [3825, 3845, "LOC"], [3860, 3867, "PER"], [3898, 3904, "PER"], [3971, 3977, "PER"], [4032, 4046, "PER"], [4053, 4059, "PER"], [4106, 4112, "PER"], [4115, 4128, "PER"], [4159, 4173, "PER"], [4242, 4248, "PER"], [4507, 4522, "PER"], [4551, 4561, "SHIP"], [4594, 4610, "PER"], [4654, 4659, "PER"], [4669, 4679, "SHIP"], [4715, 4720, "PER"], [4732, 4737, "PER"], [4743, 4748, "PER"], [4770, 4775, "LOC"], [4828, 4840, "SHIP"], [5041, 5055, "PER"], [5224, 5237, "PER"], [5403, 5417, "PER"], [5421, 5427, "PER"], [5456, 5461, "PER"], [5485, 5498, "PER"], [5597, 5603, "LOC"], [5768, 5778, "SHIP"], [5801, 5806, "PER"], [5876, 5883, "SPEC"], [5892, 5900, "SPEC"], [5903, 5919, "PER"], [5970, 5978, "SPEC"], [6017, 6028, "SPEC"], [6047, 6053, "PER"]]}
{"id": 628, "text": "“Guinan,” Riker began, “I believe the stress is getting to you.  Perhaps you could talk to Counselor Troi and…”\n “No” Guinan said, as if unattached from the conversation all together.\n “You have gone through a lot in your grieving process since Jean-Luc passed away,” Riker stated.  “I think if you would just talk to her then…”\n “Look,” Guinan said as she backed off, “I’ll get it worked out.  Don’t worry about it.”\n “Guinan, if you should ever want to talk, you can come to Troi or me,” Riker offered.\n Guinan smiled politely and stepped out of the ready room.  “Ten Forward,” she spoke as she entered the turbolift.  Guinan felt inside as if something without was coming towards her, as if something was coming for her…\n “Death has always interested me,” the entity spoke to the approaching entity.  “I thought I was going to be out here alone for an eternity.  Or maybe this is the prelude to some sort of judgment?”\n “You know me?” the other entity spoke.  “How is this possible?  I’ve encountered others but they seemed to be too caught up in personal grief to even notice me.”\n “Ah, good friends are friends forever,” the entity said, “mon capitaine.”\n “Q!” the other entity spoke, recalling at once that he was Jean-Luc Picard.  “What madness is this?  What have you gotten me into now?”\n In a flash, the blackness vanished and Q and Jean-Luc were standing on a hillside, the breeze blowing, the trees waving, the grass beneath them, and the sun shining high in the sky.  It reminded Jean-Luc of his home in France.  “What is this?” Picard demanded, finding that now he had a body, or at least a representation of what was his body.\n “You’re dead,” Q replied, “and your life is about to pass before your eyes, starting with your old stomping grounds.”  He yawned.  “I’m sure it will be as droll as you; wake me when it’s over.”\n “Dead?” Picard echoed.  He remembered being shot, Worf immediately firing upon the assassin, Beverly looking into his eyes during his last moments of life, floating up, seeing his body with Beverly over him along with the other people who had gathered to hear his address, and then he floated out of the ship. He floated out past the stars, into the blackness where he met Q.\n “Deader than a door nail,” Q replied.  “This is my first time dead, too.  You know, I was rather concerned at the start of it all.  I thought I was in human Hell, what with that horrible feeling of isolation and all, but I had no idea why your God would want to send me there, especially since I had done so much work to help His poor, pathetic people.  Then I saw you and I knew that I must be in Heaven.”  Q smiled warmly as he approached Jean-Luc and put his hand on Jean-Luc’s right shoulder.  “Just think, mon capitaine, an eternity together!”\n “You were right the first time,” Picard grumbled as he removed Q’s hand from his shoulder.  “This must be Hell.”\n Q rolled his eyes.  “For once you think you would show a little gratitude!  After all, I was trying to help you out!”\n “You can help me out by returning me to my ship!”\n “I am just as human as you, Picard,” Q replied dryly.  “Don’t you remember?  I came aboard your ship seeking to help you after the Continuum stripped me of my powers but you whined and put me in the brig then the Calamarain came.  They took me, tortured me, and left me for dead on some God forsaken moon.  After that, I was passed from race to race, species to species, being tortured not only for things I had done but also for things the other members of the Continuum had done.  I was actually relieved when the Taecate executed me.”\n “I hope you’re satisfied, Q,” Picard said irately.  “You always wanted to find out all you could about humans and now you get to find out about death.  I hope you’re learning something.”\n “None of this would have happened if you had been more cooperative when I came aboard your ship,” Q advised.\n “What do you mean?” Picard demanded.\n “I came aboard to help you, Picard,” Q stated.  “You know, a funny thing happened to me on my way to eternity-the Continuum showed me what things might have been like had I lived.  One thing that would have been different is that you would still exist in your limited existence in time.”\n “Q, I am not interested in…,” Picard began to say.\n “Oh, but you should be, mon capitaine,” Q replied.  “If I had lived, it would have meant that somebody from your crew was able to save me from the Calamarain and then the Continuum would have restored my powers.  I could have been there to save you from your assassin.”  Picard looked at Q with unbelief.  “Trust me.  That is the way it would have worked out.”\n “I’d rather see you dead and out of our way,” Picard said with a sardonic smile.  “I guess if I had to die as a result then that is a small price to pay.”\n “There you go again, Picard,” Q sighed.  “You do wound me.  I have only wanted to help you; I have always held your best interest in mind.”\n “Thank you for your concern, Q, but we can manage just fine without you,” Picard asserted.  “The last thing humanity needs is your superior attitude directing our lives!”\n “You know,” Q said nostalgically, “that is exactly what John F. Kennedy told me just before he decided to go on his joy ride through Dallas on November 22, 1963.  When he died, I was swimming in the waters of Orxim Theta.  Where were you?”\n “Q…,” Picard began irately.\n “Humanity has never appreciated me,” Q continued.  “I tried to tell Hitler that he could make it as an artist but do you think he listened?  Humph!  You and he have a lot in common, Picard.  I remember when…”", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[1, 7, "PER"], [10, 15, "PER"], [91, 105, "PER"], [118, 124, "PER"], [245, 253, "PER"], [268, 273, "PER"], [338, 344, "PER"], [420, 426, "PER"], [477, 481, "PER"], [490, 495, "PER"], [506, 512, "PER"], [552, 562, "LOC"], [566, 577, "LOC"], [609, 618, "LOC"], [621, 627, "PER"], [1144, 1157, "PER"], [1162, 1163, "PER"], [1220, 1235, "PER"], [1337, 1338, "PER"], [1343, 1351, "PER"], [1493, 1501, "PER"], [1517, 1523, "LOC"], [1542, 1548, "PER"], [1658, 1659, "PER"], [1846, 1852, "PER"], [1888, 1892, "PER"], [1931, 1938, "PER"], [2028, 2035, "PER"], [2211, 2212, "PER"], [2242, 2243, "PER"], [2623, 2624, "PER"], [2372, 2376, "LOC"], [2613, 2619, "LOC"], [2656, 2664, "PER"], [2685, 2695, "PER"], [2726, 2739, "PER"], [2798, 2804, "PER"], [2828, 2831, "PER"], [2871, 2875, "LOC"], [2879, 2880, "PER"], [3063, 3068, "SPEC"], [3077, 3083, "PER"], [3086, 3087, "PER"], [3262, 3272, "SPEC"], [3565, 3572, "SPEC"], [3614, 3615, "PER"], [3618, 3624, "PER"], [3691, 3697, "SPEC"], [3874, 3875, "PER"], [2366, 2371, "SPEC"], [3906, 3912, "PER"], [3952, 3958, "PER"], [3961, 3962, "PER"], [3180, 3189, "ORG"], [3511, 3520, "ORG"], [4038, 4047, "ORG"], [4214, 4215, "PER"], [4243, 4249, "PER"], [4289, 4302, "PER"], [4305, 4306, "PER"], [4412, 4422, "SPEC"], [4436, 4445, "ORG"], [4536, 4542, "PER"], [4553, 4554, "PER"], [4673, 4679, "PER"], [4804, 4810, "PER"], [4813, 4814, "PER"], [4953, 4954, "PER"], [4998, 5004, "PER"], [5108, 5109, "PER"], [5152, 5167, "PER"], [5229, 5235, "LOC"], [5305, 5316, "LOC"], [5338, 5339, "PER"], [5343, 5349, "PER"], [5367, 5375, "SPEC"], [5403, 5404, "PER"], [5434, 5440, "PER"], [5548, 5554, "PER"]]}
{"id": 629, "text": "PART 1\n Stardate 77372.14\n Captain Mark Alexander Smith stood on the bridge of his starship, the USS Lexington. He looked out at the gargantuan Borg vessel on the viewscreen. “Captain, the Borg seem unaware of our presence, but their scans are increasing” said his operations officer, “Maintain Grey-mode Protocol” he ordered. The ship was following the Borg Cube trying to divert it from its course to Earth. Starfleet was bogged down with the Borg in other sectors and even with help from the Klingons and Romulans, they were not making much headway. Planet after planet in system after system were falling to the Borg. a siren alerted at the tactical status, “Captain, we’ve been detected, Borg vessel altering course to an attack position” reported his tactical officer, “Full shields and weapons, fire” he ordered. The Borg vessel was faster as his crew bustled. The first shot was staggering. Explosions rocked the vessel, throwing the Captain to the floor. “Damage report” demanded the Captain, staggering to his feet, “Hull breach on deck 24, main power to 15%, secondary power and emergency back-ups are destroyed, weapons are offline, shields are at 27%, Sir” shouted his tactical officer, “Number 1” he shouted, mimicking an old mentor and role model. His first officer was dead under some debris. The ops officer shouted up, “Captain, what’s left of the sensors are detecting tachyon emissions “. The Captain ignored that and shouted, “Helm, all forward, lay in a collision course, Lieutenant, drop an emergency beacon with information about what happened here” he ordered to his bridge staff, “Bridge to Main Engineering, shunt all available power to the impulse engines on my mark” he said. He took a deep breath to calm himself, “Mark” he said, “Power shunted, Captain” said the Chief Engineer. “Helm, Engage” he said. The ship moved forward, disintegrating as it went, the computers warning system kicked in, “Warning, collision detected, impact in 30 seconds”. The Captain watched with resignation as the Borg ship completely filled the viewscreen. Just before impact he saw a bright light, then lost consciousness.\n Stardate 48905.72. USS Enterprise NCC-1701-D. Earth\n Captain Jean-Luc Picard sat face to face with Admiral Edward Robertson. Sat next to him was Commander William Riker. The Admiral was briefing the Enterprise command officers as to their mission, “Captain, you understand this mission is to be classified, news of the possible return of the Borg could destabilise the Quadrant. Given that previous Borg attacks have been targeted at humanity, it might give those hostile to Starfleet the excuse they have been looking for to launch assaults along the Federation Borders” said the Admiral, “Understood, Sir, shall we be on our way, time is critical if it is indeed the Borg” said Picard. The wizened Admiral nodded, “Very well, Captain, I pray that I’m wrong” said the Admiral. The Admiral stood, shaking hands with Picard and Riker before leaving the briefing room. Before Picard or Riker could say anything, Lieutenant Commander Data contacted them, “Data to Picard, Captain, internal sensors are reading massive tachyon and chronoton emissions on deck 4” he said. Picard and Riker looked at each other, “Are you sure, Mr Data” said Picard, “Quite certain, Captain, the emissions seem to be occurring in an area about the size of a humanoid male about 6 feet tall” said Data. “Very well, Mr Data, have a security detail meet me and Commander Riker on deck 4” said Picard, leaving the briefing room with Commander Riker close behind.\n 5 minutes later, Picard, Riker and the security forces sent by Data and Worf were at the area where the tachyons were concentrated. The corridor seemed normal. Nothing seemed out of place, “Picard to Data, we have arrived at the area you directed us to, but there doesn’t seem to be anything here” he said. There was slight interference when Data responded, “Captain, the emissions are concentrating into one area, you might see something in the next few minutes” said Data, through the interference. They did.\n As the emissions condensed and concentrated, a bright light filled the corridor. When it cleared enough for the crew to look, a man lay on the deck. His uniform wasn’t recognisable, but the insignia showed he was a Starfleet officer. “Medical scan” ordered Picard. He watched the medic scanning the new man, and looked at him with a comparative eye. Whereas his uniform was black all the way up to the shoulder with red on the shoulders and a blue collar showing with his four command pips, the strangers uniform was black up to the shoulder where the shoulder pads turned grey. The collar was red and Captain Picard noticed that he was looking at another Starfleet Captain. “He’s alive, Captain” said a Security Ensign, “Picard to Transporter Room Three, two to beam directly to sickbay” said the Captain. They both dissolved and left the Commander and the security team on the deck. “Picard to Riker, return to the bridge and set a course for Ceridian III, Warp 6” said the Captain as Doctor Beverley Crusher examined her patient. The Captain watched the bustle quietly as they worked to heal the man’s extensive injuries. Thirty minutes later, the medical team stepped away from the patient, “I’ve stabilized him for the moment, but he is very weak. The next hour should determine his rate of recovery” she said. The Captain pondered the situation, “Can you wake him” he asked. The Doctor looked at him again, “Yes, of course, but he will be very weak” she replied.\n Captain Mark Smith was slowly becoming aware of his surroundings. It took him a few seconds to realize that he shouldn’t be able to become aware of his surroundings at all. He tentatively opened his eyes and saw a face that he hadn’t seen in the 20 years since his death. Captain Jean-Luc Picard stood over him. This was impossible as the Captain had been dead for 20 years. “My name is Captain Jean-Luc Picard of the Federation Starship Enterprise” he said briskly, “I know who you are, Sir” said Smith weakly, “I’m Captain Mark Smith, USS Lexington” he said. Before the Captain could reply, Smith fed him the vital piece of information, “Captain, I grew up on this ship, I think I have travelled back in time” he said. Picard didn’t seem surprised, “Yes, we observed tachyon emissions around the time and place you were discovered. But who are you to have grown up aboard the Enterprise” said Picard. Smith sighed, “My dad was the Deputy Chief Engineer who was killed in an EPS explosion when I was eleven” said Smith, “Yes, Lieutenant Smith was killed a week ago, Mr LaForge is trying to find out exactly what caused the explosion. Counsellor Troi is working with, erm, you” said Picard. There was a moment of awkward silence between the Captains. “What’s the Stardate where you’re from” said Picard. Smith cleared his throat, “77371.95” he said. The Captain sighed, “What’s Starfleet doing 40 years from now” said Picard, genuinely interested, “Well, Sir, there is lots I can’t say because of the Temporal Prime Directive. I couldn’t tell you much about the next forty years. However, for the last two years in my time, the Federation has been plagued by the Borg. The USS Alaska monitored several temporal distortions around the badlands, and a number of them had Borg signatures. When the Borg started hitting Federation colonies, the temporal schisms became a low priority” said Smith. Picard looked at him, looking ever so slightly haunted at the mention of the Borg, “What were you doing when you ended up on the Enterprise” asked Picard. Smith wracked his brain, “I believe that we were following a Borg vessel when we were detected. My ship was heavily damaged so I ordered all power to be diverted to the impulse engines and lay in a collision course” said Smith. Picard responded instantly, “Captain, we are on a mission to investigate the sudden appearance of Borg vessels in the Ceridian System. There have been no Borg incursions since the Battle of Wolf 359, but a deep space sensor relay suddenly picked up about 20 signatures. The Enterprise has been sent to investigate” said Picard. Smith frowned, “What’s the precise Stardate, Sir” said Smith, “48905.72” replied Picard. Smith suddenly had all his fears confirmed, “Captain, my recollection of this Stardate is the Enterprise going to Starbase 384 for weapons system refits” said Smith. Picard looked at him, “Yes, but Admiral Robertson redirected us to investigate the readings from the deep space sensor array” said Picard, equally concerned. “It would appear that some event has changed the timelines, quite possibly starting with the Borg invasion in my time, leading to the destruction of my ship to my appearance aboard the Enterprise” said Smith.\n On the bridge Commander Riker was looking at the sensors with Data. “What could be causing these readings, Mr Data” said Riker. Data made a face that almost looked pensive, “The parameters do not conform to that of any known sub-space or temporal distortions currently on record, Sir” said Data. Riker considered his options, “Any theories” he said. Before data responded, Worf spoke up, “Commander, there is a Borg signature emanating from the distortion. A Gravimetric distortion extending from the main disturbance” he said. Before the commander could give an order, the ship was enveloped in the gravimetric disturbance. “Red alert, Captain Picard to the bridge” said Riker, “All engines, full reverse” he ordered. The ship shuddered violently as the helm officer carried out Riker’s orders, “Commander, engines are at full reverse, it’s not having any effect” said the helm officer.\n Down in sickbay, Captain Picard was deliberating with Captain Smith, “Captain, come with me” said Picard. The Captains left the sickbay and walked towards the bridge. “Picard to the Bridge, Number One, what’s the situation” said Picard. “We are caught in a gravimetric distortion expanding from a larger anomaly. Mr Worf has detected a Borg signature and Mr Data has no theories. Engines are at full reverse but it’s not having any effect” said Riker. Picard sighed, “Understood” he said.\n Riker was watching the situation evolve in front of him. “Bridge to LaForge, I need more power to the impulse drive” said Riker urgently as the ship shook more violently, “I’ll do what I can, Sir, but if we keep this up the manifolds will rupture and we’ll be dead in the water” said Commander LaForge. The turbolift doors hissed open and Captain Picard stepped out with the other Captain, Riker was aware of the ripple of unease at the stranger on the bridge. “Report, Commander” said Picard, “Sir our best indication is that a Borg vessel is about to emerge from the distortion, there are chronoton emissions emanating from the distortion” said Riker, he looked at the other Captain, “It’s possible that this distortion could also lead to your time, Sir” said Riker. Picard looked to Smith, “Suggestions” he said. Smith thought for a second. “Mr Data, can you display sensor readings or the distortion on the main viewer” said Smith. Data complied instantly and Smith studied the readings, “This looks like a Borg Transwarp conduit, but the readings are unusual. Commander Riker’s assessment is correct, Sir, this distortion could indeed lead to my time” said Smith. He walked over to Worf, “Commander, launch a photon torpedo at these coordinates , prime it to explode on arrival. The antimatter discharge may break the ship free, helm reduce power before the manifolds rupture” he said, walking back to Picard and Riker at the centre of the bridge. He looked at Picard, “Ready, Sir, that should free the Enterprise from the distortion field” he said. Picard nodded, “Mr Worf, fire torpedoes” said Picard. Worf nodded, “Firing, Captain”. The torpedo flew from the ship, exploding right on target, “Captain, gravimetric distortion is weakening” reported Data, “Helm full reverse” said Picard.\n As the Enterprise  reversed away from the distortion, a Borg vessel protruded from it. The vessel was enormous in size and scope. “Captain, engines are overtaxed from the effort of escaping the distortion, we must power down or the impulse manifolds will rupture” said the helm officer. Picard focused on the helm officer, “Warp Engines” he questioned. The helm officer checked, “No, Captain, the gravimetric disturbances are interfering with the warp bubble I can’t get it to stabilize” said the helm officer. Smith stepped in, “Ensign, is there a way to reduce the warp profile of the Enterprise” said Smith. The Ensign thought for a second, “Yes but we can’t do it from here” she said, “ there is a malfunction in the command relays, it will have to be done from Main Engineering” she said. Picard stood, tapping his communicator, “Picard to Engineering, Mr LaForge, find a way to lower the warp profile of the ship” he said. The Borg ship continued to emerge from the distortion when LaForge contacted them again, “LaForge to Bridge, warp profile should be concealed” said LaForge. The Borg vessel was fully out of the distortion and the distortion was dissipating. “Scan the vessel, Mr Data” said Picard. Data scanned the Borg ship. “It is larger than the Borg vessels we have encountered so far, but its structure is perfectly geometric. There is a large section of damage to the vessel, indicating that a starship similar in size to the Enterprise collided with the ship” said Data. A sound of anguish and pain came from Captain Smith. The crew looked at him, “Remember what I said, Captain. The last thing I remember before waking up on deck 4 was my ship being heavily damaged in a Borg attack as a Borg vessel headed for Earth. I rammed the Borg to try and destroy them. I failed” said Captain Smith, sinking to his knees. A beeping cut through the tension on the bridge, “Captain, we are being hailed” said Worf. Captain Smith still knelt on the bridge, head held in shame, Captain Picard stood and walked forwards. Before he could order the channel open Worf said, “We are being scanned, Sir”. Picard looked at the damaged vessel, “Open a channel” he said. The screen showed an image of a terrible creature. It looked like a woman, only it had tubes sticking out of the crown of its head. Captain Picard and Captain Smith recognised it as a Borg queen. Her face showed an expression that had she not been an emotionless cybernetic abomination would have been likened to imperious and smug. “Locutus” she said to Picard. Picard’s face stonewalled, “That is not my name” he said, “Why do you resist us, Locutus, you know what we are capable of” she said. The bridge was quiet as Captain Picard and the Borg queen faced off. “Lucky for you, Locutus, we are not interested in you today” said the Borg queen suddenly. “Then what do you want” demanded Picard, coldly. She almost smiled, “Captain Mark Smith” she said, the words carefully measured for maximum effect. Picard’s gaze swung toward Smith briefly, “And if we refuse” said Picard. The Borg queen didn’t answer straight away. After a couple of seconds she said, “Deck 14 is now overrun with drones. If you do not had us Mark Smith, they will force visual and audio imagery of the slow assimilation of your crew until you change your mind” she said. Before Picard could respond, Smith stood, rage filling his thoughts. “You want me? Fine. Prepare to receive me, but if you want an easy assimilation subject, no if you expect an easy assimilation target then prepare for the biggest resistance you have ever encountered” said Smith. Picard flashed him a steely glare. “You’re threats are irrelevant, you know I won’t sacrifice a member of my crew” said Picard. Smith shot Picard an equally steely glare, “With respect, Captain Picard, the lives of the crew aboard this ship are worth more than mine. I lost my ship and all my crew are dead, so I will do anything to protect this ship and this crew” said Smith. Before Picard could respond the Borg queen smiled, that same mechanic, mirthless smile. “Not all of your crew are dead, Captain” she said.\n To be continued…", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[27, 55, "PER"], [101, 110, "SHIP"], [144, 148, "SPEC"], [176, 183, "PER"], [189, 193, "SPEC"], [354, 363, "SHIP"], [403, 408, "LOC"], [410, 419, "ORG"], [445, 449, "SPEC"], [495, 503, "SPEC"], [508, 516, "SPEC"], [616, 620, "SPEC"], [663, 670, "PER"], [693, 697, "SPEC"], [824, 828, "SPEC"], [942, 949, "PER"], [993, 1000, "PER"], [1042, 1049, "LOC"], [1201, 1209, "PER"], [1338, 1345, "PER"], [1413, 1420, "PER"], [1494, 1504, "PER"], [1448, 1452, "ORG"], [1607, 1613, "ORG"], [1617, 1633, "ORG"], [1745, 1749, "PER"], [1776, 1783, "PER"], [1794, 1808, "PER"], [1811, 1815, "ORG"], [1982, 1989, "PER"], [2022, 2026, "SPEC"], [2157, 2167, "SHIP"], [2180, 2185, "LOC"], [2187, 2210, "PER"], [2233, 2257, "PER"], [2279, 2302, "PER"], [2308, 2315, "PER"], [2333, 2343, "SHIP"], [2383, 2390, "PER"], [2476, 2480, "SPEC"], [2503, 2511, "LOC"], [2533, 2537, "SPEC"], [2568, 2576, "SPEC"], [2609, 2618, "ORG"], [2686, 2704, "LOC"], [2715, 2722, "PER"], [2803, 2807, "SPEC"], [2814, 2820, "PER"], [2834, 2841, "PER"], [2862, 2869, "PER"], [2903, 2910, "PER"], [2916, 2923, "PER"], [2950, 2956, "PER"], [2961, 2966, "PER"], [3008, 3014, "PER"], [3018, 3023, "PER"], [3044, 3069, "PER"], [3087, 3091, "PER"], [3095, 3101, "PER"], [3103, 3110, "PER"], [3184, 3190, "LOC"], [3201, 3207, "PER"], [3212, 3217, "PER"], [3255, 3262, "PER"], [3269, 3275, "PER"], [3293, 3300, "PER"], [3406, 3410, "PER"], [3368, 3376, "SPEC"], [3424, 3431, "PER"], [3468, 3483, "PER"], [3487, 3493, "LOC"], [3500, 3506, "PER"], [3520, 3533, "LOC"], [3539, 3554, "PER"], [3587, 3593, "PER"], [3595, 3600, "PER"], [3633, 3637, "PER"], [3642, 3646, "PER"], [3760, 3766, "PER"], [3770, 3774, "PER"], [3912, 3916, "PER"], [3929, 3936, "PER"], [4039, 4043, "PER"], [4297, 4306, "ORG"], [4339, 4345, "PER"], [4684, 4698, "PER"], [4738, 4747, "ORG"], [4748, 4755, "PER"], [4770, 4777, "PER"], [4786, 4801, "PER"], [4804, 4810, "PER"], [4814, 4836, "LOC"], [4862, 4869, "LOC"], [4880, 4887, "PER"], [4922, 4931, "PER"], [4968, 4974, "PER"], [4978, 4983, "PER"], [4940, 4953, "ORG"], [5027, 5039, "LOC"], [5058, 5065, "PER"], [5069, 5092, "PER"], [5119, 5126, "PER"], [5402, 5409, "PER"], [5467, 5473, "PER"], [5552, 5570, "PER"], [5824, 5847, "PER"], [5891, 5898, "PER"], [5939, 5962, "PER"], [5970, 5980, "GPE"], [6050, 6055, "PER"], [6069, 6087, "PER"], [6093, 6102, "SHIP"], [5990, 6000, "SHIP"], [6124, 6131, "PER"], [6145, 6150, "PER"], [6192, 6199, "PER"], [6273, 6279, "PER"], [6430, 6440, "SHIP"], [6447, 6453, "PER"], [6455, 6460, "PER"], [6485, 6506, "PER"], [6566, 6571, "PER"], [6579, 6595, "PER"], [6619, 6629, "PER"], [6687, 6702, "PER"], [6735, 6741, "PER"], [6793, 6801, "PER"], [6848, 6854, "PER"], [6856, 6861, "PER"], [6906, 6913, "PER"], [6930, 6939, "ORG"], [6970, 6976, "PER"], [7180, 7190, "GPE"], [7215, 7219, "SPEC"], [7229, 7235, "SHIP"], [7321, 7325, "SPEC"], [7347, 7351, "SPEC"], [7368, 7387, "LOC"], [7438, 7443, "PER"], [7445, 7451, "PER"], [7522, 7526, "SPEC"], [7574, 7584, "SHIP"], [7592, 7598, "PER"], [7600, 7605, "PER"], [7661, 7665, "SPEC"], [7821, 7826, "PER"], [7828, 7834, "PER"], [7857, 7864, "PER"], [7926, 7930, "SPEC"], [7946, 7961, "LOC"], [7982, 7986, "SPEC"], [8102, 8112, "SHIP"], [8148, 8154, "PER"], [8156, 8161, "PER"], [8211, 8216, "PER"], [8237, 8243, "PER"], [8245, 8250, "PER"], [8290, 8297, "PER"], [8339, 8349, "SHIP"], [8359, 8371, "LOC"], [8404, 8409, "PER"], [8411, 8417, "PER"], [8443, 8460, "PER"], [8542, 8548, "PER"], [8662, 8666, "SPEC"], [8754, 8764, "SHIP"], [8771, 8776, "PER"], [8793, 8808, "PER"], [8841, 8845, "PER"], [8886, 8893, "PER"], [8900, 8905, "PER"], [8907, 8911, "PER"], [9069, 9073, "PER"], [9075, 9080, "PER"], [9136, 9140, "PER"], [9152, 9156, "PER"], [9168, 9177, "PER"], [9190, 9194, "SPEC"], [9318, 9327, "PER"], [9416, 9430, "PER"], [9451, 9456, "PER"], [9559, 9566, "PER"], [9534, 9546, "PER"], [9576, 9585, "PER"], [9685, 9699, "PER"], [9676, 9683, "LOC"], [9653, 9665, "PER"], [9722, 9735, "PER"], [9738, 9745, "PER"], [9766, 9772, "PER"], [9778, 9786, "PER"], [9796, 9803, "LOC"], [9827, 9833, "LOC"], [9836, 9842, "PER"], [9850, 9856, "ORG"], [9858, 9868, "PER"], [9897, 9903, "PER"], [9981, 9988, "PER"], [10004, 10008, "SPEC"], [10023, 10030, "PER"], [10113, 10118, "PER"], [10120, 10126, "PER"], [10158, 10163, "PER"], [10216, 10222, "ORG"], [10226, 10233, "PER"], [10280, 10285, "PER"], [10442, 10459, "PER"], [10465, 10474, "LOC"], [10497, 10511, "PER"], [10539, 10546, "PER"], [10548, 10553, "PER"], [10628, 10637, "PER"], [10644, 10650, "PER"], [10687, 10691, "SPEC"], [10805, 10810, "PER"], [10835, 10842, "PER"], [10920, 10925, "PER"], [10927, 10933, "PER"], [10944, 10949, "PER"], [10974, 10979, "PER"], [11003, 11010, "PER"], [11087, 11092, "PER"], [11094, 11098, "PER"], [11122, 11127, "PER"], [11169, 11173, "SPEC"], [11223, 11240, "PER"], [11320, 11325, "PER"], [11345, 11349, "PER"], [11352, 11361, "PER"], [11565, 11571, "PER"], [11576, 11581, "PER"], [11603, 11609, "LOC"], [11624, 11630, "PER"], [11666, 11676, "SHIP"], [11713, 11719, "PER"], [11729, 11736, "PER"], [11759, 11765, "PER"], [11767, 11771, "PER"], [11789, 11796, "PER"], [11859, 11866, "PER"], [11914, 11918, "PER"], [11945, 11951, "PER"], [11961, 11971, "SHIP"], [12010, 12014, "SPEC"], [12085, 12092, "PER"], [12227, 12239, "PER"], [12241, 12247, "PER"], [12263, 12275, "PER"], [12311, 12323, "PER"], [12338, 12345, "PER"], [12451, 12463, "PER"], [12465, 12470, "PER"], [12484, 12490, "PER"], [12541, 12551, "SHIP"], [12558, 12563, "PER"], [12569, 12575, "PER"], [12720, 12736, "LOC"], [12748, 12754, "PER"], [12789, 12795, "PER"], [12799, 12810, "ORG"], [12812, 12822, "PER"], [12887, 12891, "SPEC"], [12942, 12949, "PER"], [12973, 12980, "PER"], [12984, 12990, "ORG"], [13031, 13038, "PER"], [13044, 13048, "SPEC"], [13142, 13149, "PER"], [13156, 13162, "PER"], [13164, 13168, "PER"], [13181, 13185, "SPEC"], [13215, 13219, "SPEC"], [13398, 13408, "SHIP"], [13438, 13442, "PER"], [13482, 13495, "PER"], [13544, 13551, "PER"], [13645, 13649, "SPEC"], [13662, 13666, "SPEC"], [13685, 13690, "LOC"], [13705, 13709, "SPEC"], [13599, 13605, "LOC"], [13750, 13763, "PER"], [13828, 13834, "LOC"], [13837, 13844, "PER"], [13872, 13876, "PER"], [13878, 13891, "PER"], [13939, 13953, "PER"], [14020, 14024, "PER"], [14060, 14066, "PER"], [14255, 14269, "PER"], [14274, 14287, "PER"], [14307, 14311, "SPEC"], [14457, 14464, "PER"], [14478, 14484, "PER"], [14486, 14494, "PER"], [14567, 14574, "PER"], [14623, 14629, "LOC"], [14643, 14657, "PER"], [14666, 14670, "SPEC"], [14704, 14711, "PER"], [14758, 14762, "SPEC"], [14812, 14818, "PER"], [14848, 14866, "PER"], [14927, 14935, "PER"], [14954, 14959, "PER"], [14993, 14999, "PER"], [15005, 15009, "SPEC"], [15082, 15089, "LOC"], [15139, 15149, "PER"], [15275, 15281, "PER"], [15297, 15302, "PER"], [15543, 15548, "PER"], [15550, 15556, "PER"], [15670, 15676, "PER"], [15678, 15683, "PER"], [15689, 15695, "PER"], [15736, 15750, "PER"], [15921, 15926, "PER"], [15935, 15941, "PER"], [15960, 15964, "SPEC"], [16048, 16055, "PER"]]}
{"id": 630, "text": "PART 2\n Captain Jean-Luc Picard and Captain Mark Smith stood at a critical turning point. The Borg had placed a demand for Captain Smith. Captain Picard knew that handing him over would only mean that the Borg would chase the Enterprise until they recaptured him. Picard also had a hostage situation on deck 14 where the malicious Borg queen had transported scores of drones aboard as leverage to get what they wanted. Picard was trying to maintain control of a hot-headed Captain Smith who wanted to rescue the remnants of his crew. “If you have my crew, show me” demanded Smith. The Borg queen didn’t respond, other than moving aside to show two drones holding a struggling figure of a woman in the same uniform as him. “Mark” came the struggled gasps of the woman. Again Captain Smith fell to his knees as he recognised Lieutenant Commander Alyssa Smith, his wife”. The Borg queen again stepped back into the picture, “Will you join us, Smith” asked the queen, knowing she had the Enterprise crew and Smith backed into a corner. Knowing the situation was beyond him, Smith looked to Picard, “Captain” he said, resigned and defeated. Picard looked to him, “I cannot allow you to leave this ship, the Borg will just come after us again regardless, but then again, I cannot expect you to abandon your crew” said Picard, “Sir, we can’t save them” said Smith, “The Enterprise is more important” he said. Riker exploded, “How can you abandon them to assimilation”. Smith glared at him, “I don’t do it easily, Commander, that’s my wife on the screen, but here and now I have a duty as a Starfleet officer” he said. He turned to the screen, “My love, I’m sorry” he said, head sinking, before turning his attention to the Borg queen, “Go to hell, you skinny mechanic bitch” he growled. The drone holding Lieutenant Commander Smith lifted its hand, injecting the nanites into her blood stream. She screamed, the pain unbearable as the Borg nanites began to alter her. Her scream was not long-lived. Soon only a shell of the former human remained. “Locutus, you will be ours again, Smith, you will make an excellent drone” said the queen, closing the channel. A sniffle escaped Smith.\n Worf was intently watching the sensors throughout the whole exchange, nothing had really changed until now, “Captain, Borg weapons systems charging” he said. Picard wasted no time, “Helm, Warp 4, engage” he shouted. The Enterprise leapt away to warp 4. “Captain, receiving a distress transmission from deck 14” said Worf. Picard stood up, “Are the Borg following us from Earth” he asked. Worf checked the sensors, “Yes, Captain, closing at warp 7” said Worf. “Increase to maximum warp” he said, “Lets lead them away from Earth, Mr Worf, scan deck 14, I want to know what’s going on down there” said Picard. Worf worked the sensors, “Captain, visual contact” said Worf. “On screen” said Picard. The corridor was dark, drones moved around assimilating crewmembers of the Enterprise. Picard and the Bridge crew watched in horror, “Survivors” asked Riker. “None, Commander, all either assimilated or in the process of being assimilated” said Worf. The bridge was silent, “Vent deck 14” ordered Picard. The crew rippled, “Captain” said Commander Riker, “Number one, venting deck 14 might spare the crew a living hell, I’m doing it to save the Enterprise” said Picard. Worf keyed in the command sequence, “Ready, Captain” he said, indicating that the deck was primed for venting. “Make it so, Commander” said Picard. Worf punched it in. “Venting complete, Captain” said Riker, “Nothing is alive down there” he finished.\n The Borg cube pursued the Enterprise relentlessly. The Borg queen was hell bent, if you could consider her hell bent, on capturing Locutus and Captain Smith. The Enterprise was going at maximum cruise speed. She watched as the Enterprise drew closer as the Borg ship was outrunning her. She could picture the resistance that Locutus and Smith would put up as they were assimilated into the Collective. If you could call what she felt pleasure, she had a pleasurable anticipation of the assimilation to come.\n Back on the Enterprise, Captain Picard watched the Borg ship closing in, “What is our current velocity” he asked. “Warp 9.2, Sir” reported Data, “Increase to Warp 9.8” said Picard. Smith stood up, “Captain, Warp 9.8 puts the Enterprise at extreme risk, especially given that the Borg are pursuing us” said Captain Smith. Picard looked over at him, “What are you suggesting, Mr Smith” he asked. “Mr Data, show me a map of the region” said Captain Smith. The map came up at Data’s station. “There, the Archanis Nebula, if we head there at Warp 9.6, we can be there in about 11 hours. With that Borg cube as badly damaged as it is, it is unlikely that they will be able to go much faster that Warp 9.6” said Smith. Picard nodded, “Make it so” he said, returning to the command chair.\n The Borg queen experienced something that could be likened to rage and frustration. The Enterprise had increased speed to Warp 9.6 and with the damage caused by the impact with the Lexington meant that the cube could not outpace the Enterprise. The only way they would out run the ship is if they carried on for more than 12 hours and had to drop out of warp. The entire collective consciousness of the Borg was focused on the Enterprise and little more.\n 10 hours 53 minutes 23 seconds later\n The Enterprise dropped out of warp and headed into the nebula. Commander Riker stood next to Data’s station, “Captain, this nebula has a high level of Particle Flux, we can’t stay in here long” he said. Picard nodded, “How long do we have, Number one” he said, gravely. Riker looked at the screen, “24 minutes, Captain”. “Take us to the edge of the nebula, Mr Worf, prepare a full spread of Photon torpedoes to fire straight into the damaged section of the Borg cube” said Captain Picard. “Aye, Sir” said Worf. The Enterprise moved out at half impulse, Worf ready to unleash the Enterprise’s weapons systems on the Borg ship. When they reached the edge of the Nebula, there was no Borg ship. “Full sensor scan” said Picard. Data performed the Scan, “Captain Smith, please have a look at this information” said Data. Smith had a look, “Captain, the Borg vessel has set a course for Starbase 245, it looks like it’s just approaching the edge of sensor range, so presume it’s moving at Warp 9.7” said Captain Smith. Picard looked shocked, “Bridge to Engineering, Geordi, what is the effect on the warp engines from our prolonged travel at warp 9.6” he said, “We have to keep power output of the warp engines to a minimum, Captain, I suggest you don’t push her faster than warp 7”  said Geordi LaForge. Picard turned to Data, “Mr Data, how soon could we be there at warp 7” he said, “2 hours 28 minutes 45 seconds, Sir” said Data, “Helm, lay in a pursuit course, Engage” said Picard.\n Starbase 245\n Commodore Andre Heston was the base commander of Starbase 245. It was a quiet assignment as Starfleet had always routed invading forces before they approached the base. Today however, they were watching the sensors as they showed a Borg vessel approaching at high warp with no Federation Starships to route it. The Commodore watched as the crew bustled to the final preparations, making sure the weapons and shields were active. “Sir, Borg vessel arrival in 2 minutes” said an officer. This was it, the battle was afoot and there was nothing anyone could do about it. Moments later, the gargantuan cube dropped out of warp. Without warning it savagely attacked the Starbase. Within moments officers were reporting shield failures and hull breaches. After a meagre 7 minutes, the station was little more than a debris field. The Borg cube silently moved off, hoping to lure the Enterprise towards them.\n 2 hours 21 minutes later\n The USS Enterprise dropped out of warp 50000 kilometres away from the debris field that was Starbase 245. “My God” said Captain Smith looking at the devastation left in the wake of the Borg. “Captain, the Borg are trying to lure us into a trap. Judging by the continuing trail away from this site, it is the only conceivable solution”. Riker thought hard, “We need reinforcements, Captain, but we can’t take the Enterprise back into Federation space. The Borg would just follow” he said. “Mr Worf, what is the nearest Starship to our location” he said. Worf checked, “The Galaxy, Sir” he responded. “Open a channel” he ordered. Within seconds, the face of Captain Alex Bertrum was on the screen, “Captain Picard, how can we help you” he said, “We need to get an officer back to Earth to brief the Council about a Borg invasion. But I can’t take the Enterprise back in to Federation Space, could you rendezvous with us” asked Picard, “Certainly, Captain, set a course to meet us and we will do the same, rendezvous in 3 hours, Galaxy out”  said Captain Bertrum. “Helm, lay in an intercept course and engage at warp 6” said Picard, “All senior officers, report to the bridge” said Riker.\n Picard, Riker, Data and Worf walked into the observation lounge. Picard took the seat at the head of the table and waited, the tension palpable between the officers. Moments later, Doctor “Commander” Beverley Crusher, Lieutenant Commander Geordi LaForge and Councillor “Lieutenant Commander” Deanna Troi walked into the briefing room. When they were all seated. “For those who haven’t met our new crewmate, this is Captain Mark Smith. He commands the Federation Starship Lexington about 30 years from now and was only sent back when he intersected with a temporal distortion” said Picard, introducing Smith. There was a ripple of recognition as they all recognised the 41 year old version of the boy who still regularly saw Councillor Troi and Doctor Crusher. “Good Morning” said Smith, formally to the people who had helped raise him to what he was. “As you know the Borg are trying to lure this ship into a trap in an attempt to acquire Captain Smith and myself, so we can’t fly back to Earth, without bringing the Borg down on us. So we are setting a course to rendezvous with the USS Galaxy. I will go aboard the Galaxy and we will head back to Earth at maximum warp. Commander Riker and Captain Smith will assume control of the ship, with Captain Smith leading the Borg away” said Picard. Picard turned to Smith, inviting him to talk, “I know it won’t be easy, taking orders from someone you perceive to be a small boy, but I promise you, I will do everything I can to keep this ship safe. I would welcome any suggestions you might have while I’m in Command” said Smith. Picard turned back to the crew, “We rendezvous with the Galaxy in 3 hours, Captain Smith please stay, the rest of you return to your duties” he said. Captain Smith remained seated alongside Captain Picard. “Captain, what I’m about to do is dangerous. When I was assimilated by the Borg, they assimilated my thought patterns and its possible that wherever they are they know what I’m planning, or at least they can guess” he said. He looked distant for a moment, and Smith knew what pressure this was putting on the Captain. “I’m going to send a report to the Admiralty explaining who you are, but I’m going to classify it top secret, so you will have to get into a Starfleet uniform like what the crew wears. I also would like you to keep a sensor lock on the USS Galaxy for as long as you can in case the Borg attack. Are you prepared to command my ship, Captain” said Picard, “Aye, Sir” said Smith, “Computer, transfer all command functions to Captain Smith, authorization Picard Alpha Tango” said Picard. “There is no Authorization for Captain Smith, please enter the relevant information” said the computer. “Computer, enter authorization code Smith Zulu five” said Smith, “Register information under Captain Mark Smith” said Smith. “Command functions transferred to Captain Mark Smith” said the cool voice of the computer. “The Enterprise is now your ship, Captain” said Picard. Smith smiled sadly, “The Enterprise will always be your ship, Captain, I will just be another chapter in hers and your story, Sir” said Captain Smith.\n 3 hours later\n The USS Galaxy was holding position just off the starboard bow awaiting Captain Picard’s arrival. “Smith to Transporter room two, is Captain Picard ready to disembark” he said, “Yes, Sir, just waiting for confirmation from the Galaxy, Sir” replied Miles O’Brien. Smith settled into his chair and his new uniform. “As soon as you have confirmation from the Galaxy, beam Captain Picard over” he said, “Yes, Sir” said O’Brien.\n Captain Smith was somewhat uncomfortable. The universe was in a state of temporal flux that none could predict and he and Captain Picard were now right at the centre of things. A single mistake could result in the destruction of the Enterprise, writing the rest of history for the Federation in a completely different manner, it could even destroy the Federation. As the report came in that Captain Picard had been transported to the other ship, Smith ordered that a wide band covariant signal be transmitted on all frequencies and that the ship move away at warp 6. As far as all intelligence aboard the Enterprise, only one Borg vessel had been reported, so that meant they had to keep it busy until Picard could muster the fleet to destroy it.  “Captain, Borg vessel approaching from heading 232 mark 4” said Worf, his deep voice rumbling across the bridge, “Hold your course, Mr Evans” ordered Smith as the crew rippled with unease. “Mr Worf, Report” he said  turning to look at his tactical officer. Worf checked the sensors, “Borg vessel is approaching at warp 9.1 , visual contact in ten seconds, its weapons are fully charged” said Worf. Smith sighed, “On Screen” he said. The image showed a Borg vessel, but it looked to be too small to be a Borg cube. “Magnify” he said. The magnified image showed a Borg sphere, “Damn” shouted Smith, “Mr Evans, drop out of warp, Mr Data, contact the Galaxy, warn them that they might be at risk of attack” said Smith. “Time to intercept, 1 minute, 24 seconds”  said Worf. “Red Alert, all hands to battle stations” said Riker. “Captain, I am unable to raise communications with the Galaxy” said Data. “Sensors show a second Borg signal on an intercept course with the Galaxy” said Worf, as the Borg sphere dropped out of warp. “Mr Worf, fire a full spread of photons and phasers at a concentrated section of that vessel” he said, “Helm, lay in an intercept course for the USS Galaxy, maximum warp” he said. He watched dispassionately as Worf’s barrage of weapon fire slammed into the Borg vessel, ripping it apart. “Helm, the USS Galaxy, engage” he said, urgency gripping him.\n The Enterprise jumped to warp. “ETA on the Galaxy” he said, “12 minutes, Captain” said the helm officer, “Maintain course and speed” he said, “Senior officers, report to the bridge” said Smith. He turned to Commander Riker, “Mr Riker, when we complete this briefing, I want  you and Mr Worf to prepare a fully armed security detail and lead it over to the Galaxy if I see fit” said Smith. “Aye, Sir are you expecting trouble” said Riker, “Yes, Commander” he turned to Councillor Troi, “Councillor, what do you imagine the news of an imminent threat to the Federation would do to the crew” he said, “ Panic them, and if we are wrong, it would cause resent and the crew would be bristling under your command” said Troi. Smith sighed, “Options, we are facing a real and present danger from the Borg and I cannot in good consciousness keep them in the dark” he said. Smith wished he had Picard’s wisdom in this situation, “We are informing the crew, I’ll address them at the proper moment” he said as the bridge turbolift doors hissed open and the senior officers stepped out. “This is a critical briefing, it will be given to all hands, open internal communications link” he said. He sighed, “All hands this is the bridge, there is an extreme risk to the Federation. We just lost contact with the USS Galaxy which Captain Picard transferred to in order to warn Earth of the impending Borg attack. We have reason to believe that the Galaxy is under attack from a Borg cube and are therefore setting a course to intercept, I want all stations battle ready in 4 minutes” he said, closing the internal comms. “I need to options. The Enterprise may be out matched by the Borg and I need ways to keep her in the fight. Mr LaForge, Mr Data, work on a way of increasing shields and weapons to compensate for the adaptive nature of the Borg, Commander Riker, Mr Worf, I need tactical strategies in place. Captain Picard may still be in a position where we can rescue him and so we must try to do so. The future of the Federation may depend on it” he said, “Doctor Crusher, Captain Picard may be injured if we can retrieve him, and the battle may cause injuries across the ship, I want your medical teams on full standby” he said as Doctor Crusher nodded her assent. “Councillor Troi, I need you to remain on the bridge, with the rest of the senior staff off the bridge, I’ll need you to act as my first officer” he said, Troi looked worried, but accepted his orders, “Captain, we are approaching the USS Galaxy I’m not reading any Borg vessels” said the Helmsman, “Slow to 1/3” he said. “Mr Worf, open a channel, we shouldn’t have met the Galaxy so soon” he said. Turning his attention to the Galaxy, he said “Enterprise to Galaxy”. There was no response, “Enterprise to Galaxy, please respond” still nothing, “Mr Worf, intensive scan” he said. Worf scanned the Galaxy, “Nothing out of the ordinary, Captain”. Then the first shot came. “Captain, we are being hailed” said Worf, “On screen” shouted Captain Smith.\n The Borg queen observed the crew of the USS Enterprise with an almost excited disposition. She knew that they would be demoralized when they saw her, and even more demoralized to see who accompanied her and what she had done to him.  It pleased her to have so many new ‘children’ in her fold. “You, what the hell are you playing at” said Captain Smith. “Perfecting the galaxy” replied the queen cryptically. “Where is Captain Picard” demanded Smith.\n The bridge crew of the Enterprise were bristling at the appearance of the Borg queen on the USS Galaxy. The Borg queen hadn’t responded to Captain Smith’s question as to the whereabouts of Captain Picard. Suddenly she stepped aside. A figure stepped forward, “I am Locutus of Borg, lower your shields and surrender your ship, resistance is futile”\n To be continued…", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[8, 31, "PER"], [36, 54, "PER"], [94, 98, "SPEC"], [123, 136, "PER"], [138, 152, "PER"], [205, 209, "SPEC"], [226, 236, "SHIP"], [264, 270, "PER"], [303, 310, "LOC"], [331, 335, "SPEC"], [419, 425, "PER"], [473, 486, "PER"], [574, 579, "PER"], [585, 589, "SPEC"], [723, 727, "PER"], [774, 787, "PER"], [823, 856, "PER"], [873, 877, "SPEC"], [940, 945, "PER"], [984, 994, "SHIP"], [1004, 1009, "PER"], [1070, 1075, "PER"], [1086, 1092, "PER"], [1095, 1102, "PER"], [1136, 1142, "PER"], [1202, 1206, "SPEC"], [1312, 1318, "PER"], [1351, 1356, "PER"], [1363, 1373, "SHIP"], [1402, 1407, "PER"], [1462, 1467, "PER"], [1506, 1515, "PER"], [1583, 1592, "ORG"], [1716, 1720, "SPEC"], [1798, 1824, "PER"], [1928, 1932, "SPEC"], [2041, 2048, "PER"], [2024, 2029, "SPEC"], [2074, 2079, "PER"], [2170, 2175, "PER"], [2178, 2182, "PER"], [2287, 2294, "PER"], [2296, 2300, "SPEC"], [2336, 2342, "PER"], [2366, 2372, "LOC"], [2398, 2408, "SHIP"], [2480, 2487, "LOC"], [2526, 2530, "SPEC"], [2432, 2439, "PER"], [2494, 2498, "PER"], [2500, 2506, "PER"], [2549, 2554, "LOC"], [2566, 2570, "PER"], [2598, 2605, "PER"], [2631, 2635, "PER"], [2699, 2704, "LOC"], [2706, 2713, "PER"], [2720, 2727, "LOC"], [2777, 2783, "PER"], [2785, 2789, "PER"], [2811, 2818, "PER"], [2841, 2845, "PER"], [2864, 2870, "PER"], [2947, 2957, "SHIP"], [2959, 2965, "PER"], [2974, 2985, "ORG"], [3023, 3028, "PER"], [3037, 3046, "PER"], [3116, 3120, "PER"], [3126, 3132, "ORG"], [3168, 3174, "PER"], [3195, 3202, "PER"], [3209, 3224, "PER"], [3247, 3254, "LOC"], [3316, 3326, "SHIP"], [3333, 3339, "PER"], [3341, 3345, "PER"], [3385, 3392, "PER"], [3465, 3474, "PER"], [3481, 3487, "PER"], [3489, 3493, "PER"], [3528, 3535, "PER"], [3542, 3547, "PER"], [3597, 3601, "SPEC"], [3619, 3629, "SHIP"], [3648, 3652, "SPEC"], [3724, 3731, "PER"], [3736, 3749, "PER"], [3755, 3765, "SHIP"], [3820, 3830, "SHIP"], [3850, 3854, "SPEC"], [3918, 3925, "PER"], [3930, 3935, "PER"], [3983, 3993, "ORG"], [4114, 4124, "SHIP"], [4126, 4140, "PER"], [4153, 4157, "SPEC"], [4241, 4245, "PER"], [4275, 4281, "PER"], [4283, 4288, "PER"], [4300, 4307, "PER"], [4408, 4421, "PER"], [4423, 4429, "PER"], [4476, 4484, "PER"], [4497, 4504, "PER"], [4540, 4553, "PER"], [4574, 4580, "PER"], [4602, 4617, "LOC"], [4381, 4385, "SPEC"], [4327, 4337, "SHIP"], [4694, 4698, "SPEC"], [4807, 4812, "PER"], [4814, 4820, "PER"], [4888, 4892, "SPEC"], [4972, 4982, "SHIP"], [5065, 5074, "SHIP"], [5117, 5127, "SHIP"], [5287, 5291, "SPEC"], [5311, 5321, "SHIP"], [5382, 5392, "SHIP"], [5441, 5456, "PER"], [5471, 5477, "PER"], [5488, 5495, "PER"], [5581, 5587, "PER"], [5648, 5653, "PER"], [5689, 5696, "PER"], [5735, 5742, "PER"], [5835, 5839, "SPEC"], [5851, 5865, "PER"], [5883, 5887, "PER"], [5893, 5903, "SHIP"], [5931, 5935, "PER"], [5957, 5969, "PER"], [5993, 5997, "SPEC"], [6038, 6044, "LOC"], [6059, 6063, "SPEC"], [6094, 6100, "PER"], [6102, 6106, "PER"], [6128, 6141, "PER"], [6188, 6192, "PER"], [6194, 6199, "PER"], [6213, 6220, "PER"], [6226, 6230, "SPEC"], [6259, 6271, "LOC"], [6376, 6389, "PER"], [6391, 6397, "PER"], [6415, 6421, "ORG"], [6425, 6436, "ORG"], [6438, 6444, "PER"], [6597, 6604, "PER"], [6661, 6675, "PER"], [6677, 6683, "PER"], [6694, 6698, "PER"], [6701, 6708, "PER"], [6799, 6803, "PER"], [6850, 6856, "PER"], [6806, 6810, "ORG"], [6859, 6871, "LOC"], [6873, 6895, "PER"], [6922, 6934, "LOC"], [6965, 6974, "ORG"], [7105, 7109, "SPEC"], [7150, 7160, "GPE"], [7188, 7197, "PER"], [7308, 7312, "SPEC"], [7538, 7546, "LOC"], [7701, 7705, "SPEC"], [7750, 7760, "SHIP"], [7810, 7820, "SHIP"], [7894, 7906, "LOC"], [7922, 7935, "PER"], [7987, 7991, "SPEC"], [7994, 8001, "PER"], [8007, 8011, "SPEC"], [8138, 8143, "PER"], [8183, 8190, "PER"], [8214, 8224, "SHIP"], [8235, 8245, "GPE"], [8257, 8261, "SPEC"], [8291, 8298, "PER"], [8374, 8380, "SHIP"], [8458, 8478, "PER"], [8499, 8513, "PER"], [8580, 8585, "LOC"], [8599, 8606, "ORG"], [8615, 8619, "SPEC"], [8651, 8661, "SHIP"], [8673, 8689, "LOC"], [8727, 8733, "PER"], [8747, 8754, "PER"], [8828, 8834, "SHIP"], [8846, 8861, "PER"], [8864, 8868, "ORG"], [8981, 8986, "PER"], [8989, 8995, "PER"], [8997, 9002, "PER"], [9004, 9008, "PER"], [9013, 9017, "PER"], [9054, 9060, "PER"], [9170, 9205, "PER"], [9207, 9242, "PER"], [9247, 9292, "PER"], [9309, 9322, "LOC"], [9404, 9422, "PER"], [9440, 9450, "GPE"], [9460, 9469, "SHIP"], [9570, 9576, "PER"], [9590, 9595, "PER"], [9713, 9728, "PER"], [9733, 9747, "PER"], [9769, 9774, "PER"], [9857, 9861, "SPEC"], [9928, 9941, "PER"], [9978, 9983, "LOC"], [10006, 10010, "SPEC"], [10077, 10083, "SHIP"], [10106, 10112, "SHIP"], [10138, 10143, "LOC"], [10161, 10176, "PER"], [10181, 10194, "PER"], [10233, 10246, "PER"], [10259, 10263, "SPEC"], [10275, 10281, "PER"], [10283, 10289, "PER"], [10300, 10305, "PER"], [10558, 10563, "PER"], [10565, 10571, "PER"], [10621, 10627, "SHIP"], [10640, 10652, "PER"], [10715, 10728, "PER"], [10755, 10769, "PER"], [10772, 10779, "PER"], [10846, 10850, "SPEC"], [11031, 11036, "PER"], [11080, 11087, "PER"], [11124, 11133, "ORG"], [11230, 11239, "ORG"], [11329, 11335, "SHIP"], [11371, 11375, "SPEC"], [11421, 11428, "PER"], [11435, 11441, "PER"], [11459, 11464, "PER"], [11511, 11524, "PER"], [11565, 11571, "PER"], [11604, 11617, "PER"], [11735, 11740, "PER"], [11770, 11788, "PER"], [11795, 11800, "PER"], [11836, 11854, "PER"], [11898, 11908, "SHIP"], [11927, 11934, "PER"], [11941, 11947, "PER"], [11949, 11954, "PER"], [11974, 11984, "SHIP"], [12011, 12018, "PER"], [12085, 12098, "PER"], [12124, 12130, "SHIP"], [12188, 12204, "PER"], [12215, 12220, "PER"], [12224, 12244, "ORG"], [12249, 12263, "PER"], [12343, 12349, "SHIP"], [12364, 12377, "PER"], [12379, 12384, "PER"], [12472, 12478, "SHIP"], [12485, 12499, "PER"], [12531, 12538, "PER"], [12541, 12554, "PER"], [12663, 12677, "PER"], [12774, 12784, "SHIP"], [12822, 12832, "GPE"], [12893, 12903, "GPE"], [12932, 12946, "PER"], [12987, 12992, "PER"], [13146, 13156, "SHIP"], [13167, 13171, "SPEC"], [13243, 13249, "PER"], [13290, 13297, "PER"], [13299, 13303, "SPEC"], [13353, 13357, "PER"], [13394, 13400, "LOC"], [13421, 13429, "PER"], [13439, 13444, "PER"], [13479, 13486, "PER"], [13546, 13550, "PER"], [13573, 13577, "SPEC"], [13681, 13685, "PER"], [13687, 13692, "PER"], [13741, 13745, "SPEC"], [13792, 13796, "SPEC"], [13851, 13855, "SPEC"], [13879, 13884, "PER"], [13887, 13895, "PER"], [13915, 13922, "PER"], [13936, 13942, "SHIP"], [13997, 14002, "PER"], [14052, 14056, "PER"], [14105, 14110, "PER"], [14113, 14120, "PER"], [14167, 14173, "SHIP"], [14180, 14184, "PER"], [14209, 14213, "SPEC"], [14253, 14259, "SHIP"], [14266, 14270, "PER"], [14279, 14283, "SPEC"], [14313, 14320, "PER"], [14416, 14420, "ORG"], [14461, 14467, "SHIP"], [14522, 14528, "PER"], [14569, 14573, "SPEC"], [14601, 14605, "PER"], [14615, 14621, "SHIP"], [14667, 14677, "SHIP"], [14706, 14712, "SHIP"], [14736, 14743, "SPEC"], [14837, 14843, "LOC"], [14850, 14855, "PER"], [14870, 14885, "PER"], [14888, 14896, "PER"], [14946, 14953, "PER"], [15019, 15025, "SHIP"], [15045, 15050, "PER"], [15094, 15099, "PER"], [15107, 15116, "PER"], [15131, 15146, "PER"], [15149, 15159, "PER"], [15219, 15229, "GPE"], [15375, 15379, "PER"], [15381, 15386, "PER"], [15454, 15458, "SPEC"], [15526, 15531, "PER"], [15546, 15554, "PER"], [15875, 15881, "ORG"], [15915, 15925, "GPE"], [15961, 15967, "SHIP"], [15974, 15988, "PER"], [16021, 16026, "LOC"], [16044, 16048, "SPEC"], [16092, 16098, "SHIP"], [16122, 16126, "SPEC"], [16289, 16299, "SHIP"], [16326, 16330, "SPEC"], [16373, 16383, "PER"], [16385, 16392, "PER"], [16487, 16491, "SPEC"], [16493, 16508, "PER"], [16510, 16517, "PER"], [16556, 16570, "PER"], [16669, 16679, "GPE"], [16708, 16722, "PER"], [16724, 16738, "PER"], [16883, 16897, "PER"], [16918, 16933, "PER"], [17072, 17076, "PER"], [17119, 17126, "PER"], [17155, 17161, "SHIP"], [17182, 17186, "SPEC"], [17205, 17213, "PER"], [17239, 17246, "PER"], [17290, 17296, "SHIP"], [17344, 17350, "SHIP"], [17361, 17371, "SHIP"], [17375, 17381, "SHIP"], [17408, 17418, "SHIP"], [17422, 17428, "SHIP"], [17462, 17469, "PER"], [17496, 17500, "PER"], [17513, 17519, "SHIP"], [17551, 17558, "PER"], [17588, 17595, "PER"], [17623, 17627, "PER"], [17649, 17662, "PER"], [17669, 17673, "SPEC"], [17709, 17719, "SHIP"], [18003, 18016, "PER"], [18083, 18097, "PER"], [18108, 18113, "PER"], [18120, 18131, "ORG"], [18139, 18149, "SHIP"], [18190, 18194, "SPEC"], [18212, 18218, "SHIP"], [18224, 18228, "SPEC"], [18255, 18270, "PER"], [18305, 18319, "PER"], [18381, 18388, "PER"], [18392, 18396, "SPEC"]]}
{"id": 631, "text": "PART 3\n Captain Mark Alexander Smith stood on the bridge of the USS Enterprise looking at her former Captain. “Resistance is futile, lower your shields and surrender your ship. Your culture will adapt to service us” said Locutus, formerly Captain Picard, “No, we will not surrender, Locutus, you were taken from the Borg by this crew and restored to Captain Picard before” said Captain Smith. “The unit Picard is part of us, he cannot be removed” said Locutus, “Surrender is the only option” he said. Smith sighed, “Commander, prepare boarding parties to recover Captain Picard” he said, “Mr Worf, go with him” he said. Ensign Macaulay stepped up to replace Worf, “Ensign, target the Galaxy shields, Mr Data, do whatever you have to, to keep the Enterprise a step ahead of the Borg” he said. Weapons fire from the Galaxy hit the Enterprise first. The power of the shots quickly overwhelmed the defences, “Damage report” shouted Captain Smith. “Main power is offline” shouted Ensign Macaulay, “Shields and Weapons are inoperative, hull integrity down to 74%” shouted Data. “Helm, reverse course, full impulse” shouted Smith, “Manifolds can’t handle full impulse, Captain” shouted the helm officer. “Commander LaForge” shouted Smith, “I’ll be in Engineering” replied LaForge.\n Commander Riker was regaining his feet, “Riker to Bridge, what’s happening” said Riker, tapping his commbadge, “The Galaxy is attacking, we are taking heavy damage. I’m sorry, Commander, we have to pull back and focus on rescuing Captain Picard another time” said Smith, “Understood, Captain” said Riker. He steadied himself against another shot, “Mr Worf, what are the odds that the Borg try to board the ship” asked Riker, “High, Sir, the Borg only live to assimilate, it is their way” he said, “Take a security detachment and secure main engineering. I’ll take the rest and secure other key areas of the ship” said Riker, “Aye, Commander replied Worf. The officers walked in separate directions leading security detachments across the ship. As they went another volley of shots crippled secondary power, “Right, we won’t make it to the bridge, I suggest we head to sickbay and help Doctor Crusher keep the wounded alive and safe” said Riker.\n The bridge lights exploded, “Captain, impulse engines are offline” shouted Data, “I’ve lost helm control” shouted the Helm officer, “Secondary power systems are offline” shouted the stand-in tactical officer. The assault stopped, “Captain, incoming message from the Galaxy, audio only” reported Ensign Macaulay. “Let’s have it” demanded Captain Smith. “Witness the beginning, resistance is futile” said the voice of Locutus.\n Stardate 48922.81, Starfleet Headquarters, San Francisco\n Vice Admiral John Adamson was looking at the report given to him by Captain Michael Thornton, Commanding Officer of the USS Akira. “Captain, I want an account of everything” said the Admiral, “Sir, about 4 hours ago, we lost contact with the Starships Enterprise and Galaxy. Our sensors picked up massive amounts of weapons fire as well as Borg signatures. When everything died down, we detected a starship but we could not open a line of communication. Intensive scans showed it to be the Enterprise, she was maintaining position when we moved back to transmission range. Admiral, we are the only other starship within 4 days of the Enterprise, if the Borg are gathering forces in this area, we need more ships” said Captain Thornton. “Understood, Captain, you are to hold your position on the edge of the sector until reinforcements arrive. Monitor the Neutral Zone for any signs of the Romulans taking advantage of the weakened state of the Enterprise, Adamson Out” he said. He turned away from the viewscreen feeling uneasy. As the head of Fleet operations, Captain Jean-Luc Picard had filed a report about Captain Smith, and the position Picard was assigning him. With the Galaxy and Picard MIA and a heavy Borg presence being noted, along with the destruction of Starbase 245, the Admiral was becoming concerned with the security of the Federation.\n “Damn it, we were attacked 4 hours ago, Locutus could be anywhere by now and we have no way of contacting Starfleet” snapped Captain Smith, in what was left of Starboard observation. “Mr LaForge, status of the Engines” he said, “We think we have thrusters back, Captain, we need to test them before we can bring Impulse and Warp power back online” he said. He nodded, his temper subsiding slightly. “Mr Data, how are the sensors” he said, “We can only use short range sensors at the present time. All long range sensors have been destroyed” he said. Smith’s head dropped, “Find a way to reroute long range sensors through the short range sensor arrays, then transfer all power from the long range arrays back into shields and weapons. Mr LaForge, assist Mr Data when we are sure about the status of the Engines” he said. Riker pitched in, “Captain, Doctor Crusher is requesting that anyone with a level 2 medical qualification assist her teams in triage” he said. “Give her all the help she needs” ordered Smith. He turned his attention to Worf, “What about weapons” he said, “The phasers are being repaired as we speak. The torpedo firing system is online” he said. Smith sighed, “Very well, dismissed, prepare for engine trials” he said, joining the officers as they stepped onto the bridge. “Helm, forward thrusters to 50%, port and starboard at station keeping” he said. The thrusters activated, seemingly without fault, “LaForge to Bridge, Captain, the thrusters repairs are complete, I can give you partial impulse in 10 minutes and partial warp in 15 minutes”  said LaForge. Exhausted with the fatigue of defeat, Captain Smith turned to Councillor Troi, the most senior officer on the bridge at that time, “Councillor, you have the bridge, alert me if we run across the Galaxy” he said, walking into his ready room as Councillor Troi sat in the command chair.\n After a few hours of restlessness, he was thrown to the floor as an explosion rocked the ship. “Report” he said. Walking out onto the bridge, “Romulans” was the only reply, “Open a channel” ordered Smith. The stand in tactical officer was doing so, “No response, Captain”. Smith pondered, in his time, the Romulans were allies, he even had Romulan friends, but where he was now, they would attack and they would not consider being friends. They wanted a ship like the Enterprise.  “Back us off, use thrusters and impulse engines to get us inside that proto-stellar nebula” ordered Smith. “Captain, if we go in there, we will be cornered, if the Romulans leave, the Borg will just take their place” said Ensign Macaulay. “Agreed, very well, Ensign, helm go to warp 1 and get us away from Romulan space” ordered the Captain.\n The Enterprise repairs were going well, after 15 hours, weapons and shields were at 94% while Data and LaForge had managed to enhance the short range sensor arrays with long range equipment. Impulse engines had been fully repaired and Commander LaForge was preparing to unlock the magnetic constrictors and allow the full use of the warp drive. Commander Riker had returned to the bridge, but he had left security details at main engineering and sickbay ready for any Borg incursions. They were both sat in their chairs at the centre of the bridge. “Captain, our long range sensors have picked up unusual readings, I went to Stellar Cartography and ran a Quantum Spectral Analysis. The signatures are Borg, in about 3 days, the Viridian and Ceridian systems will be overwhelmed” said Riker, “I contacted Starfleet and forwarded the date I had, they are marshalling all ships to Sector 221 to engage, but I also found the Galaxy” he said. Smith looked at Riker, “Where is she” he said. Riker pulled up the data on a PADD. “The Goren sector, approaching Earth at maximum warp, accompanied by 2 Borg scout-ships” said Riker with a sigh. Smith looked at the data, “What’s their ETA” he said quietly. Riker looked at the information, “20 days 4 hours at maximum warp, Sir” said Riker. He stood slowly, “Captain, we have also been hailed by Admiral Rogers, we have been ordered to meet with the fleet at the edge of Sector 221” reported Data, “I can’t get a stable communications line due to interference from a plasma storm in that area” he reported. “Helm, lay in an intercept course for the Galaxy, warp 4.8” ordered Smith. The helm officer shot a look at Data, “Course plotted, Captain” reported the officer. “Engage” replied Smith, “Red alert” he finished, “Commander, I apologize, but hopefully this is an opportunity to rescue Captain Picard before he is destroyed. The timeline relies on it, so disregard any and all Starfleet Protocols. Submit the situation in your report” he said. Turning to the helm officer he said, “Ensign, ETA on the Galaxy”. The helm officer looked back, “At this speed 15 hours, but if we can get to maximum warp, I can do that in less than 4 hours” she said. Smith nodded, “Smith to LaForge” he said, tapping his communicator. “LaForge here” replied Lieutenant Commander LaForge. “Commander, can you have the constrictors unlocked in 1 hour” he asked, “Yes, Captain, I’m just finishing the preparation procedure, it’ll be done in about 20 minutes” reported LaForge. “Acknowledged” he said.\n Meanwhile, on Earth, “Admiral, we have just got a long range sensor report from the USS Rhode Island. We are seeing a ship that appears to be the USS Galaxy as well as the USS Enterprise” reported a Vulcan Commander. Admiral Robertson looked at the report, “What is the heading of the Galaxy” he asked. “They are on a direct course for sector 001, the Enterprise is on an intercept course” reported the Commander, “Get me the Enterprise” ordered the Admiral. Minutes later, the Enterprise bridge was on his monitor. “Admiral, what’s the situation” asked Commander Riker. “Where is Captain Smith” he said, remembering the report of Picard and the Galaxy crew being assimilated. “On his way, Admiral” replied Riker. “Commander, what the hell is going on” said Admiral Robertson. “The Galaxy is making a direct run at Sector 001 while the fleet is engaged at Sector 221. They have Borg escorts, we are pursuing in the hopes of recovering Captain Picard, the future of the Federation may depend on it” said Riker. “Do you require assistance, I can have ships meet you in 3 days” said the Admiral, “Not necessary, Admiral, the fleet will be needed where they are”. The Admiral nodded, “Robertson Out” he said.\n An hour later, the Enterprise was travelling at Warp 9.6 in an attempt to intercept the Galaxy and Captain Picard. The ship was only 2 and a half hours out travelling at current speeds. “I want shields set to rotating harmonics, weapons set to high-end EM frequencies, prepare anti-matter spreads to confuse their sensors. All emergency and secondary power to shields, reduce lighting in all areas of the ship to 15% and divert that energy to the weapons” ordered Captain Smith. “Reduce all non essential systems to minimal requirements and hold that energy in reserve” ordered Riker.\n 2 hours later\n The darkened bridge was comforting for Captain Smith. He was used to the bridge dimming at red alert to divert power to the weapons and shields, it felt like normal to have a darkened bridge again. “Captain, the Galaxy has altered course to intercept but its escorts are continuing on course to Sector 001” reported Worf. “What’s