{"id": 909, "text": "(This was written before Generations and does not acknowledge Kirk’s later\n demise)\n Also, and you’ll have to take my word for it, I wrote this before the\n episode “Relics”, so the holodeck scene with Scotty really is a coincidence.\n Hope you like it,\n Adrian Kleinbergen\n THE CHAINS OF COMMAND\n A STORY FROM THE STAR TREK UNIVERSE\n by\n Adrian Kleinbergen 1989/1995\n 8,052 words\n PROLOGUE\n “Jim,” the voice said, “are you listening?” The man standing before the\n observation window nodded.\n “I’m listening, Bones.” The man sighed and straightened his shoulders,\n which crackled as he moved.\n “The shuttle is waiting, and we have to go.” Leonard McCoy stated\n patiently. Two escorting security officers silently brought up the rear as\n the two men continued past the row of ceiling-high windows.\n “I hope this Jean-Luc Picard knows what he’s doing,” James Kirk muttered,\n “I hate being a passenger.”\n “We all become passengers in the end, Jim. Don’t get sensitive about it.\n This mission might be official fluff but it’s not exactly shore leave either.”\n “I know, Bones.I’m just upset at being used a figurehead.\n “Maybe so, Jim. Maybe so. There’s one consolation, at least.”\n “And what’s that?” Kirk stopped.\n “You’re going aboard the Enterprise.”\n I", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[62, 66, "PER"], [201, 207, "PER"], [253, 271, "PER"], [337, 355, "PER"], [391, 394, "PER"], [507, 512, "PER"], [637, 650, "PER"], [809, 824, "PER"], [849, 859, "PER"], [938, 941, "PER"], [1063, 1068, "PER"], [1124, 1127, "PER"], [1195, 1199, "PER"], [1235, 1245, "SHIP"]]}
{"id": 910, "text": "Captain’s Log, Stardate 7704.22\n “We are currently boarding dignitaries for the Romulan-Federation peace\n conference on Tinian, a planet within the Neutral Zone. Amongst these\n Starfleet diplomats, I’m proud to say, is none other than Admiral James T.\n Kirk, former commander of the first starship Enterprise, and retired\n Surgeon-General Leonard McCoy, Chief Medical Officer of the same. I’m\n looking forward to meeting these two distinguished men, especially Admiral\n Kirk.”  Picard hesitated for a moment, then concluded his log entry. “I have\n high hopes for the mutual success of the conference and I hope peace and\n cooperation can soon exist between the Federation and our former enemies.”\n “Bridge to Captain Picard,” Announced Commander Data from Picard’s\n communicator.\n “Picard here.”\n “Captain, Admirals Kirk and McCoy will be arriving at the shuttle bay in\n five minutes.”\n “Why the shuttle bay? Why not the transporter?”\n Picard questioned.\n “A special request from Admiral McCoy, Captain,” Data answered, “he has\n made this preference known before.”\n “Very well Mr. Data. I’ll meet them there, then. I wish Mr. Riker and\n yourself to accompany me.  Picard out.”\n Riker adjusted his uniform and smiled naturally at his own reflection as he\n smoothed away the last crease in the material. He loved the Starfleet dress\n uniform; he never felt more like a Starfleet officer than when duty\n compelled him to don the gold trimmed parade uniform. He checked himself\n over one more time and touched the communicator.\n “Data, I’m heading for the shuttle bay now, joining Captain Picard enroute.”\n “Affirmative, Commander,” came the crisp reply.\n Picard, Riker and Data entered the huge expanse of the shuttle deck as the\n similarly uniformed officers of the Enterprise’s command staff stood at", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[80, 87, "GPE"], [88, 98, "GPE"], [120, 126, "LOC"], [148, 160, "LOC"], [177, 186, "ORG"], [235, 257, "PER"], [298, 308, "SHIP"], [323, 352, "PER"], [354, 375, "PER"], [461, 474, "PER"], [478, 484, "PER"], [699, 705, "ORG"], [709, 723, "PER"], [661, 671, "GPE"], [736, 750, "PER"], [756, 762, "PER"], [782, 788, "PER"], [798, 805, "PER"], [807, 820, "PER"], [825, 830, "PER"], [855, 866, "LOC"], [896, 907, "LOC"], [921, 932, "LOC"], [936, 942, "PER"], [980, 993, "PER"], [995, 1002, "PER"], [1005, 1009, "PER"], [1077, 1085, "PER"], [1122, 1131, "PER"], [1164, 1170, "PER"], [1178, 1183, "PER"], [1315, 1324, "ORG"], [1367, 1376, "ORG"], [1526, 1530, "PER"], [1552, 1563, "LOC"], [1577, 1591, "PER"], [1617, 1626, "PER"], [1652, 1658, "PER"], [1660, 1665, "PER"], [1670, 1674, "PER"], [1764, 1774, "SHIP"]]}
{"id": 911, "text": "attention alongside the hastily laid out red carpet that stopped at the open\n hatch of the shuttlecraft Aristarchus. The bay was silent except for the\n soft footfalls of the three men as they approached the small craft.\n Kirk stepped out slowly and McCoy followed. They approached Picard and the\n group of command officers. Kirk looked around him, his eyes still sharp.\n “Big,” he whispered.\n “That’s an understatement, Jim,” Bones replied.\n Picard faced the two. Kirk smiled and spoke.\n “Permission to come aboard, Captain?”\n “Permission granted, Admiral,” Kirk smiled as he was piped aboard and\n grinned to himself. McCoy nodded silently at Kirk and extended his hand to\n Picard.\n “Welcome aboard, both of you. If you wish we can proceed with the\n inspection of the vessel, or postpone it until later if you wish to rest.”\n Picard continued carefully, “a long shuttle trip can be fatiguing.”\n “Not at all, Captain,” Kirk answered, unoffended, “I’m eager to see what\n this Enterprise can do.”\n “I’d like to see what passes for a ‘sickbay’ these days,” McCoy added\n sceptically, “Engineers. Always changing things.”\n Picard introduced his companions.\n “Admirals Kirk and McCoy, I’d like you to meet my first officer Commander\n Riker and my science officer Mr. Data.”  Handshakes were exchanged and McCoy\n looked keenly at Data.\n “I’ve met you before, son, haven’t I?”\n “This is true, sir. I escorted you to the starship Hood on the Enterprise’s\n maiden voyage. McCoy nodded with a grin.\n Kirk turned to address Riker.\n “How long have you served aboard the Enterprise, Commander?”\n “Seven years, Admiral. By the way, I’ve studied a lot of your books while\n in the Academy. Even the one’s that weren’t required reading.” Kirk laughed", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[104, 115, "SHIP"], [221, 225, "PER"], [249, 254, "PER"], [281, 287, "PER"], [324, 328, "PER"], [420, 423, "PER"], [426, 431, "PER"], [442, 448, "PER"], [464, 468, "PER"], [516, 523, "PER"], [548, 555, "PER"], [558, 562, "PER"], [618, 623, "PER"], [643, 647, "PER"], [674, 680, "PER"], [826, 832, "PER"], [908, 915, "PER"], [918, 922, "PER"], [974, 984, "SHIP"], [1053, 1058, "PER"], [1117, 1123, "PER"], [1153, 1166, "PER"], [1171, 1176, "PER"], [1216, 1232, "PER"], [1256, 1264, "PER"], [1298, 1303, "PER"], [1322, 1326, "PER"], [1420, 1424, "SHIP"], [1432, 1442, "SHIP"], [1461, 1466, "PER"], [1488, 1492, "PER"], [1511, 1516, "PER"], [1568, 1577, "PER"], [1556, 1566, "SHIP"], [1595, 1602, "PER"], [1663, 1670, "ORG"], [1719, 1723, "PER"], [121, 124, "LOC"]]}
{"id": 912, "text": "===============================================================\n Chapter One\n “Captain’s log, stardate 48039.5\n We are proceeding to starbase 141 for repairs and refits, as well as some\n minor changes in the crew. Since the plans to add a new weapon to Galaxy\n class starships have been cancelled when we found out that the Borg are no\n longer a threat, we are not expecting any major changes. The crew is\n scheduled for shore leave in the starbase’s recreational areas. After our\n recent strenuous missions, it will be a welcome change.”\n Though he would never admit it to the crew, Picard was looking forward to\n the leave, and hoped it wouldn’t be cancelled like their last promised off-\n time. Granted, their mission to explore the anomaly in the Romulan Neutral\n Zone had been important and urgent, but how many more urgent events could\n wait for his ship and crew?\n His old friend and Academy roommate in the first year, Admiral S’trel, was\n in command of starbase 141. It would be good to see him again.\n He stood up, and pulled his uniform jacket down. “I’ll be in my ready\n room. Number One, you have the bridge.”\n They were in the middle of Federation space. He would probably not be\n needed on the bridge until they arrived at the starbase. It would give him\n an opportunity to practice saying “SShSrsreowSrtSskr SsS KRkRst”, the\n Setallian greeting – back in the Academy, S’trel had always bugged Picard\n about not being able to give a proper welcome. The Setallian language,\n like the languages of most other sentient cat-like beings, was extremely\n hard to learn for humanoids. It had 42 different “s” sounds, and only two\n vowels. With the genaral availability of universal translators, the need\n to learn foreign languages had gone, but there were some things that could\n be expressed in other languages better than in Federation standard, and\n Picard had tried to know the basics of all important languages spoken in\n the Federation.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[133, 145, "LOC"], [324, 328, "SPEC"], [584, 590, "PER"], [751, 772, "LOC"], [891, 898, "ORG"], [927, 941, "PER"], [962, 974, "LOC"], [1076, 1087, "LOC"], [1089, 1099, "PER"], [1114, 1120, "ORG"], [1151, 1161, "GPE"], [1209, 1215, "LOC"], [1342, 1351, "SPEC"], [1375, 1382, "ORG"], [1384, 1390, "PER"], [1409, 1415, "PER"], [1468, 1477, "SPEC"], [1835, 1845, "GPE"], [1861, 1867, "PER"], [1939, 1949, "ORG"]]}
{"id": 913, "text": "While Picard practised, Data reviewed the results of the latest\n cybernetics conferences. Commander Maddox still served on starbase 141,\n and it would be a good opportunity to discuss android construction –\n procreation, he thought – with another expert.\n Riker sat in the captain’s chair without anything special to do – he knew\n what he’d do on the starbase, and it didn’t require preparation. Starbase\n 141 had been equipped with the latest holodeck technology, and after the\n Bynars had shown him what holodecks might be able to do, he didn’t pass up\n an opportunity to check out improved holodecks.\n “Estimated time of arrival, Ensign Seron?”, he asked.\n The Vulcan navigator replied, without looking up from his console, “At the\n current speed, without further delays, we will arrive at starbase 141 in\n fifty-nine minutes.” Seron’s mentioning of fifty-nine minutes reminded\n Riker of Data’s early days, and remembered his insistance on seconds\n whenever mentioning a time. He wondered if the Vulcan was just more\n inaccurate than an android, or whether he had just asked fifty-nine\n minutes and zero seconds before they would arrive.\n One more hour… Riker was tempted to let Data have the bridge, or to\n order Seron to increase speed, but he couldn’t find a professional excuse.\n The hour passed – extremely slowly, Riker thought – and the Enterprise\n docked at the starbase. Riker had decided to dock manually. It was a good\n training for the crew, and besides, it was less boring than just a routine\n automatic docking. Picard, Troi and LaForge were the first personnel to\n beam off the ship – before starting their time off, they had to co-\n ordinate the changes in the ship and crew with the starbase personnel.\n S’trel and two humanoids welcomed them.\n “Admiral”, Picard greeted his old friend. With his crew members around, he\n tried to be more formal than necessary.\n “Good to see you again, Jean-Luc. Apparently, some things have changed\n since we last met.” S’trel had never been a formal person – and he hadn’t", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[6, 12, "PER"], [24, 28, "PER"], [90, 106, "PER"], [123, 135, "LOC"], [256, 261, "PER"], [396, 409, "LOC"], [633, 645, "PER"], [664, 670, "SPEC"], [480, 486, "SPEC"], [793, 805, "LOC"], [831, 836, "PER"], [882, 887, "PER"], [891, 895, "PER"], [999, 1005, "PER"], [1157, 1162, "PER"], [1182, 1186, "PER"], [1217, 1222, "PER"], [1323, 1328, "PER"], [1347, 1357, "SHIP"], [1383, 1388, "PER"], [1529, 1535, "PER"], [1537, 1541, "PER"], [1546, 1553, "PER"], [1724, 1730, "PER"], [1766, 1773, "PER"], [1776, 1782, "PER"], [1906, 1914, "PER"], [1974, 1980, "PER"]]}
{"id": 914, "text": "expected to be called “Admiral” by his old friend (who had never liked\n being formal – back in the Academy). “These are my assistants, Lieutenant\n Commander Tyro of the personnel department, and Commander Taiara from\n Engineering. Jean-Luc, I don’t think your crew members will need you to\n discuss the changes.” He pointed his tail to his office door – a Setallian\n gesture to invite Picard in.\n Picard followed S’trel into the office, and said, “Yes, S’trel, some\n things have changed indeed… SShSrsreowSrtSskr SsS KRkRst.” His reference\n to changes was supposed to mean he had managed to get his Setallian\n greeting right, in all the years.\n “Oh, yes, of course.” S’trel reacted. “Back in academy days, your ‘s’ was\n better. Just how could I forget?”\n Picard noticed the doors closing behind them, and just before they were\n shut, he saw a grinning Geordi LaForge. He’d overheard their conversation.\n Damn. Just why couldn’t he have waited a few seconds longer…\n LaForge quickly regained control, and started discussing system upgrades\n with Taiara.\n ***\n Data beamed to the starbase shortly after. Though the android didn’t think\n it was necessary, Worf kept a transporter lock on him. The Chief of\n Security had insisted on taking some measures, just in case Maddox would\n get the idea to disassemble the android for research purposes. Worf was\n convinced that a person who had wanted to disassemble – to kill – one of\n “his” crew members, no matter how long ago it had been, couldn’t be\n trusted, though Data had forgiven Maddox. He thought that, over the time,\n Maddox had got to know him good enough to know he was more than just a\n fine piece of engineering and software programming, and he doubted Maddox\n would risk a life for his research. He was a fanatic scientist, and he’d\n dismantle a uniquely advanced computer for research purposes without\n problems, but he wouldn’t kill.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[23, 30, "PER"], [99, 106, "ORG"], [135, 161, "PER"], [195, 211, "PER"], [169, 189, "ORG"], [218, 229, "ORG"], [231, 239, "PER"], [356, 365, "SPEC"], [385, 391, "PER"], [397, 403, "PER"], [413, 419, "PER"], [453, 459, "PER"], [599, 608, "SPEC"], [667, 673, "PER"], [692, 699, "ORG"], [755, 761, "PER"], [852, 866, "PER"], [966, 973, "PER"], [1045, 1051, "PER"], [1059, 1063, "PER"], [1153, 1157, "PER"], [1194, 1212, "PER"], [1264, 1270, "PER"], [1341, 1345, "PER"], [1510, 1514, "PER"], [1528, 1534, "PER"], [1569, 1575, "PER"], [1708, 1714, "PER"]]}
{"id": 915, "text": "Mirror Vulcan, Mirror Not\n By Erin Blackwell\n Spock stood with his back completely straight, hands folded behind him, and\n wondered why he had allowed this to happen. He knew it would; there had\n been no margin of doubt. And yet, when it came time, he made sure the\n woman was assigned here with him.\n He had, however, warned her. He told her what she would be facing and\n suggested she might prefer to remain elsewhere in the Empire’s fleet. She had\n replied, quite logically, that she was already receiving the same treatment and\n she preferred an assignment with him.\n And, as he well knew, he needed her. He needed a new Chief for his personal\n guard, someone utterly loyal and totally committed to him. It had to be\n someone he could trust and she was the only one he trusted now. If he was to\n move any further in the challenge given him by the parallel Kirk, he had to\n have just such a person with him. So he had agreed and arranged the\n assignment.\n Saavik stood in front of Kirk for her first inspection. His eyes were travelling\n insolently down her body in the tight revealing uniform. Spock clenched his\n hands together more firmly. This was what he had expected. It was known\n throughout the ship that a crewwoman’s first inspection ended in Kirk’s bed:\n captain’s orders. Spock’s presence would not deter it.\n Kirk abruptly frowned as his eyes reached waist level. Pointing to the clip\n hanging from her belt, he asked, “What are those for?”\n She glanced down briefly at the collection of Imperial insignia pins, unique in\n their design of a dagger embedded in a planet. “They’re from the people I’ve\n killed. My way of keeping count. Sir.” She allowed a half-smile when Kirk\n sat straighter in his desk chair. Nothing of her Vulcan nature was evident and\n the POW tattoo on her left forearm only emphasized her Romulan half. If Kirk", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[46, 51, "PER"], [427, 433, "GPE"], [860, 864, "PER"], [959, 965, "PER"], [984, 988, "PER"], [1098, 1103, "PER"], [1256, 1260, "PER"], [1287, 1292, "PER"], [1325, 1329, "PER"], [1686, 1690, "PER"], [1741, 1747, "SPEC"], [1827, 1834, "SPEC"], [1844, 1848, "PER"]]}
{"id": 916, "text": "knew more about the war camps’ numbering system, he’d know this particular\n tattoo marked her as a Vulcan/Romulan hybrid.\n “So, you’re going to be Spock’s new Chief,” Kirk continued.\n “Yes, sir. Of his personal guard.”\n “Since his previous one was killed.” He locked eyes with her. Spock must\n know that it was his guard who had murdered Stek. Therefore, Saavik must\n have been told.\n “A regrettable action, sir.”\n Kirk relaxed back into his chair. Better. She was less arrogant now, more\n easily approachable. He directed his next statement at Spock. “You can go\n now. She’ll be at her post later.”\n The Vulcan did not move right away, ready to argue that Saavik was, after all,\n his personal guard. He was not supposed to be without her. But Kirk’s next\n words left no doubt that he was quite serious, and the agony booth was not too\n far away.\n “That was an order, Mr. Spock.”\n There was no further choice. The Vulcan gave a nod of his head and turned on\n his heel to leave. He hesitated as he passed Saavik but she made no sign that\n she considered anything wrong. She gave him the same mocking glance she\n gave Kirk which, Spock could see, the captain noted.\n She could be maneuvering herself closer to the captain for the sake of inside\n information or. An unpleasant thought suddenly occurred to him. Perhaps\n this is what she wanted; Kirk, after all, did have a great deal of power. “Report\n to me as soon as you are finished here, Lieutenant,” he said crisply and left\n without another word.\n Secretly, Saavik was relieved. It would not do to have Kirk suspect that Spock\n meant anything outside of the professional to her. At least, not for right now.\n Seeing the assured leer on his face as his eyes once more traveled over her not\n too well hidden curves, she could see he didn’t.\n In what he thought was a charming tone, Kirk told her, “Please sit down,", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[99, 105, "SPEC"], [106, 113, "SPEC"], [147, 152, "PER"], [282, 287, "PER"], [338, 342, "PER"], [355, 361, "PER"], [167, 171, "PER"], [545, 550, "PER"], [605, 611, "SPEC"], [657, 663, "PER"], [744, 748, "PER"], [868, 877, "PER"], [914, 920, "SPEC"], [1004, 1010, "PER"], [1116, 1120, "PER"], [1128, 1133, "PER"], [415, 419, "PER"], [1342, 1346, "PER"], [1440, 1450, "PER"], [1512, 1518, "PER"], [1557, 1561, "PER"], [1575, 1580, "PER"], [1834, 1838, "PER"]]}
{"id": 917, "text": "Lieutenant. Make yourself comfortable.” He was a bit surprised when she\n didn’t do so right away. She first walked around the cabin, taking in everything,\n her fingers lightly tracing the ornaments, before she turned back to face him\n with a slight twist of a smile and slipped smoothly into a chair in the living\n area of his cabin. Grinning broadly, he joined her, leaning closer towards her\n chair. He waited for a positive sign before he reached across to lay one hand\n on the seat’s arm. “So, Saavik–”\n “You shouldn’t use my name without permission,” she said evenly.\n “And do I have your permission?”\n She gave him that same, slight smile and her eyes revealed what he wanted to\n see. “I think we should first. know each other better.”\n “Oh, I agree. Being out in space, alone, you should have a good relationship\n with your captain. Who knows where it could lead?” Kirk set himself to savor\n each moment. He had never had a Vulcan, let alone a Romulan. He looked\n forward to exploring the truths of each delicious rumor, and shedding a little\n light into the private world of the Vulcan/Romulan physical life.\n His hand traced the line of her leg from her knee up around the curve of her\n left hip. His fingers lingered there to travel back to her thigh.\n “You are not supposed to touch a Vulcan,” she warned him, lowering her voice\n to a throaty softness. “It might lead to something more involved. Could you\n handle such an involvement, Captain?”\n He laughed under his breath. “I’m willing to try.” He ran his fingers through the\n clip of Imperial pins. “These aren’t regulation, you know. You’ll have to take\n them off.”\n “If you insist, Captain. However, I have settled this with Starfleet Command,\n and they gave me permission to carry them as well as any others I gather.”\n “Oh, really,” he muttered, more interested in the play of feminine muscle as he\n moved up her arm. Her skin was so warm. The thought of being surrounded\n by it tantalized him.\n “I’m rather proud of some of them. One belonged to an admiral.”", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[0, 10, "PER"], [498, 504, "PER"], [872, 876, "PER"], [931, 937, "SPEC"], [951, 958, "SPEC"], [1087, 1093, "SPEC"], [1094, 1101, "SPEC"], [1296, 1302, "PER"], [1446, 1453, "PER"], [1648, 1655, "PER"], [1691, 1708, "ORG"]]}
{"id": 918, "text": "Miracle Worker\n By Patrick Cumby\n Patrick Cumby\n cumby@mindspring.com\n His vast repertoire of Gaelic curses exhausted, his engineering\n skills stymied, his hopes of rescue abandoned, Montgomery Scott\n slouches in the pilot’s chair and watches the clouds of vapor\n formed by his breath in the cold cabin atmosphere. There is\n nothing left to do but wait – wait and watch the nightmarish\n feeding frenzy of the Monster.\n Dim, cold radiance from the Indrii singularity trickles into\n the cabin through the open forward viewport. The glow from the\n maelstrom of dying atoms bathes the shuttlecraft’s interior\n with a vague light that dances and ripples across the glassy\n surfaces of the dead control panels.\n McCoy mumbles something incoherent. He’s as comfortable as\n Scott can make him, his unconscious form arrayed on the floor\n between the rows of seats, his head cushioned by a rolled-up\n Starfleet field jacket. The head wound has stopped bleeding,\n thankfully, but the doctor has yet to regain consciousness. The\n bloodstains on his blue uniform tunic appear black in the dim,\n ethereal light.\n At least the doctor is spared the indignity of floating around\n the darkened cabin, Scott muses grimly. Although unpowered,\n inertia will keep the stator in the gravity generator spinning\n for many hours – providing synthetic gravity to the\n shuttlecraft Copernicus long after the demise of her two\n occupants.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[183, 199, "PER"], [706, 711, "PER"], [766, 771, "PER"], [891, 900, "ORG"], [973, 979, "PER"], [1112, 1118, "PER"], [1183, 1188, "PER"], [1354, 1364, "SHIP"]]}
{"id": 919, "text": "Scott envies the doctor’s oblivion to the race in which they\n are both unwilling participants, a competition by various\n specters of death to be the first to claim their lives. The\n front runner is suffocation as the oxygen content of the\n shuttlecraft’s atmosphere is depleted. A close second is the\n black hole itself, threatening to consume them as their orbit\n rapidly decays. Other participants include hypothermia and the\n invisible but deadly X- and gamma rays that pour unimpeded\n through the unshielded shuttle hull.\n Some vacation this has turned out to be, he broods bitterly.\n Spiraling helplessly into the maw of a cosmological monster\n isn’t exactly what he’d had in mind for his shore leave…\n “So where are you headed, Scotty?”\n Scott turned to the doctor. “What do you mean?”\n Dr. McCoy chased an errant jito bean around his plate with his\n fork. “Your liberty. Where are you going to spend it?” He shook\n his head at the Chief Engineer’s noncommittal shrug. “Oh, let\n me guess. You’ll stay here on the ship to make sure the\n Starfleet techs don’t scratch your precious, wee bairns during\n the baryon sweep.” He popped the bean into his mouth and smiled\n as he chewed.\n Scott frowned. “Think you know me so well, do you?” The\n doctor’s smirk caused Scott’s frown to intensify. “Well, for\n your information I’m not supervising the maintenance team. In\n fact, I thought I’d take a little vacation on Rigel, or maybe\n Argelius.”\n McCoy reeled with theatrical surprise. “Scotty! I’m shocked!\n You, leaving your beloved warp engines in the hands of a bunch\n of rank amateurs? What’s the galaxy coming to?”\n “You’re welcome to join me,” Scott offered. “I hear the", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[0, 5, "PER"], [734, 740, "PER"], [744, 749, "PER"], [764, 770, "PER"], [793, 802, "PER"], [938, 952, "PER"], [1042, 1051, "ORG"], [1186, 1191, "PER"], [1243, 1249, "PER"], [1265, 1270, "PER"], [1414, 1419, "LOC"], [1431, 1439, "LOC"], [1443, 1448, "PER"], [1483, 1489, "PER"], [1647, 1652, "PER"]]}
{"id": 920, "text": "Rigellians serve a mean single malt, and those green women of\n theirs, hmm?”\n McCoy raised an eyebrow. “Are you serious?”\n Scott shrugged again. “Sure, if you think you can keep up, what\n with your age and all.” He winked at Ensign Chekov, sitting\n across the table from the two men.\n Chekov shook his head. “Not enough time to get to Rigel and\n back. The Enterprise’s drydock only lasts ten days.”\n “Well, Argelius, then,” said Scott. “Their women aren’t green,\n but I hear they know how to have a good time.”\n McCoy looked thoughtful. “I’ve always wanted to visit\n Argelius,” he said finally. “What the hell.”\n Scott turned to the young ensign. “Chekov, laddie, how about\n you?”\n Chekov waved his hands in front of him as if warding off an\n attack from the older officers. “Oh, no,” he said. “This sounds\n like it’s w-a-a-y out of my league. I think I’ll go for\n something a little less stressful, like maybe poking at a\n Capellan power-cat with a superconducting stick.”\n “Suit yourself,” said Scott.\n Scott fumbles open his communicator, his fingers like numb\n sausages in the cold. The unit chirps tiredly, its power cell\n almost exhausted by the same exotic force that has sapped the\n shuttlecraft’s power reserves. He dials into an emergency band\n and raises the communicator to his lips.\n “Lt. Commander Montgomery Scott of the U.S.S. Enterprise to any\n Federation vessel. Emergency. My shuttlecraft is damaged and we\n have sustained injuries. We’re being pulled into the Indrii\n black hole. We need immediate assistance. Please respond.”\n It is an exercise in futility, as Scott well knows. Even", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[0, 10, "SHIP"], [78, 83, "PER"], [123, 128, "PER"], [225, 238, "PER"], [285, 291, "PER"], [335, 340, "LOC"], [356, 366, "SHIP"], [407, 415, "LOC"], [429, 434, "PER"], [512, 517, "PER"], [567, 575, "LOC"], [613, 618, "PER"], [648, 654, "PER"], [682, 688, "PER"], [924, 942, "SPEC"], [997, 1002, "PER"], [1005, 1010, "PER"], [1298, 1328, "PER"], [1336, 1353, "SHIP"], [1362, 1372, "GPE"], [1582, 1587, "PER"], [1480, 1498, "PER"]]}
{"id": 921, "text": "THE LONG WAY HOME\n by A.C. Harper\n Disclaimer/Credits:  Star Trek is the property of Paramount. (The  character of Phyllida Gaines was created by Marcia Ericson as published  in her story “The Enchanted Pool,” in Star Trek: The New Voyages.)\n Feedback is appreciated. If you have comments, e-mail me: acoleen2@aol.com\n CHAPTER ONE – DISTRESS CALL\n “Captain’s Log:  Star Date 4163.8. While on a routine patrol mission to Outpost 7, Enterprise has received a distress signal from a Federation colony located on planet M64 in Sector 13. Enterprise is the nearest ship in this sector and as such we have responded to the call. The delay should, at most, be no more than a few hours.” Captain James Kirk completed the recording, hitting the button on the arm of his command chair and settling back. “Mister Spock,” he said, turning toward the science station, “What information do we have regarding M64 and the colony there?”\n Spock swiveled his chair to face the captain. “All Federation scans to this point have revealed the planet to be uninhabited with the exception of lower animal life forms and for the most part, it is highly vegetated and has a stable, temperate climate. A Federation colony was begun there approximately one year ago to study the indigenous plant and animal life. Most recent contact with the colony was six months ago, at which time there were no reported problems.”\n “So whatever happened there probably happened very suddenly and recently,” Kirk surmised.\n “That is a possibility, Captain,” Spock replied, “However, I would hesitate to make such presumptions without additional information. Six months is a long enough period of time for any number of things to have happened.”\n “Klingons?”\n “Possible, but not probable. This is far afield of their usual sphere of influence. Even Romulan intervention, though more probable, would likely not explain the situation.”\n Kirk nodded slightly and turned toward the communications station. “Lieutenant Uhura, play back the distress call.”\n “Aye, sir,” she responded. Her slender fingers played lightly over the keys and within seconds a nearly hysterical voice sounded over the bridge com.\n “This is Commander Martin of the M64 colony. If anyone can hear this, please – please help us! We can’t get away – most of our people are dead already! They mean to kill us all!  You must help us!” The message lapsed into static.\n “It’s a recording, Captain,” Uhura volunteered. There is no way of determining how long ago it was made. I have continued to monitor and there have been no new messages.”\n Kirk nodded in acknowledgement. Who was “they,” he thought.\n “Captain,” Spock announced, “We are approaching the planet.”\n “Thank you, Mister Spock. Engage forward view screen.” A blue-green planet with a hazy cloud cover shimmered in the distance and slowly filled the screen. “Standard orbit, Mister Sulu.”\n “Aye, sir. Plotted and laid in.” Lieutenant Commander Sulu set the coordinates with practiced precision.\n “Spock,” Kirk said, rising from the command chair, “ I want you to head up a landing party to the surface. We’re going to find out what happened down there.” Spock stood to face him, hands folded loosely behind his back. Kirk continued. “Take a three-man security team, a medical officer of McCoy’s choice, and that new transfer from Yorktown…” he hesitated, “What’s her name?”\n Spock stiffened imperceptibly. “Lieutenant Gaines.”\n “Right.” Kirk turned to Uhura. “Relay the coordinates of the distress signal to the transporter room and have Lieutenant Gaines and the security team meet us there.”\n “Aye, sir.”\n “And tell McCoy I need one of his officers for a landing party in 5 minutes in the transporter room.”\n Uhura nodded and began making the calls as Kirk moved toward the turbolift, his first officer following.\n —————–\n Transporter room one bustled with activity as the landing party assembled and checked their gear. The door hissed open to admit Captain Kirk and First Officer Spock, and the crew came to quiet attention.\n “Dr. Wilson,” Kirk addressed the young, dark-haired man who stood before him. “Dr. McCoy tells me that you can handle just about anything that comes up.”", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[431, 441, "SHIP"], [420, 429, "LOC"], [480, 490, "ORG"], [509, 519, "LOC"], [523, 532, "LOC"], [534, 544, "SHIP"], [680, 698, "PER"], [795, 807, "PER"], [894, 897, "LOC"], [922, 927, "PER"], [973, 983, "GPE"], [1178, 1188, "GPE"], [1506, 1513, "PER"], [1516, 1521, "PER"], [1466, 1470, "PER"], [1705, 1713, "SPEC"], [1806, 1813, "SPEC"], [1892, 1896, "PER"], [1960, 1976, "PER"], [2169, 2185, "PER"], [2193, 2203, "LOC"], [2410, 2417, "PER"], [2563, 2567, "PER"], [2625, 2632, "PER"], [2635, 2640, "PER"], [2698, 2710, "PER"], [2858, 2869, "PER"], [2906, 2931, "PER"], [2980, 2985, "PER"], [2988, 2992, "PER"], [3137, 3142, "PER"], [3200, 3204, "PER"], [3270, 3275, "PER"], [3390, 3407, "PER"], [3435, 3440, "PER"], [3420, 3424, "PER"], [3521, 3538, "PER"], [3313, 3321, "SHIP"], [3601, 3606, "PER"], [3694, 3699, "PER"], [3737, 3741, "PER"], [3808, 3828, "LOC"], [3936, 3948, "PER"], [3953, 3972, "PER"], [4014, 4024, "PER"], [4027, 4031, "PER"], [4092, 4101, "PER"]]}
{"id": 922, "text": "The youthful doctor nodded. “Yes sir. I specialized in combat medicine.”\n “Good. We don’t know what to expect down there.” The captain stopped, taking in the landing crew. “As for the rest of you, be on the alert for anything. The colonists were not specific with their message; all we know is that a life-threatening situation exists where six months ago there was none. Mister Spock is in command and can fill you in on any necessary details.” He paused again, scanning their faces. Good crew, he thought. He turned to his first officer. “Mister Spock, keep us posted. McCoy is standing by in sickbay to receive survivors, but use discretion; if there is any trouble I want you out of there – understood?”\n “Understood, Captain.” Spock motioned to his small crew to take their positions on the transporter pads. Lieutenant Phyllida Gaines, standing on the pad nearest Spock, flashed him a smile, which he chose to ignore.\n “Nice to see you again, Mister Spock,” she whispered.\n “Energize,” came the Vulcan’s command.\n —————-\n The landing party materialized inside a small room that seemed more than anything like the aftermath of a tornado. Assorted crates and machinery lay scattered about amid rubble from a ceiling that seemingly threatened to fall at any moment. Though signs of struggle were evident, there were no inhabitants and no bodies to be seen. In the corner, Spock’s tricorder registered the presence of a small terminal buried beneath the rubble; its insistent flashing indicated a message was still being sent. He switched it off.\n Spock glanced around the room, taking in the eerie silence, and addressed the crew. “We will separate into groups of two and scout the colony area, taking complete tricorder readings. Ensign Davis,” he indicated one of the security men, “You team up with Doctor Wilson. DuPuy and Echols, you make another team. Lieutenant Gaines, you are with me. Keep your communicator frequencies open and report anything the least bit unusual; we will meet back here in half an hour.” A chorus of acknowledgements followed as the crew spread out and began their search.\n ——————\n Kirk had not been back on the bridge for more than 20 minutes when Chekov reported from the science station that a large ion storm was approaching.\n “ETA, Mister Chekov?”\n “I vould estimate 2 hours at its present course and speed, Keptin.”\n That doesn’t give Spock much time, Kirk thought. “Very well, Lieutenant. Maintain surveillance of the storm and let me know of any change.”\n “Aye, Sir.”\n —————–\n On the surface, Spock and his party had turned up nothing remarkable except one small detail. Despite a search of the immediate area surrounding the beam-down point, there were no bodies; no trace of the colony could be found apart from the abandoned and ruined instruments. Checking his tricorder readings yet again, Spock moved toward the doctor. “Dr. Wilson, you can locate no disease-producing organisms? Anything that can account for our findings?”\n The young doctor looked at him with puzzled eyes. “No, Commander. It’s strange, too, that they should just disappear like this. I really am at a loss to explain it. If I could just find some physical remains I might be able to determine a cause.”\n “Yes – fascinating. Carry on, Doctor.”\n “Yes, Mister Spock.”\n In answer to the beep that had just sounded, Spock flipped open his communicator. “Spock here.”\n “Spock,” came Kirk’s voice, “We have a large ion storm on our scanners moving rapidly in this direction. Don’t stay down there any longer than you have to. ETA is 2 hours.” There was a pause. “Revise that ETA to 90 minutes, Mister Spock. That storm is really bearing down on us. I want you up here within 40 minutes.”\n “Acknowledged, Captain. I shall take the necessary precautions. Spock out.” He strode quickly toward the others. “I have just been informed of an ion storm heading this way. Please continue your research as efficiently and quickly as possible. Meet back here in half an hour.” The crew acknowledged and once again split into their assigned groups to finish gathering data.\n Phyllida Gaines stood a few feet away with her back to him, taking tricorder readings. Her golden hair cascaded around her shoulders in an almost non-regulation style. Two years had passed since the incident on Mevinna; years during which Spock had set aside all memory of the lovely lieutenant and their unusual escape from the Andorian force field. But, with her transfer to Enterprise, memories began again to crowd in upon him; her winsome smile pervaded his thoughts unmercifully and he could still feel her warm lips on his own from the remembered kiss. “I am your destiny,” she had said. Illogical. Drawing himself up, the unwanted thoughts and rousing emotions were thrust aside with stern Vulcan discipline and the welcome and familiar non-emotion settled upon him like a shield.\n “Lieutenant Gaines.”\n She turned. “Sir?” The mischief dancing in those blue eyes was apparent even without a smile.\n Spock cleared his throat. “What are your findings in correlation with the possibility of a technical breakdown and/or cause of such within the colony itself?\n “Well, certain technological functions -have ceased. The exact date of which I can’t be certain, except that it was fairly recent. Some systems appear to have merely stopped due to lack of maintenance, others have apparently been sabotaged. Whether by the colonists themselves in an unstable emotional state or by some outside force, it is impossible to tell. However, I did find some unusual markings over here…” He followed her inside a nearby building that had apparently been a laboratory for the colonists. “See, here; on this piece of machinery.” She pointed out a large dent in the side of the main computer console. Inside and around the indentation were several sets of parallel scratch marks as though made by giant hands.\n “Fascinating…”\n By the time Spock and Gaines heard the cries it was already too late. On reaching the point where DuPuy and Echols had been scouting, they found very little left of the men. They met Doctor Wilson running to the scene from the opposite direction. Spock’s tricorder was out in an instant, as was the doctor’s.\n “How horrible!”  Phyllida gasped at the sight of the badly burned and decomposed bodies.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[127, 134, "PER"], [372, 384, "PER"], [541, 553, "PER"], [571, 576, "PER"], [722, 729, "PER"], [814, 840, "PER"], [732, 737, "PER"], [870, 875, "PER"], [949, 961, "PER"], [1001, 1007, "SPEC"], [1375, 1380, "PER"], [1550, 1555, "PER"], [1734, 1746, "PER"], [1805, 1818, "PER"], [1820, 1825, "PER"], [1830, 1836, "PER"], [1861, 1878, "PER"], [2115, 2119, "PER"], [2182, 2188, "PER"], [2270, 2283, "PER"], [2346, 2352, "PER"], [2374, 2379, "PER"], [2391, 2395, "PER"], [2417, 2427, "PER"], [2534, 2539, "PER"], [3028, 3037, "PER"], [3251, 3257, "PER"], [3267, 3279, "PER"], [3366, 3371, "PER"], [3381, 3386, "PER"], [3394, 3398, "PER"], [3328, 3333, "PER"], [3604, 3616, "PER"], [3714, 3721, "PER"], [3763, 3768, "PER"], [4073, 4088, "PER"], [4284, 4291, "LOC"], [4312, 4317, "PER"], [4450, 4460, "SHIP"], [4402, 4410, "SPEC"], [4771, 4777, "SPEC"], [4864, 4881, "PER"], [4980, 4985, "PER"], [5901, 5906, "PER"], [5911, 5917, "PER"], [5987, 5992, "PER"], [5997, 6003, "PER"], [6072, 6085, "PER"], [6136, 6141, "PER"], [6216, 6224, "PER"], [6188, 6194, "PER"], [2836, 2841, "PER"], [2868, 2878, "PER"]]}
{"id": 923, "text": "Spock was down on one knee, scanning the strange looking plants on which one of the bodies lay. “Apparently these plants produce a type of fast-acting acid, making their prey easier to digest,” he commented. “It looks as though those vines…Doctor!”\n The doctor turned from the body he was examining in time to see the vine come up to encircle his neck. He let out a strangled cry as Spock quickly fired on the plant with his phaser, destroying it instantly. Gaines lowered Wilson gently to the grass.\n “Too late…” she said softly, “Too late.”\n Spock knelt to examine the wound around the doctor’s neck. “The acid appears to be even faster acting than I had thought. See, where the tissue and vessels have been completely dissolved.” He rose, taking Gaines by the arm. “Come, we must avoid the slightest contact with these plants.”\n “We can’t just leave him here!”\n “That is an order, Lieutenant. Let’s go now!” She acquiesced reluctantly to the pressure on her arm, but her gaze remained fixed on Wilson’s body as they quickly left the area. On the move, Spock opened his communicator and signaled to Ensign Davis, who had been scouting with Doctor Wilson. “Ensign Davis, respond.”\n “Here, Mister Spock,” came the reply.\n “Ensign, return to the beam-down point promptly. Stay clear of the forest and be on your guard for creeping vines that we have determined to be deadly.”\n “Aye, Sir. On my way. Davis out.”\n Spock and Gaines had nearly reached the beam-down point when Spock’s communicator signaled. “Spock here.”\n “Spock,” came Kirk’s urgent voice, “You and your party must come up at once. The storm is advancing much more rapidly.”\n “Yes, Sir.” Although Spock was reluctant to leave when he was so close to finding a solution to the disappearance of the colony, he knew that with the loss of half of his crew and the advancing storm nothing more could be accomplished at this time. “We’ll be ready within 5 minutes. Spock out.” He changed frequencies on his communicator and signaled to Ensign Davis, who still had not returned. “Ensign Davis, return to the beam-down point.” Silence. “Ensign Davis, respond!”\n Phyllida’s brows drew together as she cast a worried look at Spock. “What if he can’t respond?” She pulled out her tricorder and started scanning in Davis’ last known direction.\n Spock answered by calling Enterprise. “Captain, one of my team is missing and is not responding. We have to find him before we beam out.”\n “Spock, you’re out of time.”\n “Just a few more minutes, Captain.” He looked at Lieutenant Gaines, who looked up from her tricorder and shook her head.\n “No life signs that I can find. I don’t think he made it.”\n “Spock,” Kirk was fairly shouting, “You don’t HAVE a few minutes! Stand by to beam up at my sig………..no for an ans………..”\n “Captain? Captain!” The only reply was static.\n CHAPTER TWO – CAPTIVES\n “Scotty, get them up here!”  The yellow alert signal flashed insistently.\n “I’m tryin’, Captain. The storm…” Lieutenant Montgomery Scott manipulated the controls as only he could.\n Kirk looked toward the transporter as two shimmering figures began to materialize, and then were gone.\n “What happened, Scott?”\n “It’s the storm. It’s already interferin’ with the transporter. We canna lock onto them, and if I try again, we’ll lose ‘em for sure!”\n Kirk struck the console with his fist. There was nothing they could do now but wait out the storm. Who knew what kind of situation they could be in down there…?\n —————-\n “Mister Spock! The storm…The transporter couldn’t lock onto our signal. That means…”\n “That means we’re stranded, for the time being, Lieutenant.” Spock took a step away and gauged their surroundings. To the south, west and north of the small clearing in which they stood, nothing but dense forest growth could be seen, mingled with the small structures of the colony. In his estimation, the proximity of the plants made the buildings unsafe to stay in for any length of time. To the east the clearing extended with less growth to a small hill some 1,000 meters away. The sky, dotted with clouds, was a deep blue, getting deeper as evening approached.\n Spock heard a faint rustling from the shadows behind them and turned to see tendrils creeping slowly toward them from the undergrowth.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[0, 5, "PER"], [240, 246, "PER"], [383, 388, "PER"], [458, 464, "PER"], [473, 479, "PER"], [544, 549, "PER"], [749, 755, "PER"], [884, 894, "PER"], [1055, 1060, "PER"], [1101, 1113, "PER"], [1142, 1155, "PER"], [1158, 1170, "PER"], [1190, 1202, "PER"], [1223, 1229, "PER"], [1398, 1403, "PER"], [1472, 1477, "PER"], [1411, 1416, "PER"], [1421, 1427, "PER"], [1504, 1509, "PER"], [1519, 1524, "PER"], [1532, 1536, "PER"], [1660, 1665, "PER"], [1922, 1927, "PER"], [1993, 2005, "PER"], [2036, 2048, "PER"], [2092, 2104, "PER"], [2117, 2125, "PER"], [2178, 2183, "PER"], [2266, 2271, "PER"], [2296, 2301, "PER"], [2322, 2332, "PER"], [2335, 2342, "PER"], [2436, 2441, "PER"], [2491, 2498, "PER"], [2514, 2531, "PER"], [2648, 2653, "PER"], [2656, 2660, "PER"], [2769, 2776, "PER"], [2778, 2785, "PER"], [2928, 2935, "PER"], [2841, 2847, "PER"], [2949, 2976, "PER"], [3021, 3025, "PER"], [3141, 3146, "PER"], [3286, 3290, "PER"], [3457, 3469, "PER"], [3603, 3608, "PER"], [4109, 4114, "PER"]]}
{"id": 924, "text": "STAR TREK\n A Second Home\n  \n by Cory Pelc\n  \n For my wife—and her acceptance of my quirks. \n  \n CHAPTER 1\n Leonard McCoy was tired. Tired of dealing with the constant threats to the well-being of the crew, and tired of filling out the endless death certificates. The last such “adventure” had claimed a total of twelve crewmen. Twelve young lives lost in the name of exploration, McCoy thought.\n  \n Of those lost, two crewmen were taken quickly by an allergic reaction to the native flora of the planet. A ship that can take men across the galaxy protected by shields and photon torpedoes, and we still can’t save someone from acute anaphylactic shock, McCoy thought to himself.\n Shortly after beaming down to the surface of Rynair II the men accidently inhaled a bit of pollen that proved fatal. The only saving grace of the situation was that the pollen only affected an individual who was also allergic to Elonian zongs, which McCoy noted in his log were roughly the equivalent to an Earth coconut. Thinking of this, McCoy shuddered slightly realizing how easily the ship could have been without three members of the senior crew, as Jim, Spock and himself had beamed down along with the landing party. Probably not Spock, McCoy thought, those damned Vulcan bodily functions probably have a back-up measure even for anaphylaxis.\n McCoy knew and accepted death as something which every doctor deals with from time to time, but he was unnerved that these sort-of situations seemed to be the norm at this point in his life. It wasn’t supposed to be this way, he told himself. As much as he enjoyed his friendship with Jim and his whatever-you-might-call-it with Spock, McCoy never had felt at home in space.\n One thing that had always reminded McCoy of home was a good drink. As a proud “Son of the South”, it was almost bred into him. At the moment, he felt like a drink might be the best friend he had. Grabbing a bottle from his shelf and taking a seat behind his desk in sickbay, McCoy poured himself some Saurian brandy. He sipped the strong liquor, attempting to relax and allowing his mind to drift back to a time in his life before Starfleet. Back then, his drink of choice was a Mint Julep, but he felt like the replicators onboard the Enterprisecould never get them quite right. Maybe it’s because the temperature is always 72 degrees in here, with simulated sunlight, McCoy thought in a matter-of-fact sense. A Mint Julep is meant to be enjoyed on a hot summer evening. Evening—even that has no meaning in space. McCoy sighed and poured another glass.\n – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – –\n Growing up inGeorgia, young Leonard Horatio McCoy always pictured himself as going to medical school, settling down with a beautiful belle, and living the life of an “old country doctor.” But, for whatever reason, he only got two of those three goals checked off his list. His wife Jocelyn was everything he had hoped for since the first time they met back at that high school dance. But after their daughter Joanna was born, it seemed to him that Jocelyn changed overnight. He never had evidence of her cheating on him, but every time he looked at Joanna the thought would arise.\n  Is she really my daughter? He would ponder as he looked down into his daughter’s crib. Does it matter?\n “Leonard! Leonard! Where are you?”\n “Out here on the back porch Jocelyn!” McCoy replied, while sipping a Mint Julip and watching the sun set on another August day.\n “We have to talk.” Jocelyn said as she finally found her husband. “I think we both know that this isn’t working anymore. I was fine staying at home being the ‘Doctor’s Wife’ but now I feel like I’m the ‘Parent of the Doctor’s Daughter’.”\n “What do you mean Jocelyn?” McCoy said, while feeling more than a little blindsided.\n “What I mean is that you go and sit in your clinic everyday and help people, and I’m stuck here raising our daughter by myself. Sometimes I think that you care more about your patients than your own wife and daughter!” she exclaimed with the force of months of suppressed thoughts.\n “Dammit Jocelyn! I’m a doctor, not a daycare provider! I spent years going through medical school to help these people and this is the thanks I get?” He angrily replied.\n “Well I went through eight and a half months of pregnancy, concluding with delivery of our child and this is the life I get? A husband that is out of the door before sunrise, and with drink in his hand at every sunset? I could have gone to school too, in California, but I chose you.”\n “Well I guess you have another choice to make.” He said, turning his attention back to the sunset.\n “I’ve already made it. You should be hearing from my lawyer in the next few days. Until then, Joanna and I will be staying with my sister.” Jocelyn sternly replied at her husband who was still refusing to look at her.\n “Why don’t you go ahead and stay at Clay’s house. I’m sure he’d be glad to have you.” McCoy said as he closed his eyes. He knew he had gone too far and regretted it instantly.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[32, 41, "PER"], [107, 120, "PER"], [380, 385, "PER"], [653, 658, "PER"], [725, 734, "SHIP"], [930, 935, "PER"], [987, 992, "LOC"], [1020, 1025, "PER"], [1136, 1139, "PER"], [1141, 1146, "PER"], [1218, 1223, "PER"], [1225, 1230, "PER"], [1253, 1259, "SPEC"], [1332, 1337, "PER"], [1617, 1620, "PER"], [1661, 1666, "PER"], [1668, 1673, "PER"], [1743, 1748, "PER"], [1983, 1988, "PER"], [2009, 2016, "SPEC"], [2139, 2148, "ORG"], [2244, 2254, "SHIP"], [2378, 2383, "PER"], [2523, 2528, "PER"], [2657, 2664, "LOC"], [2672, 2693, "PER"], [2926, 2933, "PER"], [3053, 3059, "PER"], [3092, 3099, "PER"], [3193, 3199, "PER"], [3332, 3339, "PER"], [3341, 3348, "PER"], [3395, 3402, "PER"], [3405, 3410, "PER"], [3753, 3760, "PER"], [3763, 3768, "PER"], [4105, 4111, "PER"], [4755, 4761, "PER"], [4801, 4808, "PER"], [4916, 4920, "PER"], [4966, 4971, "PER"]]}
{"id": 925, "text": "“Unbelievable!” She screamed. “I’ve told you before that things between him and I ended a long time ago. Due in large part to you, I might add. Leonard, I was always faithful to you, even though you’ll never be half the father that Clay might have been for Joanna.”\n With that, Jocelyn McCoy walked back into the house; the house that Leonard realized would soon be hers along with most all of Leonard’s money and possessions. He wondered if he’d be lucky enough that she didn’t take the bones from his body. McCoy sighed and made himself another drink. \n CHAPTER 2\n …Sweet home Alabama! Lord I’m coming home to you!….That was one from way-way back in the 20th Century folks, but still a great way to start your morning! We’ve got 10 in a row headed your way next!…\n “Hmmmmrph!” Leonard slowly sat up in bed and told himself that he was getting too old for this routine. Without even opening his eyes he could sense a hungry grandchild standing next to his bed wearing the devilish grin of someone who had just turned on her grandfather’s radio to get his attention.\n “Yes darlin’?” Leonard asked her. His drawl was always more pronounced before having his morning coffee.\n “Grandpa, can we go to the zoo today?” The little girl asked as she pulled on his comforter.\n “Perhaps dear, but first we’ll need to ask Grandma. We both know that she’s the one that calls the shots.”  McCoy stretched, slipped on his house shoes and pulled on a robe. He reached to his nightstand and grabbed his PADD to open up the day’s newspaper–Outbreak on Vulcan Outpost: Federation Seeks Help of Medical Community–the main headline read. Makes sense, thought McCoy, pointy-eared logic lovers can’t even display enough emotion to ask for help themselves.\n McCoy punched in the code for coffee on his replicator as he continued reading. Damn fake coffee. Joanna had bought him and Jocelyn the replicator for their anniversary last year and he had finally started using it—but not before he passionately explained to Jocelyn that part of the charm of coffee is its simplicity. If it was good enough for the settlers of this land so many generations ago, then it didn’t need to be upgraded.\n McCoy continued reading–…in light of the Organian medical and peace conference being held in conjunction with the Klingons, all essential Starfleet Medical personnel are unable to assist with this emergency. The Federation hopes that some of the more experienced physicians and nurses from Earth and Andoria will volunteer to assist in this urgent matter. Because the outbreak seems to only affect Vulcan individuals, it has been determined to be too great a risk to seek assistance from the Vulcan Medical Academy. For those interested in volunteering locally, shuttles will be leaving from the Atlanta Shipyards at 1200 hours today.\n “Grandma said we can go! Grandma said we can go!” Lucy yelled as she ran back into the kitchen. “Can we leave soon?”\n “Sure little lady, but first Grandpa has to get ready. And so do you…unless you plan on showing off your pajamas to the elephants.” Leonard walked back towards his bedroom and found his wife getting ready for the day. He set his PADD down on her dresser and stood behind her as she looked in the mirror.\n “Good morning Mrs. McCoy…” He said, trying to goad a response.\n “Good morning to you, too, Dr. McCoy.” She responded.\n “That’s only Monday through Friday. It’s the weekend and I’m as much a Mr. as I choose to be.”\n “Well today it sounds like you’re a Grandpa, and I’m sure you’ll treat Lucy with just as much care as you would a patient.”\n “Still bringing that up…” McCoy said with a grin. It had been twenty five years since his marriage had almost fallen apart. He was close to joining Starfleet back then, just to get away from the mess of his divorce. Medicine On The Cutting Edge – Practicing in Space the advertisement had read. He had been to space once before as an observer shortly after graduating from Ole Miss. He knew then that he wanted to be a doctor, but he was pretty sure he wanted to keep his practice local. As in on Earth, he had joked to himself.\n Instead of enlisting, he decided to cut back his office hours and make the effort to work things out with Jocelyn. It turned out that she had run back to Clay during their separation and divorce, but shortly after Jocelyn saw that Clay had not changed as much as he claimed. McCoy knew that it wouldn’t be easy–the divorce was finalized and they had to get married again–but he made a choice to use it as a fresh start and he was glad that he had. Most importantly, he was glad that Jocelyn had given him the opportunity.\n “So is this goodbye?” Jocelyn asked.\n “What are you talking about? I thought we’d both go with Lucy today.” A confused McCoy replied.\n “I’m talking about this,” Jocelyn said as she picked up his PADD and pointed to the story he had been reading. “They need help. You may not be a young buck, but you are experienced.”\n “I wouldn’t call one observation mission experience. And you know as well as I do about my aviophobia. I still try to avoid riding in a hovercar if I can. On top of that, I can’t even begin to imagine stepping onto one of those transporter pads. Last time I was lucky to not have to leave the ship. Tearing apart someone into a million little bits and then rearranging them again. It’s just not natural, Jocelyn.”  McCoy said, knowing that Jocelyn always found his excuses overblown. Sometimes he made an effort to stretch them out even more just to get under her skin.\n “Listen Leonard,” Jocelyn said with a more serious tone than McCoy had expected. “You once told me that the reason you went to school for years were to help people and make a difference. Now I know you have helped people here, but this is a chance to do something special, something important. I think you should take it.”\n McCoy paused a moment, and then said, “You know, I was going to enlist after our divorce. I had even filled out some of the preliminary forms. But I chose you and Joanna instead. I couldn’t live with running away to space instead of staying here and being a man.”\n “Well you have been a man, and a husband, and a father–”\n “Don’t forget grandfather.”\n “And grandfather. But now you need to be a doctor…and just maybe a hero.” Jocelyn had that look. The one that Leonard knew meant the conversation was over and a decision had been made.\n A hero huh? He thought. I just hope they have real coffee, because at my age I’m going to need it to keep up.\n CHAPTER 3\n McCoy arrived at the Atlanta Shipyards at 1130 hours that morning. He had packed as much as he could before Jocelyn shuffled him out the door. In a very rushed exchange, he tried to explain to Lucy that he wasn’t going to be able to go to the zoo with her and that he had to go away for a while. Hopefully not too long Lucy, for both our sakes, he had thought. McCoy walked into the main building with his head down.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[144, 151, "PER"], [232, 236, "PER"], [278, 291, "PER"], [257, 263, "PER"], [335, 342, "PER"], [394, 401, "PER"], [509, 514, "PER"], [579, 586, "LOC"], [779, 786, "PER"], [1083, 1090, "PER"], [1175, 1182, "PER"], [1311, 1318, "PER"], [1376, 1381, "PER"], [1535, 1541, "SPEC"], [1551, 1561, "GPE"], [1639, 1644, "PER"], [1735, 1740, "PER"], [1833, 1839, "PER"], [1859, 1866, "PER"], [1994, 2001, "PER"], [2168, 2173, "PER"], [2209, 2217, "SPEC"], [2282, 2290, "SPEC"], [2306, 2315, "ORG"], [2380, 2390, "GPE"], [2458, 2463, "LOC"], [2468, 2475, "LOC"], [2566, 2572, "SPEC"], [2660, 2682, "ORG"], [2764, 2781, "LOC"], [2805, 2812, "PER"], [2829, 2836, "PER"], [2854, 2858, "PER"], [2951, 2958, "PER"], [3054, 3061, "PER"], [3241, 3251, "PER"], [3318, 3327, "PER"], [3593, 3598, "PER"], [3715, 3724, "ORG"], [4064, 4069, "LOC"], [3940, 3948, "ORG"], [3513, 3517, "PER"], [3478, 3485, "PER"], [4251, 4255, "PER"], [4328, 4332, "PER"], [4311, 4318, "PER"], [4372, 4377, "PER"], [4580, 4587, "PER"], [4642, 4649, "PER"], [4715, 4719, "PER"], [4739, 4744, "PER"], [5343, 5350, "PER"], [5354, 5359, "PER"], [5379, 5386, "PER"], [5518, 5525, "PER"], [5528, 5535, "PER"], [5571, 5576, "PER"], [5834, 5839, "PER"], [5997, 6003, "PER"], [6296, 6303, "PER"], [6515, 6532, "LOC"], [4781, 4788, "PER"], [6260, 6267, "PER"], [6494, 6499, "PER"], [6602, 6609, "PER"], [6687, 6691, "PER"], [6813, 6817, "PER"], [6855, 6860, "PER"]]}
{"id": 926, "text": "“Excuse me sir, but there’s no tours today.”\n McCoy looked up to see a man in a security uniform sitting behind the main desk. This guy looks like he’s seen more buffet lines than doctors in his life, he thought.\n “Well excuse me sir, but I imagine you are constantly short of breath, have a hard time feeling motivated and constantly need some type of sugar.”\n “Uh yeah, but how’d you know that?” the guard said between grunts while attempting to sit up straight. “And what are you here for?”\n “Son, I’m Leonard H. McCoy, M.D. and I’m here for the volunteer effort. Where’s the line start?” McCoy said proudly.\n “Well, I’d say about where you’re standing.” The guard said as he smiled and looked evidently satisfied to have the last word.\n Great, McCoy thought. It looks like it’s going to be a lonely shuttle ride.\n – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – – –\n This particular transport shuttle turned out to be larger than McCoy had envisioned. Must have been expecting more volunteers, he thought. Once aboard, he was able to find a nice interior restroom with no windows. He remained there throughout takeoff and through most of the flight. Fighting back any rumblings of a panic attack, he reverted to talking in his head in order to tolerate the situation. I’m not moving, I’m just in a small room and then I’ll be in a bigger one, he tried to tell himself.\n “–This is the pilot speaking. We’ll need everyone to return to their seats as we receive clearance to dock with Enterprise.–”\n McCoy heard a knock on the restroom door and after trying and failing to explain his aviophobia to the Lieutenant, he finally stepped out of the restroom and into the cabin. He was actually surprised that it had taken so long for anyone to notice that the restroom had been continually occupied. I guess that’s what happens when you’re the only passenger, he jokingly thought. However, when he went to take a seat, he was surprised to find he was not the lone volunteer. Apparently, between McCoy locating a hiding spot in the restroom and takeoff, another passenger had come on board.\n “You wouldn’t happen to have a piece of chewing gum would you?” McCoy asked the woman as he sat down next to her and fastened his safety belt. He couldn’t help but feel that for some reason, she seemed rather familiar.\n “I’m sorry, I don’t.” She replied in a soothing voice. “Christine Chapel-Korby and you are?”\n “Dr. Leonard H. McCoy. At your service, Madame.”\n The woman laughed, “Actually, it’s the reverse, Dr McCoy.”\n At first McCoy was angered, but then he understood what she meant.\n “It looks like I will be your nurse on this rescue mission” she continued.\n “In that case, there are a few things you ought to know. First off, I’m not used to working in a sickbay with so many different species of patients.” McCoy said as he started to slip back into a more pronounced drawl. It also tended to happen when he was complaining about something.\n “So, I’ll need all the help from you that I can get. I’ve been told once or twice that my bedside manner can be a little rough. I for one, however, like to think of myself as a realist.”\n Chapel blushed. “Don’t worry Doctor,” she said with an air of care that McCoy appreciated. “I spent years in space while searching for my husband, who at that time was just my lost fiancé. I was limited to traveling aboard private ships as a nurse practitioner, but in that time, I was introduced to treating many different patients.”\n “That’s good. Probably, honest work I imagine.” He replied.\n “Believe me it was. Though it must’ve taken its toll on me, as I’ve noticed Roger hasn’t aged nearly as much as I have.” She said, more to herself than to McCoy.\n “—Attention passengers and crew: Prepare for final docking procedures—”\n The shuttle reduced its thrusters and lurched backwards slightly as it began to slow its approach to Enterprise. For the first time, McCoy allowed himself to look out of one of the window ports. Quite the vessel, he thought. Again he had the strange feeling of familiarity. I must’ve seen a starship like this in one of Lucy’s digi-books, he thought trying to explain away the sensation. He was already missing his family.\n Enterprise grew larger and larger in comparison to the window port opening as the shuttle swung around to the aft end of the starship and the shuttle bay. McCoy could feel what he assumed was the tractor beams of the ship take control as the shuttle came to a soft landing inside the bay.  The side hatch to the shuttle released its pressurization as it slowly slid open.\n “I guess this is our stop” McCoy joked to Chapel.\n The doctor and nurse stood and began to exit the shuttle. Waiting at attention just outside the shuttle door was a rather proud looking man with brown hair. McCoy, struck by his appearance,  couldn’t tell if the man reminded him of someone, or that he just looked different than most of his clinic patients.\n “Velcome aboard ze Enterprise, I am Lieutenant Commander Pavel Chekov. You must be Dr. McCoy and Nurse Chapel.”\n Don’t think he’s from Georgia. Although surprised by the gentleman’s thick accent, McCoy was relieved by the lack of a grand reception. He did, however, now find himself in the need for something to take his nerves down a notch.\n “Mr. Chekov is it–” McCoy began to ask.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[46, 51, "PER"], [505, 527, "PER"], [592, 597, "PER"], [748, 753, "PER"], [964, 969, "PER"], [1516, 1526, "SHIP"], [1531, 1536, "PER"], [1634, 1644, "PER"], [2022, 2027, "PER"], [2182, 2187, "PER"], [2394, 2416, "PER"], [2433, 2453, "PER"], [2530, 2538, "PER"], [2551, 2556, "PER"], [2836, 2841, "PER"], [3159, 3165, "PER"], [3188, 3194, "PER"], [3231, 3236, "PER"], [3632, 3637, "PER"], [3711, 3716, "PER"], [3893, 3903, "SHIP"], [3925, 3930, "PER"], [4112, 4116, "PER"], [4216, 4226, "SHIP"], [4371, 4376, "PER"], [4616, 4621, "PER"], [4631, 4637, "PER"], [4797, 4802, "PER"], [4968, 4978, "SHIP"], [4985, 5018, "PER"], [5032, 5041, "PER"], [5046, 5058, "PER"], [5084, 5091, "LOC"], [5145, 5150, "PER"], [5293, 5303, "PER"], [5312, 5317, "PER"]]}
{"id": 927, "text": "Forward\n Here Posted is the first TWO Chapters of a 25 Chapter Book. I wrote this 20 years ago, for fun, while trapped in the subway to and from work every day. Thought it might be intriguing to put it out there. I am just editing as I go along so the other chapters will come fast…..\n CHAPTER 1\n It had always been his practice to wake up at least an hour before his duty shift began. Besides the fact that it assured he was alert by the time he reported, he had always believed that a man should spend time in quiet meditation before he started his day. Of course now he had the power to spend as much time contemplating as he desired. After all, his duty shift may be twenty four hours a day, but being a commander in the Romulan Navy also afforded him the luxury of managing his time as he saw fit.\n Still, Commander S’Tal prided himself in his dedication to duty; not in a conceited, arrogant way, but with a fulfilling satisfaction that he was an honourable man. He had seen many a ship’s commander abuse his position and shirk his duty. Honour and duty was the fibre that made a good man; that was the heritage from which the Romulan Empire had grown and what would always remain in those who served the Romulan Way. Today, like most other days, he awoke to the beckoning of the computer’s masculine voice efficiently repeating a clipped military style wake up call. It did not take many conscious moments for his mind to turn to the upcoming mission.\n “Computer,” he spoke to an invisible speaker that he had always felt was in the ceiling even though he knew it was built into one of the walls. “Open the Starscape.” Open was not really the correct term since the wall did not actually open up into space. Instead, the computer adjusted the tint of the huge transplanium window that made up the wall curving into the ceiling of S’Tal’s quarters. It was not his style to use his position to get comforts that were not readily available to the rest of his crew. Nevertheless, he had indulged himself the luxury of the viewport he now looked through.\n Looking through the enormous window he could not help but be struck by what he saw. For all the trillions upon trillions of light years that made up the universe, when he looked out into space he was amazed at how two dimensional it all seemed. Every speck of light he saw could be an inch in radius and a few meters from his ship, or they could be a thousand times the radius of Romulus’ sun and a million light years away. No man had the eyes or mind to truly perceive the notion of depth in the vastness of space.\n S’Tal found the stars even more beautiful when he was actually viewing them with his own eyes, instead of the computer generated images he saw on the bridge. It was easy to get caught up in the aesthetic beauty of the stars, especially when they took on a surreal quality caused by the rippling effect the cloaking device created. Still, he had no time to spare daydreaming about the beauty of the stars when he needed to prepare for battle.\n The Praetor himself had endorsed this mission for which S’Tal, his ship, and the Vatrium were preparing. The Praetor had been convinced by his advisors that the time was right to move against the Federation. They argued that for too long now the Romulan Empire had been denying their true destiny as masters of the galaxy because they feared themselves not strong enough to conquer the Federation.  Now those advisers had convinced the Praetor that the empire was strong enough to win   if they could gain an early advantage.  The purpose of this mission was to give them that advantage.\n The years of peace had been good to the Empire; her people had grown as a society and had conquered or settled hundreds of new planets.  Honour lay with the military and duty was served by all.  S’Tal had gained his position through outstanding military service in wars with the Gorn and the IKS on the Triangle border.  He had seen war and understood the necessity to wage it.  However, this action against the Federation was different; it did not feel right for him, or for the Empire.  He did not fear for himself – in fact, he looked forward to dying in his Commander’s seat, as a real warrior should.  He feared for what the war would do to the Romulan society.  Regardless of what the Praetor’s advisors said, the war with the Federation would be long and costly.\n S’Tal had never actually battled a Starfleet vessel, but was well studied in their design and abilities.  It was this expertise that led to his assignment on this particular mission.  For all of the Empire’s technical advancements, his ship, one of the most powerful in the Royal Navy, was barely a match for many of the Federation’s cruisers. Romulan commanders were superior when their positions had been earned – of that he was sure -, but too many command positions had been given to undeserving men who knew someone of importance.  So where was the advantage in a war with the Federation?  S’Tal knew he would be successful in completing his mission, but whether it would give the Empire the element of surprise and superior knowledge remained a question.\n S’Tal got out of bed, went over to the food synthesizer, and returned to the small table that was set up against his wall viewport.  He was far too preoccupied with the mission that would begin today to worry about a proper breakfast.  This morning a cup of hot corum would suffice.  He sipped his root broth as he wondered how honourable it was to fight the Federation, who had shown no aggression to the Empire.  When he was a young man, S’Tal had thought that fighting was always a source of honour.  As he aged, the fighting seemed endless and killing his so called enemy often seemed like hurting innocent people.  More and more, S’Tal was coming to the realization that true honour lay in protecting peace and the strength of the Empire.  If it took war to do that, then so be it.  He did not feel this was the case with the Federation, which was, for the most part, an honourable entity.\n That last thought brought an audible chuckle from his throat.  As a Centurion aboard the Cl’Torin he had been furious at the espionage of a Federation captain and his first officer who conspired to steal a cloaking device.  S’Tal had been severely reprimanded for his inability to destroy the Federation vessel when it was fleeing with a stolen Romulan cloaking device.  S’Tal had been slow to react to the Enterprise cloaking and it escaped.\n It was his anger at being duped that drove him to be so great a warrior.  He also vowed to become the foremost expert on Federation military organization.  He found that his anger ran out of steam after a couple of years. His Commander later showed him that Federation officers were capable of great honour when that same command crew of the Enterprise worked together with her against Omne. She had been right to trust them even though her career was lost.  He actually developed an admiration for Starfleet and its most powerful ships and decorated officers.\n Still, of course his heart lay with his Romulan Empire.  He had fought for the prosperity of its people.  He had sworn his life to the Praetor and regardless of the consequences or possible futility of war with the Federation, he was going to honour his oath.  Duty was the utmost priority to Romulans   and S’Tal was, above all else, a Romulan.  With renewed determination, he rose from his seat and began to dress in his Romulan commander’s uniform.\n “Close viewport.”  The viewport darkened on cue as S’Tal added the honour sash to his uniform.  He reached up to the Romulan Bird cluster that held his sash in place and touched it with his forefinger.  It beeped to life.  “S’Tal to bridge,” he clipped in an efficient military tone.  “I’m heading to PTB room three.  Inform Commander Tark that I will be transporting over as scheduled.”\n “Immediately, Commander,” S’Tal heard as he left his quarters.\n Tark revelled in the command seat.  He often spent many off duty hours on the bridge.  He had spent years of his life in the security sections of various ships, dreaming of getting to where he was now   in the command seat.\n It was from the command seat that one could be part of the strategy of battle.  He was addicted to combat, he could admit that.  This was not a vice to a Romulan, provided he had self control and could make the right choices about when to battle, always ensuring the Empire came before personal needs.\n Many years of his life had been spent studying every great strategist in the known galaxy.  It did not matter to Tark whether the object of his study was an enemy or an ally, his admiration transcended political and ideological boundaries.  In fact, some of his favourite strategists were from the Klingon and Federation starfleets.  Captain Garth was his chosen commander when it came to fighting against numerous opponents.  General Kord from the Klingon Empire was outstanding at directing and participating in multi vessel encounters.  Yet his favourite was Captain James T. Kirk, commander of the Federation cruiser Enterprise.  It was Kirk who was able to turn any situation to his advantage.  Kirk, who never accepted defeat even if he had to sacrifice his own ship to win.\n Tark had spent several years as captain on smaller ships, most of them old and lacking any real power.  It was his knowledge of Kirk and his expertise on combat strategy that got him command of the Vatrium.  His ship was the first of its kind, the first special missions cruiser in the Imperial Fleet.  It had the power to beat the best from the Federation.  Still, he could only hope that it would come to battle with Federation ships, hope to meet Kirk in combat someday.  Nevertheless, it was his duty to ensure the success of this mission regardless of the cost; even if he had to give up the chance to battle Kirk.\n Success ensured power.  He would command as long as he was successful.  Command was what he wanted most in life.  As he looked around the bridge at his crew, it occurred to him that they were his to command.  As long as they were on his ship, their lives were his to control, they were extensions of himself on the bridge.  The communications officer was his ears and voice to communicate with others.  His helm and Nav officers were his legs to take him where he wanted to go.  Fists to pound the enemy were provided by his weapons officer, and his engineer was a doctor to care for the body.  The bridge was the brain of the ship and he was the brain of the bridge.\n He could not resist smiling to himself.  Here he was a Romulan commander, and he was comparing his ship to his body and himself to a brain; such were not the musings of a Romulan.  He moved his attention from his inward thoughts to the main viewscreen.  The now split screen showed the forward starfield on one half and a navigational projection on the other.  The navigational projection showed his ship’s location alongside the frigate K’Lester, the two starship’s course projection, and the border markings that represented the Triangle and Federation neutral zone boundaries.\n Tark turned to his science officer’s station, “Any ships on long range sensors yet?”\n “Nothing yet, sir,” the man answered quickly.  “We should be within scanner range of any enemy vessel patrolling the Federation side of the Neutral Zone and the Triangle boarder in…1 hour, 22 minutes.”\n “Excellent, inform me as soon as you detect anything.”\n “Yes sir.” The officer firmly punched the left side of his chest and then extended his arm so that his hand was just above the level of his shoulder.\n “Commander,” came the call of his communications officer from his post beside the science station.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[725, 737, "ORG"], [811, 826, "PER"], [1133, 1147, "GPE"], [1837, 1842, "PER"], [2438, 2445, "LOC"], [2576, 2581, "PER"], [3023, 3030, "PER"], [3075, 3080, "PER"], [3128, 3135, "PER"], [3215, 3225, "GPE"], [3265, 3279, "GPE"], [3405, 3415, "GPE"], [3455, 3462, "PER"], [3648, 3654, "GPE"], [3803, 3808, "PER"], [3887, 3891, "SPEC"], [3900, 3903, "SHIP"], [3911, 3919, "LOC"], [4020, 4030, "GPE"], [4088, 4094, "GPE"], [4258, 4265, "SPEC"], [4299, 4306, "PER"], [4379, 4384, "PER"], [4341, 4351, "GPE"], [4414, 4423, "ORG"], [4578, 4584, "GPE"], [4653, 4663, "ORG"], [4700, 4710, "GPE"], [4723, 4730, "SPEC"], [4961, 4971, "GPE"], [4974, 4979, "PER"], [5065, 5071, "GPE"], [5141, 5146, "PER"], [5500, 5510, "GPE"], [5547, 5553, "GPE"], [5581, 5586, "PER"], [5776, 5781, "PER"], [5972, 5982, "GPE"], [5877, 5883, "GPE"], [6126, 6134, "SHIP"], [6177, 6187, "GPE"], [6261, 6266, "PER"], [6330, 6340, "GPE"], [6382, 6389, "GPE"], [6408, 6413, "PER"], [6444, 6454, "SHIP"], [6602, 6612, "GPE"], [6707, 6716, "PER"], [6739, 6749, "GPE"], [6823, 6833, "SHIP"], [6867, 6871, "PER"], [6980, 6989, "ORG"], [7083, 7097, "GPE"], [7178, 7185, "PER"], [7258, 7268, "GPE"], [7336, 7344, "SPEC"], [7351, 7356, "PER"], [7380, 7387, "SPEC"], [7466, 7473, "SPEC"], [7547, 7552, "PER"], [7613, 7620, "SPEC"], [7720, 7725, "PER"], [7797, 7811, "LOC"], [7821, 7835, "PER"], [7899, 7908, "PER"], [7911, 7916, "PER"], [7949, 7953, "PER"], [8328, 8335, "SPEC"], [8441, 8447, "GPE"], [8590, 8594, "PER"], [8811, 8824, "PER"], [8787, 8797, "GPE"], [8904, 8916, "PER"], [8926, 8940, "GPE"], [9039, 9060, "PER"], [9079, 9089, "SPEC"], [9098, 9108, "SHIP"], [9118, 9122, "PER"], [9177, 9181, "PER"], [9259, 9263, "PER"], [9387, 9391, "PER"], [9457, 9464, "SHIP"], [3100, 3107, "SHIP"], [8775, 8782, "GPE"], [9545, 9559, "ORG"], [9605, 9615, "GPE"], [9678, 9688, "GPE"], [9709, 9713, "PER"], [9873, 9877, "PER"], [10018, 10024, "LOC"], [10195, 10201, "LOC"], [10479, 10485, "LOC"], [10604, 10611, "SPEC"], [10540, 10546, "LOC"], [10720, 10727, "SPEC"], [10987, 10995, "SHIP"], [11080, 11088, "LOC"], [11093, 11116, "LOC"], [11130, 11134, "PER"], [11356, 11368, "LOC"], [11333, 11343, "GPE"], [11377, 11385, "LOC"], [11627, 11636, "PER"]]}
{"id": 928, "text": "“What is it Centurion?”\n “The K’Lester informs us that Commander S’Tal will be transporting over on schedule.”\n “Confirm,” Tark answered, and then added as he headed for the speedlift, “I will be in PTB room one to meet him.”\n Tark enjoyed S’Tal’s company, they shared many of the same interests.  There were so few men in the Empire with whom he could talk to about some of the Federation’s greatest strategists.  Since being assigned to this mission, he and S’Tal had spent many hours in simulated starship battle with the simusence helmets and he looked forward to one more before the mission operations began.  Tark had a special recreated simulation that had just been programmed based on a recent event in the Federation. He wanted to run the new simulation with S’Tal.\n  \n CHAPTER 2\n Captain’s Log, Stardate 2/2305.28:\n The Enterprise’s‚ first four weeks of patrol duty on the Triangle boarder have concluded without any serious incidents. As is often the case on long and uneventful patrol duty, the crew is losing concentration and becoming bored. I am sending a recommendation to Starfleet, that following the six weeks of our patrol duty, the crew of the Enterprise be given shoreleave on the planet of Lakeland. The two Federation patrol vessels immediately adjacent to us have also reported no note worthy incidents. The Sputnik‚ in the sector to the galactic north of the Enterprise‚   has monitored no activity in its sector and has completed resupply of Outpost 1 along the Romulan Neutral Zone. The Appollo‚ to the galactic south has reported a tediously sparse amount of activity in its sector bordering the Triangle.\n Captain James T. Kirk wearily pushed the button on the arm of his command chair that switched off the log recording device.  The thought of continuing patrol duty for another six weeks was devitalizing to say the least. Yet he felt at ease now; now that he was no longer behind a desk. There was a time when he had thought setting fleet procedure behind a desk would be preferable to patrol duty. After experiencing the life of a staff officer, he was resolute that his calling in life was to command a starship   to command the Enterprise. He looked around at his bridge and the efficient crew, who by merely pushing buttons and flicking switches, made the 170,000 megaton Enterprise fly through space at speeds many times faster than the speed of light. He could think of no words to express his feelings at that time. He felt a mix of awe at the thought of travelling at such an incredible speed, and genuine feelings of loyalty for and from his crew – his friends, no, his family.\n He knew that it was, in many ways, egotistical to think of the Enterprise and her crew as his, but he often found himself doing just that when he sat in the command chair. There could be no doubt that this chair was his. Looking back now, he found it hard to believe that he had ever given up his ship and taken the appointment as Chief of Starfleet Operations. Even more incredible that he had given her up a second time after the V’GER incident. Those years spent in a desk chair he had constantly dreamed and hoped of again sitting in the command chair of the Enterprise. Now he was and he would not easily give her up again.\n The previous five years had seen three serious threats on Terra and the Federation of Planets. He had lived through all of them. His ship, his crew were heroes, but there were heavy casualties. The Enterprise and her crew had paid for their heroes’ welcome with their dearest blood. James Kirk had lost the son he had only briefly known but had loved as much as any father could. It had taken Kirk several long introspective hours and several long talks with Dr. McCoy to realize that it was his friends on the Enterprise that were his family. Still, there could be little reconciliation for the losses he felt.\n Nevertheless, all was how it should be once again. The first watch surrounded him, everything felt right. Uhura was at her communication console, her fingers moving across its dimensions as they had for so many years. She seemed to have aged the most gracefully, he decided. She was perhaps even more handsome a woman now than in her younger years.\n To her left was the familiar back of Mr. Spock. Kirk was very pleased when Spock had told him that he would stay on the Enterprise as First Officer and Science Department Head. Spock had been satisfied with his role as a Starfleet instructor, but had felt the strongest emotion that Vulcans will admit to having – curiosity. He had a desire to discover things that had never before been discovered, to understand things as yet not understood, to go where no one has gone before. It was this last phrase, to “go where no man has gone before “, that had made Spock decide to request starship duty aboard the Enterprise.  Spock had told Kirk when he filed his request to stay on board the Enterprise, that he had been reminded of his own personal charter by reading the Enterprise’s. Spock had always known the charter of the Enterprise, but it was during that time when the Captain, McCoy and himself were locked in the forward observation deck by Spock’s brother that he had the opportunity to really contemplate the importance of the Enterprise and her crew to what he was; to what he had become. He had come to the realization that it was the duty aboard the starship with his friends that truly fulfilled his one true destiny – and made him content. It was a statement to which Kirk had no argument, so even though it meant Spock giving up his command, Jim Kirk had processed and endorsed the request.\n Directly in front of him, Kirk rested his eyes on the team that had guided the Enterprise through more kilometres of space than any other ship in Starfleet history. Chekov had turned down a promotion to command a vessel of his own to stay aboard the Enterprise as Department Head for Security and Weapons System, as well as third in the chain of command. Kirk remembered his misgivings about Chekov turning down the promotion. Chekov was adamant however, he would continue to learn from the best until it was time for him to move up to command the Enterprise.\n Sulu was a mainstay in Jim Kirk’s crew, Kirk knew that Sulu would stay on the Enterprise for as long as they would allow him.  Sulu had piloted the ship in every battle manoeuvre in Starfleet’s combat textbooks as well as some that would be added to them. He flew the Enterprise like it was an extension of himself. Sulu also could have had a command position on a ship of his own but had made it clear to Kirk that he was going to wait for a chance to command the Excelsior. He had told Kirk that there was no reason to leave the best ship in the fleet unless he had the chance to command a ship he could make the best.\n To the Captain’s far left, sitting with his back to the command chair watching his instruments as though the ship were in a battle was the one man who loved the Enterprise as much as Jim Kirk did – of that he was sure. Montgomery Scott would also stay with the Enterprise until he was forced to retire. Scotty had revelled at the prospect of spending his days in this new Enterprise. Kirk remembered what Scotty had said when he learned of the new Enterprise’s equipment, “Ach, me baby’s finally got the best equipment thot Starfleet has ta offer. And ’tis about time too, a shame it took her destruction for those inept fools ta realize it.” It was Scotty who had complained the loudest about the new Enterprise not being as good as the old . It had not deterred him however; he continued to work her into shape and when the time had come, she performed beautifully and saved the lives of all aboard her. It was not long after the trip to the centre of the galaxy that Scotty was again claiming that the new Enterprise was befitting the name and was his baby. “After all,” Scotty had told Kirk, “it was those inept fools at Starfleet w’at ha’ put her tagether wrong.” The memory brought a broad grin to Jim Kirk’s face.\n “Now what’s that grin for? You look like the cat that swallowed the bird, “came the voice of the Enterprise’s Chief Medical Officer and Kirk’s long-time friend and companion. McCoy had grumbled about signing for the five year mission. He had claimed that he would be old and grey by the time he got back, and that space exploration was no way for a man to be spending his twilight years. Someone had to take care of Kirk, though, and he had decided that he was the only man alive capable of having any effect on what Jim Kirk did.\n “Hello Bones, I was just thinking back to Scotty’s comments about his baby finally getting the best from the inept fools at Starfleet,” Kirk answered instigatively. The remark had its desired affect for Spock’s head popped up from his watch over the science console. Kirk felt the weariness of patrol duty lift off his shoulders as he straightened for the exchanges that were sure to ensue.\n “Captain, I was unaware that Mr. Scott was involved in the conception of the Enterprise, and in fact, that conception of an inanimate object was possible,” Spock offered without even a trace of sarcasm. He had learned long ago that while working with humans it was important to their morale – and therefore their efficiency – for them to have a nearly constant environment of humour. It was for this reason that he allowed himself to partake in their bantering back and forth as the “straight man “. It was logical.\n “Spock,” answered Dr. McCoy, “surely you must have realized that it was only a joke and that Scotty was not suggesting that he had a biological part in the Enterprise’s creation.”\n “Ah yes,” offered the Vulcan, again without even a hint of humour in his voice or face. “Humour is an abstract human concept.  I have not yet mastered recognizing or understanding it, Doctor.” Every head on the bridge was now turned to listen to the conversation. The bridge crew of the first watch were frequently treated to dialogues between Spock and McCoy. These dialogues were quite often humorous and always interesting. Since he was one of the subjects of this particular conversation, Scotty had turned from his console and was listening intently. “Ach, but ya donna understand,” Scotty jumped in, speaking not to just Spock but to McCoy and Kirk as well. “The Enterprise is me baby just as surely as if I ha’ given birth ta the lass meself.”\n Although there was no humour meant in Scotty’s statement, Kirk’s and McCoy’s faces lit up with the widest grins. They themselves were unsure of the motives behind the grins. Perhaps it was simply an acknowledgement of how Scotty felt about the Enterprise, similar to the smile given any mother when she talked of her child. But perhaps the smiles that these grown men were flashing so brightly were because they knew that Spock could not let such an illogical statement go unchallenged. The fact that Spock gave his “interesting but very illogical ” eyebrow raise confirmed their assessment of Spock’s reaction.\n “Mr. Scott,” Spock settled into his Vulcan mode readying himself for another attempt – however futile – at righting an illogical presumption. The fact that he was even pursuing a dialogue that would, at its conclusion, not change Mr. Scott’s paternal feelings concerning the Enterprise did not deter him from the attempt. “Might I remind you that the Enterprise is owned by Starfleet Command and that it is neither a “baby” nor a ” lass “.”\n “Mr. Spock!… sir,” the Scotsman answered indignantly. “I may nota’ drawn up the plans ta the darlin’ or commissioned her assemblin’, but as sure as I’m standin’ here, I’m the one thot takes care a’ her and makes her whot she is. And Mr. Spock, she is a baby. She has to be coddled and caressed ta ge’ her ta perform as she does. As for bein’ a lass, could anythin’ so beautiful not be a true lady?” Scotty was speaking the truth about how he felt concerning the Enterprise. It was his baby.  Scotty also knew the problem Spock’s logical mind would have understanding the engineer’s feelings. He continued with the conversation for the sheer enjoyment of talking about the Enterprise and the dismay it would cause the Vulcan.\n “Mr. Scott,” the Vulcan First Officer offered. “You may have made the other Enterprise what it was previous to its destruction, but I suggest that this Enterprise is as yet unchanged by your hand and is therefore not your “baby “.”  The smiles disappeared from the faces of the bridge crew. The fact that he could have just deeply hurt Montgomery Scott did not occur to Spock until Kirk answered to Spock’s comment.\n “The thing you don’t understand Spock, is that the spirit of the Enterprise lives on in this vessel and in fact is carried by the crew that lives within her.” Kirk realized that he had been far too sentimental with his statement but he felt it was needed to raise the morale of his disenchanted Chief Engineer. He also knew that Spock would pick up on the fact that he had touched on a taboo subject and that it was time to end the conversation. “The metal may be new, some of the people may be new, but she is the Enterprise, there’s no doubt about that.” There were times during the mission with Sybok that Kirk had doubted just that. Not anymore, the Enterprise had proven herself.\n “Yes, of course. Mr. Scott, please accept my apology if I have given offence.” Spock answered right on cue to the Captain’s  – Was it mental – communication. Spock had mind melded with his commanding officer and friend on several occasions and in fact had created a mental link on occasion to keep in contact with the captain when that was the only form of communication possible. He had also thought that he had severed the thread that had joined the two men. Now he felt unsure; unsure of the presence of the link or if his feelings of camaraderie had just taught him to read his captains hints and hunches. Then, what is the difference?\n “Ach, Donna worry yourself Mr. Spock. You couldna’ known. Besides thot, I may be the mother o’ the Enterprise, but with all thot ye have added ta her you are atleast an uncle,..sir.” Scotty answered innocently. Again the faces of the bridge crew were lit up with giant Cheshire grins and Spock’s eyebrow rose underneath his hairline.\n “Indeed,” was all that Spock could or would say. He knew that he had been the brunt of another harmless joke and chose to ignore it. Turning in his chair to again monitor his console he was aware of the subdued chuckles of the bridge crew. My theory correct, I have just greatly increased the morale of these humans.\n “Jim, I came up here to see if you would like to join me for dinner when shift is over.” It often seemed as though Leonard McCoy’s southern drawl got more profound as end of shift grew nearer.", "meta": {}, "annotation_approver": null, "labels": [[12, 21, "PER"], [30, 38, "PER"], [55, 70, "PER"], [123, 127, "PER"], [199, 207, "LOC"], [227, 231, "PER"], [240, 245, "PER"], [327, 333, "GPE"], [379, 389, "GPE"], [460, 465, "PER"], [615, 619, "PER"], [716, 726, "GPE"], [769, 774, "PER"], [831, 841, "SHIP"], [884, 892, "LOC"], [1090, 1099, "ORG"], [1166, 1176, "SHIP"], [1214, 1222, "PER"], [1232, 1242, "GPE"], [1334, 1341, "SHIP"], [1386, 1396, "SHIP"], [1470, 1479, "LOC"], [1490, 1510, "LOC"], [1516, 1523, "SHIP"], [1626, 1634, "LOC"], [1637, 1658, "PER"], [2166, 2176, "PER"], [2311, 2321, "SHIP"], [2686, 2696, "SHIP"], [2963, 2983, "ORG"], [3186, 3196, "SHIP"], [3311, 3316, "LOC"], [3325, 3346, "GPE"], [3451, 3461, "SHIP"], [3536, 3546, "PER"], [3646, 3650, "PER"], [3712, 3721, "PER"], [3764, 3774, "SHIP"], [3972, 3977, "PER"], [4253, 4262, "PER"], [4264, 4268, "PER"], [4291, 4296, "PER"], [4336, 4346, "SHIP"], [4393, 4398, "PER"], [4437, 4446, "ORG"], [4499, 4506, "SPEC"], [4773, 4778, "PER"], [4822, 4832, "SHIP"], [4835, 4840, "PER"], [4850, 4854, "PER"], [4902, 4912, "SHIP"], [4983, 4993, "SHIP"], [4997, 5002, "PER"], [5039, 5049, "SHIP"], [5088, 5095, "PER"], [5097, 5102, "PER"], [5162, 5167, "PER"], [5250, 5260, "SHIP"], [5496, 5500, "PER"], [5571, 5579, "PER"], [5542, 5547, "PER"], [5647, 5651, "PER"], [5700, 5710, "SHIP"], [5767, 5776, "ORG"], [5786, 5792, "PER"], [5871, 5881, "SHIP"], [5976, 5980, "PER"], [6013, 6019, "PER"], [6048, 6054, "PER"], [6182, 6186, "PER"], [6205, 6213, "PER"], [6222, 6226, "PER"], [6237, 6241, "PER"], [6169, 6179, "SHIP"], [6260, 6270, "SHIP"], [6309, 6313, "SHIP"], [6364, 6373, "ORG"], [6450, 6460, "SHIP"], [6498, 6502, "PER"], [6588, 6592, "PER"], [6647, 6656, "SHIP"], [6670, 6674, "PER"], [6811, 6818, "PER"], [6987, 6995, "PER"], [6965, 6975, "SHIP"], [7023, 7039, "PER"], [7065, 7075, "SHIP"], [7107, 7113, "PER"], [7176, 7186, "SHIP"], [7188, 7192, "PER"], [7209, 7215, "PER"], [7252, 7262, "SHIP"], [7328, 7337, "ORG"], [7454, 7460, "PER"], [7506, 7516, "SHIP"], [7774, 7780, "PER"], [7878, 7884, "PER"], [7894, 7898, "PER"], [7813, 7823, "SHIP"], [7929, 7938, "ORG"], [8008, 8016, "PER"], [8162, 8166, "PER"], [8201, 8206, "PER"], [8123, 8133, "SHIP"], [8136, 8157, "PER"], [8442, 8446, "PER"], [8543, 8551, "PER"], [8565, 8570, "PER"], [8600, 8606, "PER"], [8694, 8698, "PER"], [8682, 8691, "ORG"], [8761, 8766, "PER"], [8825, 8829, "PER"], [8951, 8958, "PER"], [8979, 8988, "PER"], [9106, 9111, "PER"], [9468, 9473, "PER"], [9560, 9566, "PER"], [9623, 9633, "SHIP"], [9670, 9676, "SPEC"], [9201, 9207, "SPEC"], [9759, 9764, "SPEC"], [9832, 9838, "PER"], [9859, 9865, "LOC"], [9992, 9997, "PER"], [10002, 10007, "PER"], [10141, 10147, "PER"], [10236, 10242, "PER"], [10275, 10280, "PER"], [10288, 10293, "PER"], [10298, 10302, "PER"], [10317, 10327, "PER"], [10438, 10444, "PER"], [10458, 10462, "PER"], [10469, 10474, "PER"], [10622, 10628, "PER"], [10644, 10654, "SHIP"], [10822, 10827, "PER"], [11014, 11023, "PER"], [11026, 11031, "PER"], [10994, 10999, "PER"], [11049, 11055, "SPEC"], [10901, 10906, "PER"], [11243, 11252, "PER"], [11288, 11298, "SHIP"], [11364, 11374, "SHIP"], [11387, 11404, "ORG"], [11456, 11465, "PER"], [11478, 11486, "PER"], [11688, 11697, "PER"], [11854, 11860, "PER"], [11917, 11927, "SHIP"], [11947, 11953, "PER"], [11976, 11981, "PER"], [12127, 12137, "SHIP"], [12172, 12178, "SPEC"], [12182, 12191, "PER"], [12205, 12218, "PER"], [12198, 12204, "SPEC"], [12257, 12267, "SHIP"], [9485, 9494, "PER"], [12026, 12034, "PER"], [12333, 12343, "SHIP"], [12517, 12533, "PER"], [12551, 12556, "PER"], [12563, 12567, "PER"], [12580, 12585, "PER"], [12630, 12635, "PER"], [12757, 12761, "PER"], [12893, 12907, "PER"], [12927, 12932, "PER"], [13113, 13123, "SHIP"], [13196, 13201, "PER"], [13207, 13211, "PER"], [13252, 13262, "SHIP"], [12663, 12673, "SHIP"], [13301, 13310, "PER"], [13363, 13368, "PER"], [13398, 13405, "PER"], [13442, 13447, "PER"], [13952, 13961, "PER"], [14024, 14034, "SHIP"], [14108, 14114, "PER"], [14213, 14218, "PER"], [14283, 14288, "PER"], [13602, 13609, "PER"], [14579, 14582, "PER"], [14693, 14706, "PER"]]}
